<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on echen.io</title><link>http://echen.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://echen.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Verbalinkd</title><link>http://echen.io/projects/verbalinkd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/projects/verbalinkd/</guid><description>Imagine that you are fresh off the boat in the United States from China. You have decided to build a new family on the American Dream by starting an authentic Sichuan-style restaurant. You try to register your new business with the government, but you struggle due to your limited English proficiency. You run into problems with designing the interior of your restaurant, and you struggle to communicate with maintenance people to help you fix your problems.</description></item><item><title>ENES100: An Engineering Interlude</title><link>http://echen.io/projects/enes100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/projects/enes100/</guid><description>Being thrust into the world of engineering was a thrilling experience. When you&amp;rsquo;re tasked with building an autonomous data-collecting vehicle that traverses a makeshift terrestrial arena, how could it not be?
Thank you to my team: Ruth, Alex, Emmanuel, Michael, Curtis, Ajeet, Yaqi. I had a blast.
The LinkedIn Version Designed and implemented an autonomous over-terrain vehicle with the objective of collecting data and traversing an arena with obstacles Engineered the power system and circuitry of the Arduino, sensors, and motors Incorporated the Arduino C sensing code for WiFi communication and object detection Monitored communication avenues between structural and navigation subteams Presented vehicle performance and engineering design process at final conference</description></item><item><title>Pulsar Academy</title><link>http://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</guid><description>This was the first large-scale coding project I ever did. It was the big finale of all the small projects I had started a few months before. Although I had taken Java classes in school before, I was blissfully unaware of what actually went on in the tech world. From an itching to do something big during COVID, my friend Maxwell and I decided to start a small online business to teach coding to beginners.</description></item></channel></rss>