<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>echen.io</title><link>http://echen.io/</link><description>Recent content on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 16:40:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://echen.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lists</title><link>http://echen.io/lists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/lists/</guid><description>I like to keep track of things that I do. Whether it be books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, habits I&amp;rsquo;m forming, or monthly budgets, it&amp;rsquo;s important for me to keep book of my progress.
Books Can&amp;rsquo;t Hurt Me - David Goggins // 8-15-2022 The Psychology of Money - Morgan Housel // 7-29-2022 Never Split the Difference - Chris Voss // 7-19-2022 How to Win Friends and Influence People - Dale Carnegie // 6-24-2022 Atomic Habits - James Clear // 6-14-2022 The Millionaire Next Door - Thomas Stanley &amp;amp; William Danko // 6-7-2022 Currently Reading The Neuroscience of Intelligence - Richard Haier Vol.</description></item><item><title>Northrop Grumman Environmental Sustainability</title><link>http://echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</guid><description>Northrop Grumman and UMD host a collaborative annual competition in areas of high importance, ranging anywhere from Machine Learning to Cybersecurity. In 2022, the topic of interest was environmental sustainability. Per Northrop Grumman&amp;rsquo;s own description, the point of the game was to &amp;ldquo;develop an original concept for a product, service, software, or a combination of the three, in areas such as clean energy, water scarcity, food security&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
A joint team of three others and I designed an IoT stormwater management system to prevent runoff and flooding on residential properties.</description></item><item><title>ENES100: An Engineering Interlude</title><link>http://echen.io/projects/enes100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/projects/enes100/</guid><description>Being thrust into the world of engineering was a thrilling experience. When you&amp;rsquo;re tasked with building an autonomous data-collecting vehicle that traverses a makeshift terrestrial arena, how could it not be?
Thank you to my team: Ruth, Alex, Emmanuel, Michael, Curtis, Ajeet, Yaqi. I had a blast.
The LinkedIn Version Designed and implemented an autonomous over-terrain vehicle with the objective of collecting data and traversing an arena with obstacles Engineered the power system and circuitry of the Arduino, sensors, and motors Incorporated the Arduino C sensing code for WiFi communication and object detection Monitored communication avenues between structural and navigation subteams Presented vehicle performance and engineering design process at final conference</description></item><item><title>Pulsar Academy</title><link>http://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</guid><description>This was the first large-scale coding project I ever did. It was the big finale of all the small projects I had started a few months before. Although I had taken Java classes in school before, I was blissfully unaware of what actually went on in the tech world. From an itching to do something big during COVID, my friend Maxwell and I decided to start a small online business to teach coding to beginners.</description></item><item><title>SEDS - Liquid Rocket Team</title><link>http://echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</guid><description>I lead the Data Acquisition Team subteam in UMD SEDS&amp;rsquo;s Liquid Rocket Team. Our responsibility is to manage the testing instrumentation, data collection, and safety protocols of the team. The liquid rocket team is the newest addition to SEDS@UMD, launched in 2021. Liquid rocket engines are notoriously difficult to manufacture, as liquid fuel propulsion requires a considerable more amount of calculation and engineering decisions than your traditional solid-fuel rocket engines. Despite the hardships, we aim to hot-fire test our first 350lbf rocket engine during the 2022-2023 year and launch an actual rocket sometime within the next 5 years.</description></item><item><title>Terps Racing</title><link>http://echen.io/extracurriculars/terps-racing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/extracurriculars/terps-racing/</guid><description>A team that builds small-scale formula racing cars for competition? Count me in. I was a member of the composites subteam, a team full of all mechanical engineers, one materials scientist, a computer engineer (me), and a former mechanical engineering turned computer science student.
The Story I helped build the carbon fiber monocoque for our 2023 formula car. Why not this years, you might ask. That&amp;rsquo;s a great question. There are two reasons:</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://echen.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 23:48:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/about/</guid><description>Welcome! I&amp;rsquo;m Eric, and I&amp;rsquo;m a sophomore studying Computer Engineering at the University of Maryland. I have a small presence online via my Twitter and my blog, where I share advice and my inner musings. The topics I write about include:
Technology and the Internet Cognitive Science and Pyschology Areas of Science: Physics, Astronomy, and Geology Culture and Politics If you want to learn about what kind of person I am, those are the best places to look!</description></item></channel></rss>