<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>echen.io</title><link>https://echen.io/</link><description>Recent content on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://echen.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Missing Story</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/the-missing-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/the-missing-story/</guid><description>This past semester, I took an Asian American Studies course in order to fulfill some Gen-Ed credits at my university. I had the sort of bland expectations you would expect for a class like this. However, I am pleased to say&amp;hellip;I was right about the class the whole time. The entire course was framed around the fight against racism and discrimination and the difficulty for Asian Americans to integrate into the United States.</description></item><item><title>Useless Alone</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/useless-alone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/useless-alone/</guid><description>If you were transported back to 1200, what are some things that exist today that you could recreate or prove are possible to people back in the day?
I&amp;rsquo;ve long pondered this question because it really shows us what we take for granted. When you think of it, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have a self-satisfactory answer to the question above. As a computer engineering student, I have absolutely no idea how I could even convey to the 1200-dwellers what a phone is.</description></item><item><title>Left and Right</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/left-and-right/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/left-and-right/</guid><description>I recently had an argument with my sister about workers&amp;rsquo; rights in the United States. We bickered about the issue back and forth, ultimately determining that our disagreements boiled down to our different worldviews. Although I won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily concede that she is as right as I am, I will say that it did teach me about the importance of opposing ideologies.
In the political sphere, we can typically place people on the left-to-right wing ideological spectrum.</description></item><item><title>Career Value</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/career-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/career-value/</guid><description>Most people will experience a dilemma at some point in their life where they are unsure of whether to pursue a career in the thing that they enjoy or pursue a career in something that will make more money. Some people are lucky and get both. However, most people realize that they can&amp;rsquo;t make a living building professional Lego sets for rich CEOs.
It&amp;rsquo;s often a difficult decision. There&amp;rsquo;s a fine balance between choosing something you enjoy versus something that will make your life more comfortable.</description></item><item><title>Good Enough</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/good-enough/</guid><description>Exactness is rarely achievable in daily life. In most situations, we expect things to be &amp;ldquo;good enough,&amp;rdquo; where we&amp;rsquo;re okay with a result despite knowing it could be better. There is always some tolerance and wiggle room. Spending an extra 5 hours editing your essay after a two-day grind will barely make a difference. Toyota is fine with some parts being off by a few micrometers. Google Maps uses an algorithm that is likely to be the fastest route.</description></item><item><title>Perfection Takes Time</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/perfection-takes-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/perfection-takes-time/</guid><description>I often struggle with having imperfect work. My impatience leads me down a path where everything I do has to be perfect the first time. My first essay draft must be exact, my code must be optimally efficient, and homework has to be 100% correct and robust. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent countless hours dwelling on tiny details, making 0.1% improvements instead of big sweeping changes that actually matter.
My attention often narrows on the most minute of details, which often prevents me from seeing the picture.</description></item><item><title>What is Reasonable?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/what-is-reasonable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/what-is-reasonable/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering on the idea of reasonableness. It&amp;rsquo;s a word that carries a lot of weight, where its applicability to any situation is highly subjective and can be easily contested. In most scenarios, there is some semblance of agreement between most parties regarding what is considered reasonable. More aptly, ideas where a reasonable amount of people can agree on what is deemed reasonable. A good metric to assess reasonableness is to determine whether it carries more reward than risk.</description></item><item><title>The Shifting Concept of Ethnicity</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/shifting-concept-ethnicity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/shifting-concept-ethnicity/</guid><description>We live in a unique time where the homogeneity within groups is on the decline. Historically, the world has been split by region, nationality, and ethnicity. You expect to find ethnically Chinese people in China, Indians in India, Africans in Africa, etc. Even more ambiguously, we have a current concept of what it means to be white, black, or Asian. Even in the middle East where the concept of ethnicity doesn&amp;rsquo;t really exist anymore, we can still identify them by being &amp;ldquo;Middle Eastern.</description></item><item><title>Battle of the Sexes</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/battle-of-the-sexes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/battle-of-the-sexes/</guid><description>My recent Instagram Reels feed has been a battleground between the sexes. You might see a short clip of a supercifical and shallow dating show solely focused on first impressions. Or, you might find a video of a street interview of random strangers about dating expectations. Regardless, these reels about how men and women treat one another will have a warzone in the comments. It&amp;rsquo;s a coin flip whether you&amp;rsquo;ll see a tsunami of men complaining about how unfaithful women are or torrent of women complaining about how men ruin everything.</description></item><item><title>"Do What Makes You Happy"</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/do-what-makes-you-happy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/do-what-makes-you-happy/</guid><description>I was scrolling on Twitter, and I ran into this tweet:
Not saying I have an opinion on this matter in particular, it was just the inspiration to write this. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of people on social media echo this sentiment: let people do what makes them happy. This seems to make sense to a lot of people, and why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it? We all want to be happy. If someone does something that makes them happy, who are we to judge?</description></item><item><title>Implicit vs. Explicit Knowledge</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/implicit-explicit-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/implicit-explicit-knowledge/</guid><description>I was sitting in a professional learning and development meeting today about resilience and collaboration. He was quite the animated and engaging speaker, but as usual, most of everything he said was pretty basic and self-explanatory. I would argue that it was all common sense. I&amp;rsquo;ve felt this way about many of my classes before&amp;ndash;mostly the non-STEM ones. In my communications class, of course, there&amp;rsquo;s verbal and nonverbal communication. In my systems class, of course, some systems are complex and some are simple.</description></item><item><title>Right to Judge</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/right-to-judge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/right-to-judge/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to intrude on other people&amp;rsquo;s lives. I like to exist in parallel, only interfering when it actually matters. When it comes to strangers or acquaintances, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less about what they do. They lead their own lives and deal with their own struggles. Who am I to say anything.
However, we all reserve the right to judge. In these days, it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful that people have the freedom to make almost any choice they wish.</description></item><item><title>In a New City</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/in-a-new-city/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/in-a-new-city/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in New York City for the summer. It&amp;rsquo;s for an internship. This is what I wanted. A departure from my last one.
I found myself in the suburbs of San Francisco last summer. I was too far from the city to visit often. I had no car. There was no subway, and I was only armed with a very slow and oversized bike. I found myself having nothing to do after work.</description></item><item><title>Human Creativity</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/human-creativity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/human-creativity/</guid><description>With the rise of AI-generated content, will AI completely replace human creativity? Even if human-created content far outpaces what AIs can do today, how much longer will this be true? For those who scoff about how AI still makes major mistakes, remember that we&amp;rsquo;re in year 2-3 of a developmental journey that will last the rest of time. In ten or even a hundred years, do you really think that AI will still be lagging behind?</description></item><item><title>Overthinking</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/overthinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/overthinking/</guid><description>There are a few things in life that I am good at. Out of all of them, I’m the best at overthinking. Despite never even wanting to do it, I have become a master. With my unintentionally dutiful training, I have become the best at the thing I want to do the least.
Through analyzing my personality over the years, I became more aware of how often I overthink the most mundane situations.</description></item><item><title>What Makes a Person Bad?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bad-person/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bad-person/</guid><description>My friend Alex and I were talking about some of the unsavory individuals in our high school after a couple of controversies popped up over the year. I specifically recall him telling me that &amp;ldquo;even bad people are good 90% of the time&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash; a statement that&amp;rsquo;s stuck with me over my college years as I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered more and more cases of unscrupulous wrongdoings.
The claim is slightly overexaggerated&amp;ndash; clearly, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a small fraction people that are consistently rude and unpleasant.</description></item><item><title>Celebrity Obsession</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/celebrity-obsession/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/celebrity-obsession/</guid><description>A trend I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed over the past decade is the increased obsession with celebrities and influencers. It&amp;rsquo;s not a surprise either. Access to the internet has increased the amount of information distribution channels. You can easily click through hundreds of daily articles about rumors and the latest gossip about your favorite or least favorite celebs. Most of them have their personal social media platforms now where you can see carefully crafted Instagram posts or shower tweets that should have just stayed shower thoughts.</description></item><item><title>I'm so Bored</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bored/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bored/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a month since my winter break began, and I can concretely say that I have accomplished absolutely nothing of substance. I have never been at a point in my life where I&amp;rsquo;ve had nothing solid to work toward, and I have no idea what to do. In middle school and high school, I was driven by competition and the desire to get into a good college. I wanted to win debate competitions, perform well in math competitions, and win the national Science Bowl.</description></item><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Old?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/what-does-mean-old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/what-does-mean-old/</guid><description>Over the summer of 2023, I interned at an AI startup in Menlo Park, California. I purchased a gym pass to the YMCA a few miles away in Palo Alto. On my daily commute back from the gym, I biked past an old elderly couple smiling and laughing as they crossed the street together. It was a scene I saw countless times biking around the well-off suburban area full of retirees.</description></item><item><title>A Deep Dive Review of Abyss</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/abyss-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/abyss-review/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a movie or TV show review. However, this show deserves it, because I had some serious gripes about it while watching it.
A Quick Synopsis Abyss centers around two friends that die tragically in separate events and are reincarnated into new bodies that they don&amp;rsquo;t recognize. Cha Min, a rather ugly but kind heir of his family&amp;rsquo;s cosmetics empire dies from an alien passing by Earth. As compensation, he is given a magical &amp;ldquo;Abyss&amp;rdquo;, an object that grants the user to revive anybody into the form of their soul.</description></item><item><title>The Unreliability of AI</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/unreliability-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/unreliability-of-ai/</guid><description>Since the revolutionary public release of generative AI models, there has been an incredible wave of interest, hype, and expectations around their capabilities. Millions of people around the world are harnessing the powers of text-to-image and language models to explore new ideas and accomplish tasks that would have been even impossible in the past. These technologies sprung up so fast that we have yet to internalize the full extent of their possibilities, limitations, and dangers.</description></item><item><title>Gallery</title><link>https://echen.io/gallery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/gallery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bitcamp</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/bitcamp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/bitcamp/</guid><description>Bitcamp is the University of Maryland&amp;rsquo;s premier hackathon, bringing together over 1,400 students, making it the largest collegiate hackathon on the East Coast. I am a software developer on the tech team.
Accomplishments So Far Built Registration App with Vue.js, AWS Lambda, API Gateway, and DynamoDB Form logic + design Built website with Vue.js Working on the EXPO app This is a story version. I will have an update with more technical details soon.</description></item><item><title>UMD Engineering Career Services</title><link>https://echen.io/projects/engineering-career-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/projects/engineering-career-services/</guid><description>Our team of five, consisting of Shruthi, Vincent, Allison, Nikita, and myself, were tasked with optimizing the volunteer registration and check-in process for the Engineering Career Services (ECS) at the University of Maryland. The organization had to revert to a manual and error-prone method of registering and checking in employers and student organizations after the servers that hosted their digital registration and check-in portal for career fairs were shut down. The new process made it difficult for ECS to properly track organizers and student volunteering hours, which made it challenging to compensate them adequately.</description></item><item><title>Verbalinkd</title><link>https://echen.io/projects/verbalinkd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/projects/verbalinkd/</guid><description>Imagine that you are fresh off the boat in the United States from China. You have decided to build a new family on the American Dream by starting an authentic Sichuan-style restaurant. You try to register your new business with the government, but you struggle due to your limited English proficiency. You run into problems with designing the interior of your restaurant, and you struggle to communicate with maintenance people to help you fix your problems.</description></item><item><title>Why Bits and Bytes?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bits-and-bytes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bits-and-bytes/</guid><description>Why do computers use binary? The human world is practically defined by the number 10. Ever since we evolved to be competent enough to manipulate numbers, we have almost exclusively used a number system in base 10, cross-culturally. But computers use base 2. Why base 2 specifically? There are an infinite number of bases to use&amp;ndash; some that make more sense to us than others&amp;ndash; but we decided to go with base 2.</description></item><item><title>One-Month Reflection</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/one-month-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/one-month-reflection/</guid><description>February 4th marked the one-month anniversary of the creation of my shorts page, a collection of my short-form writing. Seeing my friend Eli embark on his one-month writing journey inspired me to try it for myself. I was at a point where I was desperate to share my ideas, but I could not find the right medium to do so. Over the course of 2022, I wrote one single ten-thousand-word monstrosity detailing my self-reflection over the second semester of my freshman year.</description></item><item><title>Stepping Stones</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/stepping-stones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/stepping-stones/</guid><description>In many of my science classes over the years, I found myself extremely confused about the intuition behind theorems and proofs. I would ponder, how could you possibly figure that out? This pervasive thought did not only apply to complex topics. There are so many simple things that this could refer to. How about long division? We all employ that technique all the time, an elementary and systematic approach to dividing any two real numbers that seems trivial.</description></item><item><title>Free Will</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/free-will/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/free-will/</guid><description>Do we have control over our lives? Are we truly the one who makes decisions for ourselves, or is our future determined by a predetermined and inescapable fate? Philosophers have pondered this concept of free will for a long time, and the answer is not so clear. The colloquial notion of free will is a concept at a very high level of analysis, one where we evaluate the tenants of existence, consciousness, and autonomy.</description></item><item><title>Routine and Adventure</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/routine-and-adventure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/routine-and-adventure/</guid><description>Life is a balance bewteen routine and adventure. Routine gives us the stability we need. It tells us what to expect and what to do. It&amp;rsquo;s your own crystal ball. If you lose routine, you lose predictability, which would quickly turn your life into chaos. Imagine trying to balance a day full of surprises every day. It would drive you mad. On the other hand, routine brings boredom. It&amp;rsquo;s a cycle of expectation and action.</description></item><item><title>Shaped by Upbringing</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/shaped-by-upbringing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/shaped-by-upbringing/</guid><description>We are shaped by our upbringing. Everything that we experience is through the lens through which we view the world, influenced by the major and minute variables of our environment. I have come to a point in my life where I can notice how my past affects the way I behave. I see the ways my upbringing shaped my personality and my desires, in both relationships and company. We make these sorts of observations about others very often.</description></item><item><title>Help or Harm?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/help-or-harm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/help-or-harm/</guid><description>With the rise of automation and artificial intelligence, people have begun to discuss whether they are more beneficial or detrimental to society. On the one hand, they are redefining what is possible. On the other, they are replacing tasks that humans would traditionally do. But, why is that a bad thing, if even a bad thing at all? Automating human activities can have the consequence of replacing humans completely. The invention of the telephone switchboard in the early 1900s ended up replacing hundreds of thousands of telephone operators.</description></item><item><title>You Might've Been a Nazi</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/you-mightve-been-a-nazi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/you-mightve-been-a-nazi/</guid><description>We live in the fairest time in human history. The people today are the most wealthy and free compared to almost everyone even a few hundred years ago. I didn&amp;rsquo;t say that we live in a perfect society. Poverty, racism, and inequality still plague our planet today. But, we can be thankful for all of the incredible developments we have made in recent history.
Let&amp;rsquo;s travel back in time for a second.</description></item><item><title>Time is Relative</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/time-is-relative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/time-is-relative/</guid><description>Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor tells us that the simplest idea is always the best. In many situations, this is true. There is no need to needlessly complicate. The more complications you create, the more explanations you need to find.
This rule does not apply in the realm of time. We perceive time to move in a linear fashion, but this is not the case at all. Einstein discovered almost 100 years ago that in every situation, time is relative.</description></item><item><title>Bicker Bicker</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bicker-bicker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bicker-bicker/</guid><description>The truth is the light in the darkness. When you are uncertain, the truth is the absolute defense. It gives us solid ground to stand on. We all strive for truth. It allows us to understand the reality we live in. We learn to find the truth. We think, we observe, and we grow&amp;ndash; all with the purpose of getting closer to the absolute truth. And lastly, we argue for it.</description></item><item><title>Who are You?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/who-are-you/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/who-are-you/</guid><description>Who are you? A collection of cells that form a mass of muscle, tissue, and bones around 5-7 feet high. A vessel of consciousness existing within the framework of time and space. An amalgamation of memories, character traits, and emotion. You probably have a strong sense of who you are. You are the primary witness of your body, your memories, your thought processes, and your consciousness. Everyone else is just a mere observer.</description></item><item><title>Hero or Villain?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</guid><description>Today is Martin Luther King Jr. Day. It&amp;rsquo;s a day to celebrate one of the most important leaders of the Civil Rights movement. A day to honor the man who delivered one of the most memorable and impactful speeches in American history. A day to honor the man who dreamt of a world where people would be evaluated by the content of their character rather than the color of their skin.</description></item><item><title>Death</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/death/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/death/</guid><description>Death awaits all of us. He is calm and patient. Some will arrive at his doorstep early. Some will take many years. But, at time&amp;rsquo;s end, he will greet all of us at his door. There is no escape.
Death is such a grave concept (pun intended). It marks the point where something ceases to live. Everyone lives to avoid death. We eat to not starve. We exercise to stay healthy.</description></item><item><title>In Defense of Difficult Exams</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</guid><description>Nobody likes difficult exams. After all, the professor might ask us questions we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before. He might ask about ideas we haven&amp;rsquo;t considered before. Difficult exams can tank my grade. That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair, right? Unfortunately, I would argue that those are actually &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; things.
What is the purpose of an exam? Exams are meant to test your understanding of the material. I&amp;rsquo;ve had many exams in college that are just refreshed versions of previous semesters&amp;rsquo; exams.</description></item><item><title>Shared Identity</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</guid><description>I went on a boat tour in Everglades National Park this afternoon. Our tour guide, Mitchell, took guided us through the 3-mile-long Buttonwood Canal, where we arrived at the mouth of Florida Bay. He was very knowledgeable of the different plants, birds, and animal life in the area– after all, it’s his job. Along the water, we passed by a few speedboats driven by middle-aged men with short hair, sun hats, sunglasses, fishing rods, and tanned skin.</description></item><item><title>Sunrise</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</guid><description>I watched the sun rise at Dania Beach, Florida this morning. I watched as the rays of our red-orange Sun peeked over the dark blue horizon. As it rose across the waters, the light reflected off of the ocean, forming a gold carpet towards the shore. The sky was smeared salmon and pink, gradually melting into blue. It was awe-inspiringly beautiful.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first sunrise. As a matter of fact, the Sun has rose every single day that I have been alive.</description></item><item><title>Dealt an Unfortunate Hand</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</guid><description>Life is unfair. Some people start with everything and some people start with nothing. We&amp;rsquo;re born of circumstances that we cannot control. We do not decide our parents, our birthplace, our birthday, or our name. We&amp;rsquo;re given a hand, and we&amp;rsquo;re forced to play it. It&amp;rsquo;s an undeniable fact that people have different privileges. Some people are beautiful, some people are geniuses, some people are tall, and some people have it all.</description></item><item><title>Chess Addiction</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</guid><description>Over the last two years, I have become addicted to chess. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent hours upon hours watching analyses of famous games between the strongest grandmasters that have ever lived. Each game is a story. Some are long, others are short. Some are super complicated, others are relatively simple. Some are wild, others are calm. The variety keeps the game interesting, just as different books and genres keep reading interesting. The style of a game depends on the player, the time format, the mood, the environment, and more.</description></item><item><title>Humans are Silly</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</guid><description>Humans are silly. We do a lot of really silly things. We look at squiggles on a piece of paper to learn. We bop our heads to random assembleges of acoustic waves. We go to office buildings and trade our time for pieces of paper with fancy images on them. The list goes on and on. We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard that nagging voice from a parent or friend: &amp;ldquo;why are you wasting your time?</description></item><item><title>Dating Apps</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</guid><description>I was going to write about dating apps here, but it ended up being so long that I put it on my blog. You can read it here:
https://blog.echen.io/p/dating-apps/</description></item><item><title>Carefree Writing</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</guid><description>I have not published a blog post in half a year. Emphasis on published. I have many backlogged drafts that I never completed, from book reviews to self reflections. Writing has become a chore for me. I spend too much time on the details, losing focus on the greater meaning behind the piece itself. If writing is thinking, then I have not thought. If writing is self expression, then I have not expressed myself.</description></item><item><title>Lists</title><link>https://echen.io/lists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/lists/</guid><description>I like to keep track of things that I do. Whether it be books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, habits I&amp;rsquo;m forming, or monthly budgets, it&amp;rsquo;s important for me to keep book of my progress.
Goals for 2024 Read 10 books Learn 1 powermove Create a stock / retirement portfolio Become friendly with a professor Find new intellectual interests Have meaningful things to do in my free time Books Can&amp;rsquo;t Hurt Me - David Goggins // 8-15-2022 The Psychology of Money - Morgan Housel // 7-29-2022 Never Split the Difference - Chris Voss // 7-19-2022 How to Win Friends and Influence People - Dale Carnegie // 6-24-2022 Atomic Habits - James Clear // 6-14-2022 The Millionaire Next Door - Thomas Stanley &amp;amp; William Danko // 6-7-2022 Films and Shows Films Dream The Super Mario Bros.</description></item><item><title>Northrop Grumman Environmental Sustainability</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</guid><description>Northrop Grumman and UMD host a collaborative annual competition in areas of high importance, ranging anywhere from Machine Learning to Cybersecurity. In 2022, the topic of interest was environmental sustainability. Per Northrop Grumman&amp;rsquo;s own description, the point of the game was to &amp;ldquo;develop an original concept for a product, service, software, or a combination of the three, in areas such as clean energy, water scarcity, food security&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
A joint team of three others and I designed an IoT stormwater management system to prevent runoff and flooding on residential properties.</description></item><item><title>ENES100: An Engineering Interlude</title><link>https://echen.io/projects/enes100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/projects/enes100/</guid><description>Being thrust into the world of engineering was a thrilling experience. When you&amp;rsquo;re tasked with building an autonomous data-collecting vehicle that traverses a makeshift terrestrial arena, how could it not be?
Thank you to my team: Ruth, Alex, Emmanuel, Michael, Curtis, Ajeet, Yaqi. I had a blast.
The LinkedIn Version Designed and implemented an autonomous over-terrain vehicle with the objective of collecting data and traversing an arena with obstacles Engineered the power system and circuitry of the Arduino, sensors, and motors Incorporated the Arduino C sensing code for WiFi communication and object detection Monitored communication avenues between structural and navigation subteams Presented vehicle performance and engineering design process at final conference</description></item><item><title>Pulsar Academy</title><link>https://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</guid><description>This was the first large-scale coding project I ever did. It was the big finale of all the small projects I had started a few months before. Although I had taken Java classes in school before, I was blissfully unaware of what actually went on in the tech world. From an itching to do something big during COVID, my friend Maxwell and I decided to start a small online business to teach coding to beginners.</description></item><item><title>SEDS - Liquid Rocket Team</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</guid><description>I lead the Data Acquisition Team subteam in UMD SEDS&amp;rsquo;s Liquid Rocket Team. Our responsibility is to manage the testing instrumentation, data collection, and safety protocols of the team. The liquid rocket team is the newest addition to SEDS@UMD, launched in 2021. Liquid rocket engines are notoriously difficult to manufacture, as liquid fuel propulsion requires a considerable more amount of calculation and engineering decisions than your traditional solid-fuel rocket engines. Despite the hardships, we aim to hot-fire test our first 350lbf rocket engine during the 2022-2023 year and launch an actual rocket sometime within the next 5 years.</description></item><item><title>Terps Racing</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/terps-racing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/terps-racing/</guid><description>A team that builds small-scale formula racing cars for competition? Count me in. I was a member of the composites subteam, a team full of all mechanical engineers, one materials scientist, a computer engineer (me), and a former mechanical engineering turned computer science student.
The Story I helped build the carbon fiber monocoque for our 2023 formula car. Why not this years, you might ask. That&amp;rsquo;s a great question. There are two reasons:</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://echen.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/about/</guid><description>Welcome! I&amp;rsquo;m Eric, and I&amp;rsquo;m Eric, and I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip;unemployed until August. I graduated as a computer engineering student from the University of Maryland this year. I have a small presence online via my Twitter, my short-form writing, and my blog, where I share advice and my inner musings. The topics I write about include:
Technology and the Internet Cognitive Science and Pyschology Areas of Science Culture and Politics Cloud Computing Popular media Career-wise, I specialize in machine learning (particularly deep learning), full-stack development, and cloud computing with AWS + GCP.</description></item><item><title>This is Emily</title><link>https://echen.io/emily/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/emily/</guid><description>She&amp;rsquo;s so cute :)</description></item></channel></rss>