<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Eric Chen</title><link>https://echen.io/</link><description>Recent content on Eric Chen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:40:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://echen.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lists</title><link>https://echen.io/lists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 02:04:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/lists/</guid><description>I like to keep track of things that I do. Whether it be books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, habits I&amp;rsquo;m forming, or monthly budgets, it&amp;rsquo;s important to keep book of your own progress. I&amp;rsquo;ll share some noteworthy lists I have:
Books How to Win Friends and Influence People - Dale Carnegie // 6-24-2022 Atomic Habits - James Clear // 6-14-2022 The Millionare Next Door - Thomas Stanley &amp;amp; William Danko // 6-7-2022 Learning Items GCP ACE Exam Preparation Kubernetes Deep Dive Hands-on Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn and Tensorflow - Aurélien Géron Favorite Quotes &amp;ldquo;A person&amp;rsquo;s success in life can be measured by the number of uncomfortable conversations he or she is willing to have.</description></item><item><title>Northrop Grumman Environmental Sustainability</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</guid><description>Designed an IoT storm water management system to prevent runoff and flooding on residential properties
Controlled streamflow within a swale by querying the Visual Weather Crossing API and controlling Arduino-operated pumps Built functional small-scale replica on an actual residential property in D.C. Evaluated market analytics, centers of influence, and environmental impact of our product Presented prototype and business model to judge panel and placed 1st among participating teams</description></item><item><title>SEDS - Liquid Rocket Team</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</guid><description>Organized and prepared technical analyses of data acquisition designs and electrical architecture
Designated tasks to different team members and maintained communication between the different subteams Designed the avionics and data collection pipeline with LabVIEW of our 350 lbf liquid rocket engine Managed weekly subteam meetups and relayed information from administration to subteam members</description></item><item><title>Pulsar Academy</title><link>https://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/projects/pulsar-academy/</guid><description>Initiated an online business to educate the youth about coding principles and fundamentals. Programmed and designed a website with Django and JavaScript to manage registration, payment, and course content. Containerized website with PostgreSQL database and SSL daemon using Docker compose. Hosted website using AWS EC2 and RDS using a NGINX webserver.</description></item><item><title>Terps Racing</title><link>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/terps-racing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/extracurriculars/terps-racing/</guid><description>Built the carbon fiber monocoque of the team&amp;rsquo;s formula car
Learned design and engineering process of developing rigid automotive structures Implemented carbon fiber layups, vacuum sealing, wet and dry sanding, 3D printing, Bondo, epoxy + resin, molding/mold release, waxing</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://echen.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 23:48:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/about/</guid><description>Now that you know a bit of background about me, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some career interests with you too. If you want to learn more about the type of person I am, take a look at my blog.
Career Interests My entire CS path so far has been cloud centric. It all started when I wanted to share Twitter Bot I made that would respond to my friends&amp;rsquo; tweets. I had to figure out how to deploy it.</description></item></channel></rss>