<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Short-form Writings on echen.io</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/</link><description>Recent content in Short-form Writings on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://echen.io/shorts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Missing Story</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/the-missing-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/the-missing-story/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/asian-american.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Missing Story" />&lt;p>This past semester, I took an Asian American Studies course in order to fulfill some Gen-Ed credits at my university. I had the sort of bland expectations you would expect for a class like this. However, I am pleased to say&amp;hellip;I was right about the class the whole time. The entire course was framed around the fight against racism and discrimination and the difficulty for Asian Americans to integrate into the United States. Every class was imbued with a victim narrative that only inspired a certain kind of conversation where we could only analyze the challenges and injustices without room to celebrate the contributions or cultural impact of Asian Americans. The class portrayed a reductionist view where Asian American history was simply a battle against oppressive forces, and I found myself longing to hear some celebratory stories of cultural identity outside of that particular lens. However, that never came to be. I learned nothing about how the Chinese introduced ethnic food to Americans. I learned nothing about how Indian Americans contributed to the technological boom of the 2000s. I learned nothing about how Japanese and Korean entertainment ravaged global cultural boundaries and fostered a new generation of cross-cultural appreciation. Is this aspect of Asian American history not just as pivotal to understanding as the struggles against racism and discrimination? Can we talk about Asian American success without having to evoke their struggles against oppression as the backdrop? The ironic lack of diversity in the portrayal of Asian American history left me (and other students I talked to in my class) wanting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One main point that my professor emphasized is that the Asian American psyche is not a monolith&amp;ndash;i.e. Asian Americans don&amp;rsquo;t all think the same. Anybody with a competent faculty of thinking would agree with this statement, but I found many of the discussions and material antithetical to this idea. First, the professor enforced a strict interpretation of certain ideas (e.g. affirmative action, model minority) without room for deviation. Every conversation had an assumed prior that you agreed with the portrayal&amp;ndash;for example, seeing the idea of model minority as a myth, as if that interpretation is a fact. Second, the professor would inject overtly political opinions into the discussion with a strong attitude that discouraged any kind of disagreement, essentially incentivizing conformity over critical thought.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Third, the course offered an excessive amount of material with authors who couldn&amp;rsquo;t tolerate people who didn&amp;rsquo;t share their worldview. I watched a couple of seminars of supposed Asian American Studies pundits who made statements along the lines of: &amp;ldquo;Muslims who vote Republican are a shame to their people and are only voting against their own interests&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t understand why Asian Americans are protesting affirmative action, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even imagine talking to one of them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> I found it incredibly ironic and disappointing that these experts could evoke this kind of ostracizing sentiment when their whole field revolves around the intricacies of the Asian American experience. It seemed like the entire anti-monolithic sentiment was just a façade, where none of these people can actually tolerate much disagreement at all. All of this animosity toward their so-called fellow Asians because they don&amp;rsquo;t agree with their worldview. The whole discussion begs the question, what does being Asian American even mean to them?&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="model-minority-myth">Model Minority &amp;ldquo;Myth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty difficult to encapsulate what being Asian American even means. A loose idea is an American with Asian heritage, which we can usually gauge through physical appearance. But even this interpretation is vague, as the mentality often shifts when you try to extend this idea to someone who&amp;rsquo;s half Asian, quarter Asian, or even less, but that&amp;rsquo;s a discussion for another day. It would be naive to consider the idea of &amp;ldquo;Asian American&amp;rdquo; as purely an ethnic boundary, so we often extend the definition to include common culture, values, and history. However, is there a single attitude that &lt;em>every single Asian American&lt;/em> shares? No, of course not! The whole anti-monolithic view in the previous paragraph says as much. Does that mean we can&amp;rsquo;t say anything about Asian Americans that largely applies to the population, such as the statement that Asians eat rice? Obviously you can, so why am I bringing this seemingly trivial point up? It&amp;rsquo;s because this logic somehow doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply when we talk about the &amp;ldquo;Model Minority Myth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The model minority concept points to the idea that some ethnic groups&amp;ndash;including most Asian American groups&amp;ndash; are perceived to be achieving a higher socioeconomic status in comparison to the overall population average.&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> However, it&amp;rsquo;s also commonly seen as a weapon to talk down to marginalized groups, implying that they can succeed in the same conditions while ignoring other extraneous variables. In a vacuum, I will discuss this concept using the former contextualization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of the &amp;ldquo;Model Minority&amp;rdquo; as a myth was introduced in the class as a statement of truth, ideologically akin to the statement that 1+1=2. This portrayal typically boils down to the common argument that &amp;ldquo;not all Asian Americans are successful.&amp;rdquo; More commonly, in the form of the response that &amp;ldquo;not all Asians are good at math.&amp;rdquo; This disconnect fundamentally relies on the idea that &amp;ldquo;we cannot generalize something positive about a population if some members of that population do not meet that standard.&amp;rdquo; And to some extent, I agree. It would be foolish to walk up to some Asian guy you never met and assume he&amp;rsquo;s great at math or only eats rice. However, the problem arises when the focus shifts solely to individual exceptions without considering the broader cultural or societal patterns. For example, we can generally say that humans have five fingers. You would not go out of your way to argue that some people are born with six fingers or no hands. I don&amp;rsquo;t wish to equate &amp;ldquo;not being good at math&amp;rdquo; with a genetic defect, so let me counter with the alternative statement that &amp;ldquo;college graduates earn more income than non-college graduates.&amp;rdquo; The statement holds regardless of whether you know some college graduates who are jobless or work minimum wage. So, I think I can make the fair blanket statement that &amp;ldquo;most Asian American groups have higher average income and educational attainment compared to the national average.&amp;rdquo; Since this statement is just blatantly true (statistically), we&amp;rsquo;ll go with the more common model minority statement that &amp;ldquo;many Asian American families typically hold values that lead to economic success, such as education, family, or academic achievement.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often see the refusal to accept this idea because it&amp;rsquo;s somehow stereotyping all Asians or weaponized against other groups. However, to simply call it a &amp;ldquo;myth&amp;rdquo; is throwing the baby out with the bathwater. You can consider the central ideas of this theory without falling into the trap of oversimplification or harmful generalization. However, this sort of nuance never existed within my class, as the surface-level notion that &amp;ldquo;not all Asians are successful&amp;rdquo; forced the concept of Model Minority Myth into the spotlight, which basically governed every single discussion for the rest of the course. You would think an Asian American Studies class would jump on the opportunity to talk about positive cultural aspects within the Asian American psyche, but clearly, this was not the case. There was a taboo over this defining portion of Asian American culture. Instead, the course would attribute Asian American success as the result of Asians working within complying to a racist system, Asian immigrants typically coming over with advanced degrees or Asian American children being unduly privileged. In order not to promote a reductionist view of Asian American success, the course chose to enforce an even more reductionist and narrow-minded rationale instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already explained why I vehemently disregard the arguments above in my blog post, &lt;a href="https://blog.echen.io/p/affirmative-action-unmasked/#discussing-the-model-minority-stereotype">Affirmative Action Unmasked&lt;/a>. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll give some personal anecdotes to counter them this time around. I have an incredibly fortunate and privileged background, born to two parents with graduate degrees from top Chinese institutions who immigrated over with H1-B visas. I lived in relatively wealthy areas with access to an endless array of resources like math camps, violin lessons, and art classes with the full support of my family. My parents always emphasized education and academic success. Unsurprisingly, many of the Asian American (mostly Chinese) kids I grew up with had parents with similar backgrounds and shared the same kind of academic ambition and view toward life&amp;ndash;to us, it was never a question of whether or not we would go to college, it was a given. You would imagine that we all ended up in college pursuing competitive degrees because our parents were well-educated and successful. However, when I came to college, the story remained the same &lt;em>in spite of&lt;/em> parental background. I met many Asian American friends whose parents were not well educated. They worked blue-collar jobs, owned restaurants, had little wealth, and maybe even immigrated illegally. But the expectation was the same&amp;ndash;college was the goal. Regardless of the background and trajectory, the expectation was ultimately the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve walked the streets of Chinatown in New York. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the poverty there, the absolute desolation, and the struggle to survive. Even in more dire situations than I could imagine, these people work hard so their kids can get a good education and live a better life than their own. This is no coincidence. This isn&amp;rsquo;t because they all had college degrees. This isn&amp;rsquo;t because society was unjustly propping them up for success. This isn&amp;rsquo;t because they had resources other people couldn&amp;rsquo;t access. This is because of the deep desire to have their kids succeed, and the inculcation of the values that hard work, perseverance, and education are the keys to a better life. And this sentiment, one way or another, is widely prevalent within many Asian communities. You can say that not all Asian families are like this. You can say that many parents are overly harsh about their children&amp;rsquo;s success. However, you can&amp;rsquo;t deny this aspect of Asian American culture. You can come after me for being a privileged kid and the benefactor of &amp;ldquo;successful&amp;rdquo; parents. You&amp;rsquo;re right. However, don&amp;rsquo;t be under the impression that my parents had it easy. They were the first in their families to go to college. They worked hard within a system that begged their failure. They came over to the U.S. with nothing. They sacrificed their pesonal wellbeing so my sister and I could have a good life. &lt;em>This is no coincidence.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These values are in no way baked into the biological thread of the Asian American existence. They are just more common within the Asian American psyche, whatever that reason may be. Any family can value these same things, and it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that you can find similar stories within other communities around the world. Again, what makes someone Asian American? The only thing that is &lt;em>always&lt;/em> true is that they have some Asian heritage. There is nothing else that can be conclusively said that applies to every Asian American. So, what holds the subject of &amp;ldquo;Asian American Studies&amp;rdquo; together? The Asian American category itself is in part defined by cultural and social generalizations that bring people together. If we can&amp;rsquo;t even generalize about cultural values that cause Asian American success, what can we generalize about? The whole course discusses how Asian Americans triumphed in a system that marginalized them, yet we cannot talk about specific factors that contributed to their success. You can argue that these ideas can be mechanisms to create harmful stereotypes or vilify other groups, but is the solution to preach an anti-truth instead, just to make some people feel better? I think not.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, this kind of reductionism was much too common within the humanities-focused courses I took during college. There always seemed to be this air of conformity around certain discussions, where students were expected to give some compliant view that the professor would approve of. In a system where students mostly care about their grades and the professors hold so much power, there is typically no incentive to challenge them. It&amp;rsquo;s really under the teachers&amp;rsquo; purview to encourage constructive dialogue, but I have found these teachers quite rare. In a vacuum, I have nothing against any of my professors, and I have found most of them pleasant and caring of their students, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to needlessly make a hoopla about them. However, there was this cognitive dissonance embedded into my Asian American studies class that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite shake off, which led me to write this. The course did not practice what it preached, often reducing the Asian American narrative to a narrow, monolithic view. I felt that it did not deliver on creating a cohesive description of what it means to be Asian American. I wanted to leave the course having learned something new about individual agency, cultural adaptation, and the dynamic interplay between heritage and assimilation. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get anything I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have learned from a typical U.S. history class, which left me disappointed and unfulfilled. If I want what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to find the answer somewhere else in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>I can recall one student commenting about some personal political attitudes in class one time that went against the traditional course dogma, only to be dismissed afterward.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Asian American Masculinity at the Cutting Edge&amp;rdquo;: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=5&amp;amp;v=KbytV1X3xwk&amp;amp;embeds_referring_euri=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;amp;source_ve_path=Mjg2NjY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=5&amp;amp;v=KbytV1X3xwk&amp;amp;embeds_referring_euri=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;amp;source_ve_path=Mjg2NjY&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Asian American is not a Color&amp;rdquo;: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=1&amp;amp;v=p3LJZnrXZ88&amp;amp;embeds_referring_euri=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;amp;source_ve_path=Mjg2NjY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=1&amp;amp;v=p3LJZnrXZ88&amp;amp;embeds_referring_euri=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;amp;source_ve_path=Mjg2NjY&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:4">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_minority">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_minority&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Useless Alone</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/useless-alone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/useless-alone/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/moon.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Useless Alone" />&lt;p>&lt;em>If you were transported back to 1200, what are some things that exist today that you could recreate or prove are possible to people back in the day?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve long pondered this question because it really shows us what we take for granted. When you think of it, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have a self-satisfactory answer to the question above. As a computer engineering student, I have absolutely no idea how I could even convey to the 1200-dwellers what a phone is. I may know how a computer works to the transistor level, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue of how to make one single transistor, much less make a whole machine. If you&amp;rsquo;re a software engineer making a six-figure salary, tough luck. You&amp;rsquo;d be less useful than the town jester back in 1200.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe computers aren&amp;rsquo;t fair game due to their sheer complexity. How about this: could I prove to them that the Earth is round? That&amp;rsquo;s a fact we take for granted every single day&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s not intuitive at all. It&amp;rsquo;s not normal to assume that hanging off the bottom of the Earth would feel the same as standing on the top. You probably would clown any flat-earther that exists today because they are such a small minority. But, could you convince a whole world full of flat-earthers who have never considered a spherical Earth? Good luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a biologist trying to prove the existence of cells, where are you going to find a microscope? If you&amp;rsquo;re an accountant, there is no financial system for you to work with (plus, no Excel). If you&amp;rsquo;re a lawyer, there&amp;rsquo;s barely a solid legal system for you to rely on. If you&amp;rsquo;re a doctor, you won&amp;rsquo;t have any of the tools and machinery you use on the daily today. If you&amp;rsquo;re a Starbucks barista, has coffee ever even been exported to your current location?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re probably even more useless than you think. Can you even make a simple pencil to write with? Can you make a backpack? Can you even build a chair from bare lumber? Probably not. We are all beneficiaries of an incredibly brilliant and complex environment&amp;ndash;one that allows us to be valuable to society. Without this system, we realize that we are virtually useless. Our skills only matter in the context of this environment. We should all have humility in the face of the blinding complexity that is our world. We should appreciate the systems that exist that allow us to live and thrive. We take a lot of things for granted, and we should. But, we should also acknowledge the past that allowed us to take these things for granted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Left and Right</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/left-and-right/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/left-and-right/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/leftright.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Left and Right" />&lt;p>I recently had an argument with my sister about workers&amp;rsquo; rights in the United States. We bickered about the issue back and forth, ultimately determining that our disagreements boiled down to our different worldviews. Although I won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily concede that she is as right as I am, I will say that it did teach me about the importance of opposing ideologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the political sphere, we can typically place people on the left-to-right wing ideological spectrum. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken this particular snippet from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Left%E2%80%93right_political_spectrum">Wikipedia&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Generally, the left wing is characterized by an emphasis on ideas such as freedom, equality, fraternity, rights, progress, reform, and internationalism&amp;quot; while the right wing is characterized by an emphasis on &amp;ldquo;notions such as authority, hierarchy, order, duty, tradition, reaction, and nationalism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In common politics, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the extremists at both ends of the spectrum battling it out on social media, headline news, and popular media. It&amp;rsquo;s an entertaining yet aggravating battle to watch, as most dialogues are extremely hostile and counterproductive. The heaviest proponents of either side will find it almost impossible to agree on any solution, as the way they see the issue is basically defined by completely different perspectives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both perspectives are necessary as they bring a sort of balance into the societal dynamic. The progressive left often concerns itself with &amp;ldquo;victims&amp;rdquo; of the system. It is characterized by historical movements of equality, pivotal moments of change, and a generally more &amp;ldquo;compassionate&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> attitude towards the dispossessed. On the other hand, the conservative right often concerns itself with adhering to tradition, personal initiative, stability, and hierarchies. It is inherently more reactionary, where the goal is to prevent the progressives from going too far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without the left, we&amp;rsquo;d still be in a KKK fascist world adhering to old bigoted ideas, enveloped in a system resistant to any kind of change. Without the right, we&amp;rsquo;d either be in a communist dystopia, a structureless, primal world without any societal backbone. Each side balances the other side, bringing a societal slider somewhere closer to the middle. There&amp;rsquo;s always an ongoing battle where that slider may shift too far to the left or to the right, which is going to be a battle to eternity or one that ends in imminent disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the argument with my sister, we considered the general problem of most people being unable to financially support themselves in a world that is becoming unsustainably expensive. Loosely speaking, she was concerned with people being unable to afford to live anymore due to a system that is broken, while I was concerned with many people not taking financial responsibility for their own lives. Both ideas are very fair and not mutually exclusive&amp;ndash;our system has broken in a way that has caused housing prices and inflation to skyrocket. Some solutions target a population or group level that can make things better for a lot of people. However, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that many people are neglecting their financial responsibilities, and a series of inaccurate or irresponsible decisions can cause a system-wide financial epidemic. We can have a better system with more educated and responsible citizens. It&amp;rsquo;s not so simple, either. The way you see the issue can overly influence what you think the root cause of the problem might be. At a political scale, this ideological disconnect can muddle or polarize an issue that might have a somewhat optimal solution. With a good enough system, the extremists will be knocked down a peg and you&amp;rsquo;ll end up finding this more centrist and reasonable solution. In some cases, one side is a lot more right about an issue than the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="progressive-vs-traditional-ideas">Progressive vs. Traditional Ideas&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Another dynamic I wanted to discuss is the nature of ideas brought up by the progressives and conservatives. Progressive ideas are progressive in the sense that they are new and challenge existing traditions. They are commonly overly unrealistic, idealistic, too surface-level, or flat-out harmful. This is because progressive ideas are &lt;em>new&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to come up with ideas and not so easy to come up with &lt;em>good&lt;/em> ideas. Progressives will offer solutions that are not thought out because it is incredibly hard to fully think things through in our extremely complex systems. When good progressive ideas are accepted as the new norm, they are usually tuned to a more reasonable degree&amp;ndash;after the conservatives have had their way with them. Conservatives stick to tradition because the only reason why traditional ideas exist is because they have worked (to some extent) in the past. They have a proven track record and have predictable outcomes. Progressives often challenge traditional ideas without fully understanding why they exist, bringing in novel ideas that break things in ways they haven&amp;rsquo;t considered. On the other hand, conservatives may be too rigid with tradition, holding onto outdated and potentially harmful ideas of the past. They are resistant to change when change is needed, which may cause bad ideas to go unpunished for long periods of time. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to see why progressives and conservatives need each other. They are each there to keep the other in check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s often hard to find the boundary between the two sides, as any individual&amp;rsquo;s moral and value system is strongly shaped by their ideological preference&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. People will find solace in their in-group, relating to those more similar to them. Even in gray areas, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to find some middle ground. Regardless of what side you are on, you can&amp;rsquo;t automatically dismiss the other side. They exist for a reason&amp;ndash;a reason that isn&amp;rsquo;t always clear at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Too much compassion for one party can often lead to vitriol for another party. That&amp;rsquo;s why most left-wing extremists are as toxic and arrogant as right-wing extremists.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>Your political leaning is very influenced by your personality. Women tend to be more compassionate and emotional (by a small margin), which partially explains why women are on average more left than men.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Career Value</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/career-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/career-value/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/career.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Career Value" />&lt;p>Most people will experience a dilemma at some point in their life where they are unsure of whether to pursue a career in the thing that they enjoy or pursue a career in something that will make more money. Some people are lucky and get both. However, most people realize that they can&amp;rsquo;t make a living building professional Lego sets for rich CEOs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s often a difficult decision. There&amp;rsquo;s a fine balance between choosing something you enjoy versus something that will make your life more comfortable. As a naive high school or college graduate, it is often tempting to want to pursue that one niche thing we were good at during our childhood. We hope it&amp;rsquo;ll carry us the whole nine yards, only to find out that there was never really a chance to begin with. Our parents may encourage us down the more practical, sustainable path, likely having witnessed horror stories of their friends&amp;rsquo; children failing to find a job. For my Chinese immigrant parents, it would have literally been impossible for them to get a visa to the United States without obtaining their graduate degrees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, you want people to try their hand at something risky because they love it. There&amp;rsquo;s a small chance of success, which may be worth the risk. On the other hand, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance they will fail and blame you for not pushing them harder to study or do something more useful. Humans are complicated and emotional. You&amp;rsquo;re probably going to lose no matter which option you suggest to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there&amp;rsquo;s a broader question here: why are some careers more encouraged than others? Why are some jobs higher paying than others? When I mentioned sustainable and high-paying careers, you probably imagined careers, in engineering, the medical field, computer science, or legal studies. They are notorious for their difficulty but extremely high return on investment&amp;ndash;all with a solid and promising career path (mostly STEM). When I mentioned risky or unsustainable careers, you probably thought of careers in art, music, history, food, or sports (mostly humanities). Jobs in these fields typically pay a lot less, and it&amp;rsquo;s way more difficult for you to &amp;ldquo;make it.&amp;rdquo; Some stars will rise to the top creating an image of glamour, but most people&amp;rsquo;s careers will never take off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of my friends are encouraged to go into computer science math or engineering. They know they will likely find high-paying jobs after they graduate, and their parents typically approve of their career choice. But, if everyone thought that way, our world would implode as it became saturated with Patagonia-vested, rock-climbing tech bros. Simply put, we need our artists, history experts, and musicians. We want some people out there to pick their interest in history despite knowing they won&amp;rsquo;t make as much money in life. We need indie producers to keep on pushing out music despite their small audiences. Some of these singers and rappers eventually make it and will shape our entire culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, why are some careers higher paying or more sustainable than others? It&amp;rsquo;s mostly due to the market, whether you like it or not. It decides the game. Everybody needs a doctor or a lawyer. People need their plumbers and electricians to fix their homes. We all need our cell phones and washing machines and airplanes and cars. The common thread of these higher-paying careers is that they directly impact the everyday lives of most people. They are in constant demand, and we need them to live[^1]. On the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s harder to explicitly outline what a history major or an amateur athlete or a painter does for you. A painter&amp;rsquo;s work or a humanities research may not be realized or valued for a long time. We may not realize their worth immediately or at all. Furthermore, it&amp;rsquo;s much harder for an individual to make an impact. While the most famous painters will completely shape what art means, most painters&amp;rsquo; names will never even be spoken. The value they add to society may be more indirect or harder to realize, and so, the market adjusts to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it should be this way, although I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good answer for it, either. If the market shouldn&amp;rsquo;t decide what a career or job is worth, then who should? How do we create a system that still incentivizes people to try things that society devalues or doesn&amp;rsquo;t encourage? We want a society full of people tackling different problems. In our own little worlds, we don&amp;rsquo;t realize the value that even the most &amp;ldquo;insignificant&amp;rdquo; people have on our lives. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to scoff at that person who clearly made the wrong career choice and may be suffering now. But, if people like that never tried at all, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even be alive today to judge. However, life isn&amp;rsquo;t fair. The incentive system that exists today drives certain careers above others in terms of monetary value. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to change this system without pulling up its roots. And maybe, we don&amp;rsquo;t have a better option.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good Enough</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/good-enough/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/imperfect.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Good Enough" />&lt;p>Exactness is rarely achievable in daily life. In most situations, we expect things to be &amp;ldquo;good enough,&amp;rdquo; where we&amp;rsquo;re okay with a result despite knowing it could be better. There is always some tolerance and wiggle room. Spending an extra 5 hours editing your essay after a two-day grind will barely make a difference. Toyota is fine with some parts being off by a few micrometers. Google Maps uses an algorithm that is &lt;em>likely&lt;/em> to be the fastest route. In these scenarios, we don&amp;rsquo;t expect 100% perfect optimization. We understand that what we have is good enough, where squeezing out improvements is never worth the tradeoff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the tradeoff? Usually, it&amp;rsquo;s time, money, effort, or a combination of all three. Editing for 5 hours will barely make your essay 1% better. Making a more precise part will increase manufacturing expenses twofold. Having a perfect navigation algorithm will run a hell of a lot slower. In life, we are almost always okay with &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo; Most of the time, perfection isn&amp;rsquo;t even feasible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="application-in-schools">Application in schools&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We have a lot of indicators in life that people can use to estimate things. A lot of the time, these indicators are bogus. But sometimes, they can be quite helpful. For example, your GPA is a relatively good indicator of your academic capability. There are many cases where this isn&amp;rsquo;t true. Some schools have insane grade inflation. Some majors are way easier than others. Some people learn perpendicular to the grain of the way the average person learns. But, within specific domains, GPA is often a &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; estimator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No set of metrics can holistically represent a person, their personality, or their capabilities. If you really wanted someone to understand who you are via paper, would you even be able to do so? The transfer of information is always an imperfect medium, which is why it could take years for us to really get to know someone. When colleges are assessing your abilities, they&amp;rsquo;ll look at your GPA, student activities, SAT score, and essays to get a glimpse of your character. They deem these sets of metrics to be &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; estimators. Why are these metrics good enough? Across a population, Harvard will get a good chunk of the most capable students in the United States. They may miss a few good apples here and there and pick up a few rotten apples as well, but overall, their selection process is &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo; Any one individual they miss out on is not a dealbreaker.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="application-in-hiring">Application in hiring&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When you apply for a job, most companies will use your resume, a series of interviews, and a background check as &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; estimators of your fit for a given role. It&amp;rsquo;s not always an exact science, since many companies will hire bad employees that will cost them a lot of time and money. However, they are generally &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; because most of their candidate picks will have a positive expected value (obviously, some companies do much better than others).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When they pass resumes in bulk through some computer algorithm that filters for GPA &amp;gt; 3.0, they may be removing many super-qualified candidates that would do a great job. However, this risk is worth it, because they can narrow their pool down to &amp;ldquo;probably good candidates.&amp;rdquo; They understand that looking into candidates with low GPAs will waste a lot of time, and it&amp;rsquo;s not worth it to search for a gem within the rubble (harsh but good metaphor)—the same for those pesky trading firms that almost exclusively hire from MIT or Ivy League schools. There are great students without degrees or at different schools, but these companies expect the concentration of good candidates among them to be much lower. Instead of looking through 10k applicants, they can narrow it down to a few hundred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One area of controversy often revolves around the use of coding assessments within the tech industry. Most companies will have a few rounds of behavioral interviews (background, experience, personality) as well as a few rounds of technical interviews (sometimes offered after an initial coding screen). These technical interviews often revolve around solving difficult coding problems outside the typical realm of what you might do at most jobs. People often complain that these coding assessments are not representative of the skills needed to excel at the company and are a waste of time. While I understand the sentiment, critics should understand that these coding assessments are simply &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; estimators of job aptitude.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People may have good projects on their resume, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard for hiring managers to see how truly good they are, whether they are legit or embellished, or whether any given applicant is being deceitful. Therefore, they need some sort of aptitude test to ensure candidates are as good as they say. Most tech companies do not have the time to create individually tailored assessments for each role they hire for. They want tests that are broad enough to cover many roles while assessing the capability of their candidates. Coding assessments were the ultimate solution: they test the ability to program with a language, critical thinking, data structures, and general reasoning skills. Every applicant has different skills they could test for, but everyone who applies must know how to program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being good at these assessments doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you are good at using whatever technology the job calls for, but the companies think the correlation must be &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo; Together with a resume showing off job-specific skills, a coding assessment can show that the candidate at minimum has good technical chops as well. Remember, these tests are also filters to show who is definitely not qualified. There is no chance you are a skilled candidate if you can barely code during the interview. You may struggle with solving a problem, but at least, you have to know how to do things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are there extremely gifted developers who can do amazing work but suck at coding tests? Yeah, for sure. It&amp;rsquo;s simply just more unlikely. These tech giants don&amp;rsquo;t need to solely hire god-tier applicants. They just need to be sure most of their candidates are good. They&amp;rsquo;re fine missing a gem every now and then. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to put in 10x the effort to achieve a 10% better employee pool. These companies are driven by their desire to make as much profit as possible. If they knew these coding assessments were not worthwhile, you know they&amp;rsquo;d be the first to jump ship for a method that better brings in the bag.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="takeaway-for-us">Takeaway, for us&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not saying any of this is fair. But, for practical purposes, these estimators are &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; for a reason. In any individual circumstance, it&amp;rsquo;s okay to feel cheated. It&amp;rsquo;s normal to think &amp;ldquo;They just don&amp;rsquo;t understand me.&amp;rdquo; You may be right, but to an uncompromising school or corporation, you&amp;rsquo;re just a fish in the water. If you are good and cast your net wide enough, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a bite. It&amp;rsquo;s a matter of time, patience, and effort. Many things aren&amp;rsquo;t fair. They&amp;rsquo;re simply just &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perfection Takes Time</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/perfection-takes-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/perfection-takes-time/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/blocks.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Perfection Takes Time" />&lt;p>I often struggle with having imperfect work. My impatience leads me down a path where everything I do has to be perfect the first time. My first essay draft must be exact, my code must be optimally efficient, and homework has to be 100% correct and robust. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent countless hours dwelling on tiny details, making 0.1% improvements instead of big sweeping changes that actually matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My attention often narrows on the most minute of details, which often prevents me from seeing the picture. I often procrastinate tedious work, simply because I know I will feel unsatisfied for hours on end trying to achieve perfection. It&amp;rsquo;s often this mindset of perfection that halts me from making progress. When starting a new venture or task, getting something out the door is step one. The details come as we go, piecing together slowly over time until some semblance of perfection is reached. Most aspects of life are comprised of iterative steps and improvements on a solid foundation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good, solid base is necessary, but a perfect one is not. Imperfect work can be improved. Mistakes can be fixed. But, you have to have something to start with first. Most of the most successful people were people who have tried a lot and failed a lot. They go through 10 ideas in the time that the average person takes to go through one. They put a lot at risk, but that risk is what can usher in the reward. A focus on perfection at the start simply stifles the development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel uneasy when things aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly the way I want it to be, and this small feeling of uneasiness prevents me from doing bigger things. I can appreciate my mindset in some situations, but I can recognize it isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal. A good mindset is a balance of making rapid development at the start, only to refine when refinement is needed. A methodology that goes against my nature will be hard to internalize and act on, but integrating an existing mindset into a better one may just strike the chord I need.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t let the perfect be the enemy of the good.
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfect_is_the_enemy_of_good">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfect_is_the_enemy_of_good&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>What is Reasonable?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/what-is-reasonable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/what-is-reasonable/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/reasonable.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What is Reasonable?" />&lt;p>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering on the idea of reasonableness. It&amp;rsquo;s a word that carries a lot of weight, where its applicability to any situation is highly subjective and can be easily contested. In most scenarios, there is some semblance of agreement between most parties regarding what is considered reasonable. More aptly, ideas where a reasonable amount of people can agree on what is deemed reasonable. A good metric to assess reasonableness is to determine whether it carries more reward than risk. More reasonable items carry substantially more reward than risk or have no risk at all. In daily life, reasonableness can be easily determined. However, in difficult situations, things can get a lot more tricky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to perform an action that has a small but nonzero chance of dying. Would you do it? Maybe, depending on how small that probability is. Let&amp;rsquo;s say across your lifetime, the odds of you dying is around 1 in 93. Would you still do it? If you said &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;, then I guess you&amp;rsquo;d better never drive again. This example isn&amp;rsquo;t so black and white, though. Even though your chances of dying or killing someone while driving are slim, most people still choose to drive. Although the benefit you get from any one drive is small, it compounds over the course of time, where it would essentially be impossible to do anything in your life if you couldn&amp;rsquo;t drive. With this argument, maybe the rewards do outweigh the risks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not so simple, though. We engage in risky activities all of the time that aren&amp;rsquo;t as &amp;ldquo;reasonable&amp;rdquo; as driving a car. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s speeding down the road or the freeway when you&amp;rsquo;re late to a meeting, having a few cheat days in a row during a diet, or spending a hefty percentage of your paycheck on that one thing you don&amp;rsquo;t really need, we choose to ignore risk for brief periods of time. Under an objective lens, speeding down the road dramatically increases your chance of injury and death. Even worse, you can end up harming innocent bystanders. All of this to maybe save a few minutes off your commute. With this context, you should never even dream of speeding on your way to work. Although the chances for you to crash while speeding are pretty slim, across the globe, thousands of people will die because of this &amp;ldquo;reasonable&amp;rdquo; decision. Despite the risk, we just move on with our day.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="a-case-study-covid-19">A Case Study: COVID-19&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The one topic I&amp;rsquo;ve found the most controversial about reasonable behavior is disease. During COVID-19, the entire world went into shutdown while an unknown virus wreaked havoc. After months of researchers frantically researching this new disease, we slowly began to understand the virus, its adverse effects, and potential measures we could take to fight it. During this time, there was a huge debate on whether we should open the countries back up or stay locked down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lockdown advocates and critics could both agree that more people would die if we opened the country up. Typically, more death is bad and certain more death is even worse. A &amp;ldquo;reasonable&amp;rdquo; decision would just be to keep the lockdowns forever. As usual, it&amp;rsquo;s not so simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think everyone can agree that at some point, we needed to end the lockdowns. It was just a matter of when. Regardless of when we opened back up, more people would die as a result. If you criticized lockdown dissenters for killing more people by opening up the country, you are essentially doing the same thing if you ever wanted the country to open up again. Even if to a lesser extent, you are still &amp;ldquo;killing people.&amp;rdquo; The safest option would be to lockdown forever, or long enough to where COVID no longer existed. But clearly, that&amp;rsquo;s unreasonable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another hot topic of debate was the issue of masking. Some people wanted to remove mask mandates early on, while other people wanted to keep them around. In this case again (not discussing the efficacy of masking), it&amp;rsquo;s an issue of reducing risk, where not masking would supposedly cause more death. As was the case before, almost everyone would agree that we needed to remove the mandates at some point&amp;ndash;the question was just when. And as was the case before, regardless of when we did (assuming masking was effective), we would end up killing more people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We all might have held that the anti-vaxxers and anti-maskers were responsible for an increased COVID-19 death toll. They had an easy choice to prevent the spread of a deadly disease but decided against it. However, most of us are guilty of the same things, even if we don&amp;rsquo;t want to admit it. There&amp;rsquo;s a chance that we made someone seriously ill that time we took that exam despite having a cough. There&amp;rsquo;s a chance that one time we didn&amp;rsquo;t properly wash our hands, our germs may have ended an immunocompromised person&amp;rsquo;s life. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying these things are all morally equivalent to the example above. However, I am saying that they are not as different as you would like to believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a disease- and risk-free world, we should lock down forever to prevent all diseases from spreading. Everyone would mask forever to prevent anyone else from ever getting sick again. We would never touch or talk to anyone ever again. Clearly, this is unreasonable. This is unreasonable without even considering the secondary consequences of lockdowns and masking: the degradation of education quality, the destruction caused to relationships, and the increased drug overdoses from lockdowns. My point is not to convince you of whether any of these measures were good or bad. I just want you to see how everything is much more complicated than what meets the eye. Having a black-and-white image of what is good or bad, reasonable or unreasonable, is simply too shallow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, we all allow some tolerance of risk, even if the result ends up with more suffering. We have to realize that no matter what we do, there is always risk involved. Some people will thrive and some people will suffer regardless of what you do. Too often, people are forced into shallow factions, debating issues at a surface level without considering secondary or tertiary consequences. It boils down to one simple metric (e.g. death) that can&amp;rsquo;t possibly contextualize the whole situation. I don&amp;rsquo;t advocate for you to be more fuzzy with your opinions or morals. But, I do encourage more nuanced opinions with more consideration of factors that most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think of. It&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to contextualize the world in a way you have never seen before.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="inspiration">Inspiration&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This thought process originated from when I did competitive debate back in high school. For every argument, we were supposed to &lt;em>weigh&lt;/em> our impact. The idea was that each argument had a variety of consequences, and the goal was to prove why your benefits or consequences were better or worse than your opponents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s say for a given topic, team A&amp;rsquo;s impact was that if we did some action X, we would grow the economy by 30%. Team B&amp;rsquo;s impact is that if we did action X, we would worsen climate change substantially. Both teams want to argue how their argument &amp;ldquo;outweighs&amp;rdquo; their opponents, i.e. how the benefits and consequences (secondary, tertiary, etc.) should be more important at the end of the day. Examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Team A: with a 30% better economy, we can invest more money in green energy, offsetting climate change.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team A: people&amp;rsquo;s lives will be better, which matters more than climate, which we can adapt to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team B: climate change will happen so fast that the effects will be detrimental before any green energy can be enacted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team B: even with people&amp;rsquo;s lives improving, more people will die, which is worse than any marginal benefits&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It was an aspect of debate that encouraged teams to be as creative as possible. We would have to argue why growing the economy was more important than a potential nuclear war, or why preserving moral principles is more important than saving a million lives. It forced me into a critical lens where things weren&amp;rsquo;t black and white, where you had to evaluate layers of information, where there are benefits and consequences of all action and inaction. In the end, it allowed me to better understand risk, suffering, and their considerations in everyday life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Shifting Concept of Ethnicity</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/shifting-concept-ethnicity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/shifting-concept-ethnicity/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/mix.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Shifting Concept of Ethnicity" />&lt;p>We live in a unique time where the homogeneity within groups is on the decline. Historically, the world has been split by region, nationality, and ethnicity. You expect to find ethnically Chinese people in China, Indians in India, Africans in Africa, etc. Even more ambiguously, we have a current concept of what it means to be white, black, or Asian. Even in the middle East where the concept of ethnicity doesn&amp;rsquo;t really exist anymore, we can still identify them by being &amp;ldquo;Middle Eastern.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is quickly changing in the western world, where people are starting to become a hodgepodge of multiple ethnicities and races. Many families, particularly first-generation immigrant ones, still want and expect their children to marry people of their race. Whether it be for cultural, historical, or even somewhat racist reasons, their children will slowly (or even quickly) care less about preserving race. As we move down the generations, the concept of race will slowly dissolve as people become a mix of well&amp;hellip;everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will essentially be the first time in history where race and ethnicity are not clearly defined. In places like the United States, the concept of Asian or black culture will cease to exist as the clear-cut groups with culturally-unifying qualities slowly merge together. My theory is that we&amp;rsquo;ll all sort of form a unifying &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo; culture that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have a particular identity today. It really puts all the stupid racial barriers we talk about today into context, where the differences that exist between groups are temporary and socially arranged. In the end, I hope we&amp;rsquo;ll see that we&amp;rsquo;re all just human, where we can no longer blame our circumstances on socially-constructed barriers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Battle of the Sexes</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/battle-of-the-sexes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/battle-of-the-sexes/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/battle-sexes.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Battle of the Sexes" />&lt;p>My recent Instagram Reels feed has been a battleground between the sexes. You might see a short clip of a supercifical and shallow dating show solely focused on first impressions. Or, you might find a video of a street interview of random strangers about dating expectations. Regardless, these reels about how men and women treat one another will have a warzone in the comments. It&amp;rsquo;s a coin flip whether you&amp;rsquo;ll see a tsunami of men complaining about how unfaithful women are or torrent of women complaining about how men ruin everything. Every now and then, you might find a slurry of both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often leave these comment sections bemused, angry, or disappointed. To some extent, all of these crazies have a point. On the other hand, they all collectively miss the point. Why have these people come to a point where they see the relationship between men and women as a battle to be won? People of each party wants to prove that they have a harder time in life or in relationships. Each side wants to prove that the other side is corrupt beyond repair. &lt;em>All men are pigs&lt;/em>, they say. &lt;em>All women are for the streets&lt;/em>, they say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, why? Do you want to be right? Do you want to be bitter and resentful? In the end, most of these people want a stable and fulfilling relationship. Instead of looking at difficult situations on a case-by-case basis with consideration for their hypothetical partner, these online warriors want to force their black-and-white, uncontexualized opinions onto others as undeniable truths. Any deviation from their opinion is a symptom of a declining and bigoted society, and any pushback against them is simply dismissed with a series of pejorative remarks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fighting for a good future is a collaborative effort between all parties. If we all just end up being pitted against one another, we all lose. Even if you win the online battle, all you&amp;rsquo;ve done is limited your future prospects of a good relationship. Unfortunately, social media has polarized the masses, becoming a prime battlefield for this cyber-driven human disconnect. As the youth grows up surrounded by digital discord, their heads will be filled with unrealistic and pessimistic expectations for their future relationships. They&amp;rsquo;ll become the soldiers for a war that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not everything needs to be a battle. A villifying mindset will only deepen a divide that, in the context of history, is the smallest it has ever been. My advice is: don&amp;rsquo;t engage. You have your life to worry about. Your problems will never fit the stencils that the online cesspool fabricate. Don&amp;rsquo;t fight battles for other people, mostly when they&amp;rsquo;re on a platform that was created to steal your attention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>"Do What Makes You Happy"</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/do-what-makes-you-happy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/do-what-makes-you-happy/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/false-happiness.jpg" alt="Featured image of post "Do What Makes You Happy"" />&lt;p>I was scrolling on Twitter, and I ran into this tweet:&lt;/p>
&lt;figcaption>Not saying I have an opinion on this matter in particular, it was just the inspiration to write this.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of people on social media echo this sentiment: let people do what makes them happy. This seems to make sense to a lot of people, and why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it? We all want to be happy. If someone does something that makes them happy, who are we to judge?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think about this statement even a little more, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty surface level. A lot of things make people happy. Should anyone be able to do something simply because it makes them happy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The easiest counterexample to this is to look at parents and children. Imagine your child wants to eat crayons because he likes the way they taste. Are you going to let him? Hell no. But, it makes him happy! We don&amp;rsquo;t care, because we know better. He shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be gnawing on these cancerous plastic coloring sticks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are we limiting his freedom to choose? Yes, we are, because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand the consequences. The same sort of logic applies to everyone else. We see our friends choose to something they think will make them &amp;ldquo;happy,&amp;rdquo; often without understanding the consequences. Maybe they want to try that one hardcore drug, hookup with their toxic ex, or party in that suspicious-looking club. They want to chase that cheap thrill while warning signs are screaming in your head. Do you stand back and let them, simply because they think it&amp;rsquo;ll make them happy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a society, we are responsible for looking after one another. Happiness isn&amp;rsquo;t a justification to do whatever you want. It never has been and never should be. Nowadays, we are far too willing to let people get away with this excuse. How do we even quantify happiness? It might temporarily make them happy while they regret it in the long run. Even if nothing bad happens, they may have been more satisfied with an alternative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happiness is a vague and fluctuating emotion and is not always aligned with reality. Our impulses often control us more than we&amp;rsquo;d like to admit. Don&amp;rsquo;t you think that thief who stole that TV from Best Buy just wanted to be happy? This is a more clear cut example that obviously everyone understands because there&amp;rsquo;s collateral damage. We don&amp;rsquo;t like when people&amp;rsquo;s happiness intrudes on someone else&amp;rsquo;s happiness. But, what if there is no collateral damage? We are more willing to let people get away with things then. But usually, who takes the hit? It&amp;rsquo;s the person themself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, we don&amp;rsquo;t have control of most people like parents have over their children. We cannot compel anyone to do anything, nor should we be able to. But, we can have a say, particularly for people that we care about. Don&amp;rsquo;t let someone do something dumb because it might make them happy. They might not even know what happiness really means. You might just be the one to save them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="sacrificing-happiness">Sacrificing Happiness&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In many cases, happiness is a rather selfish desire where we prioritize our personal wellbeing at the expense of others. We might roast someone else for laughs, take someone else&amp;rsquo;s opportunity, flake on a birthday party for something more fun, and more. In these cases, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s okay not to be happy because it&amp;rsquo;s more important to be virtuous. Even in our short and potentially meaningless lives, we can do a lot of good and a lot of bad. The universe may have chosen to make you suffer more than others. Some of us might just be unlucky. But in the end, our pursuit of happiness should not be at the cost of others. Somtimes, it&amp;rsquo;s okay to suffer. It&amp;rsquo;s what makes us human.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You might agree with everything I&amp;rsquo;ve said, so I want to challenge you to the following situation: let&amp;rsquo;s say you get married and have a child with your signficiant other (SO). But at some point, you realize you and your SO are not meant for one another. You don&amp;rsquo;t love each other anymore and want nothing to do with one another. You may choose to divorce. What&amp;rsquo;s the collateral? The collateral is your child, who will suffer from the lack of a stable household with both parents, which is stasticially shown to do undue harm to them&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Despite this, most people I&amp;rsquo;ve asked would choose to divorce in order to be happy. How is this more acceptable than stealing a $100 item from Walmart? You&amp;rsquo;re doing a lot more damage than that, but divorce is not as frowned upon as theft. What would you choose?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I talk about issues in this piece that are pretty uncontroversial in nature. This was intentional. I want you to think about some more serious situations where this thought process might be relevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.medicinenet.com/how_does_single_parenting_affect_a_child/article.htm">https://www.medicinenet.com/how_does_single_parenting_affect_a_child/article.htm&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Implicit vs. Explicit Knowledge</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/implicit-explicit-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/implicit-explicit-knowledge/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/knowledge.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Implicit vs. Explicit Knowledge" />&lt;p>I was sitting in a professional learning and development meeting today about resilience and collaboration. He was quite the animated and engaging speaker, but as usual, most of everything he said was pretty basic and self-explanatory. I would argue that it was all common sense. I&amp;rsquo;ve felt this way about many of my classes before&amp;ndash;mostly the non-STEM ones. In my communications class, of course, there&amp;rsquo;s verbal and nonverbal communication. In my systems class, of course, some systems are complex and some are simple. In my design class, of course, we should make mockups before actually building products. In many of these situations, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever left thinking I had learned anything new or revolutionary. I&amp;rsquo;ve walked out thinking a class was completely useless simply because I felt like the material was obvious. Over time, I began to realize that I may have been thinking of these things the wrong way&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that verbalizing and conceptualizing a trivial concept changes the way we think about things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to bring light to the difference between implicit and explicit knowledge&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Implicit knowledge is knowledge we consider to be common sense. It&amp;rsquo;s the assumptions that can be expressed without necessarily having to conceptualize something tangible. For example, when brainstorming new ideas for a project, you and your teammates might write quick ideas on sticky notes and put them on a board. After a quick brainstorming session, you group similar ideas and try to pick the ones worth keeping. This is a pretty natural process that a lot of people would also come up with. However, in the corporate world, there&amp;rsquo;s a defined and accepted term for this process: affinity mapping. Imagine your professor in your consulting class brought attention to this idea, telling your group that this is a good way to get a project going. This idea is so simple, straightforward, and obvious that you might not think much of it. But, explicitly conceptualizing this idea turns it into something tangible that you can refer to moving forward. Introducing the physical idea of affinity mapping is where the implicit knowledge becomes explicit knowledge&amp;ndash;information that is documented, codified, and easily communicated with other people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are four insights. First, making ideas concrete and tangible in our minds allows us to exploit our knowledge to the fullest extent. People make frameworks of simple and obvious ideas for this reason. We most effectively use something when it is concrete. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to exploit ideas that kind of just float around in our heads, and they only become useful once they exist in an organized way. A pie chart is an obvious and easy way of showing percentages. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple idea, but without being taught about pie charts by your teachers, would you instinctively think to use one to represent percentage data?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, everything taught is explicit knowledge. Humans are literally made to think in organized ways. The whole reason you go to school is to learn things and information that is explicit and codified. We don&amp;rsquo;t learn things in a jumble. We organize learning into subjects and topics, grouping ideas that are similar and relevant to one another. Algebra doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in nature. Humans did work on math, realized that there was some unifying backbone between certain ideas, and grouped it into one topic and called it &amp;ldquo;algebra.&amp;rdquo; All classes teach some things that are common sense. Some classes only teach things that are common sense. But, when you really think about it, they are codifying knowledge that you might have but do not explicitly organize in your head. When you approach problems in the future, these classes teach you what to think and how to think based on what worked in the past. It removes the guesswork and how much active thinking you have to do, letting you focus only on what is actually important&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Third, human experience is implicit knowledge. When you&amp;rsquo;re sitting in the shower and have a realization, you&amp;rsquo;re converting your implicit knowledge into explicit knowledge. You turn things you have observed and were aware of into something with meaning. No one else has this knowledge because no one else is you. The act of thinking itself is simply a conversion of implicit knowledge to explicit knowledge. It&amp;rsquo;s funny that we have to think. When you are given a math problem, you already have all the information necessary to solve it (given that there is a solution). Instead, we have to figure out the intermediate steps to get to the answer rather than just having the answer on the spot. That&amp;rsquo;s because not everything is known at once. Things have to be figured out. Implicit knowledge has to become explicit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly, this discussion was pretty trivial. This whole piece might be so obvious that it didn&amp;rsquo;t even need to be written. It&amp;rsquo;s very possible I created a deep topic out of something shallow. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible that all of this is simply nonsense. Regardless, by writing this, I have converted some implicit knowledge into explicit knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>I assume there is some term for this phenomenon somewhere out there, but this is a concept I tried to think of myself.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>This is a theoretical discussion. Some teachers suck. Some classes are actually useless. But, some supposedly useless classes may have been useful in ways you didn&amp;rsquo;t consider.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Right to Judge</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/right-to-judge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/right-to-judge/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/judge.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Right to Judge" />&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to intrude on other people&amp;rsquo;s lives. I like to exist in parallel, only interfering when it actually matters. When it comes to strangers or acquaintances, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less about what they do. They lead their own lives and deal with their own struggles. Who am I to say anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, we all reserve the right to judge. In these days, it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful that people have the freedom to make almost any choice they wish. However, it also seems that we are expected to be accepting of those choices. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the case. People make bad choices&amp;ndash;if not flat out wrong choices&amp;ndash;all the time. Yes, you have the freedom to make those choices. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s ultimately your decision to make. But, it&amp;rsquo;s also our freedom to judge. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to comply with what we think. After all, we could be the ones that are wrong. But, just because you made a choice doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we don&amp;rsquo;t have a say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone is judging everyone and everything constantly. We view the world with a certain lens and a certain set of values. A lot of people do things that go against those values. And when they do, we judge. We live in an imperfect world where no one is perfect. After all, we violate our own morals from time to time. It&amp;rsquo;s human nature. In recent years, we&amp;rsquo;re asked not to judge. But, why not? People aren&amp;rsquo;t making fewer mistakes now than they did in the past. Why should we stop now?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my experience, people are still just as judgemental as before. People may hide it, but they still view things in a critical lens. After all, we have to evaluate everything in our lives with some value system. Otherwise, how can we decide what deserves attention and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t? When you catch that super senior flirting with freshmen, go ahead and judge. When you see that girl from your school posting feet pics on OnlyFans, it&amp;rsquo;s fine to disapprove. A judgement is simply an opinion. An opinion that may be right or wrong. An opinion, usually without the full story. An opinion nonetheless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can always choose to be empathetic. Most of the time, people have reasons why they do things that you may frown upon. Whether it be from trauma, differences in upbringing, or simply a difference in values, you should always understand where people are coming from. At the same time, simply understanding doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you approve. Someone reading their partners texts without permission because their ex cheated on them is understandable. However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it right, nor is it the right solution. Recognizing this is a big deal because you&amp;rsquo;ll know when you should make judgement calls. More importantly, you can diagnose a problem by understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When people say don&amp;rsquo;t judge, just don&amp;rsquo;t judge someone&amp;rsquo;s full character by a snapshot of behavior. They&amp;rsquo;re not perfect, and neither are you. But, you can and should judge people&amp;rsquo;s behavior, given enough context. Don&amp;rsquo;t let people you care about get away with something simply because it&amp;rsquo;s their choice. Even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t harm you or anyone else, it may harm them. And its our responsibility to look after them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Society always tends towards the progressive. After all, there are new ieas that the traditional elitists aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to explore. But, new ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t always good. People are welcome to make decisions in their lives. A crack down on personal choice is just tryannical. But, we don&amp;rsquo;t have to agree with people&amp;rsquo;s decisions. In some cases, we should oppose their decisions. Whether they choose to listen is up to them. But, we still reserve the right to judge.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In a New City</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/in-a-new-city/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/in-a-new-city/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/new-city.jpg" alt="Featured image of post In a New City" />&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m in New York City for the summer. It&amp;rsquo;s for an internship. This is what I wanted. A departure from my last one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I found myself in the suburbs of San Francisco last summer. I was too far from the city to visit often. I had no car. There was no subway, and I was only armed with a very slow and oversized bike. I found myself having nothing to do after work. I would be able to see some friends from high school over the weekend, taking the expensive Caltrain to visit them with my less than minimum wage salary. Although I found it initially quite isolating, I was able to make do. The gym and dancing kept me busy. I called my friends day-in and day-out. They kept me sane during those times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted something else this summer. I wanted to be in New York. It&amp;rsquo;s closer to home and nearer to all my friends. In &lt;em>the&lt;/em> bustling city, how could I be alone?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After my arrival last week, I felt a new kind of isolation. In a city surrounded by all kinds of people that you can imagine, I know almost nobody. I have access to everything, yet I still fall short. Over the weekend, I wandered the streets alone. I see friends chatting, couples coupling, and families trotting about. In restaurants, I sit with menu in hand, surrounded by a buzz of hollow laughter. Last year, I had nothing. This year, I have everything. But sometimes, everything at once can be too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s all in my head. This feeling of desolation is self-inflicted. I have all the options in the world. But in the face of it all, I am frozen. There are too many choices, too many adventures. I don&amp;rsquo;t know which way is right. I box myself into thinking nothing will work out. But, is that worse than what I have to suffer if I do nothing? Probably not. In my desperate moments, I feel that I have no way out. But, I do. Almost every option is within a stretched arms reach. I just have to grab it. It&amp;rsquo;s really not that hard. It&amp;rsquo;s all in my head.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Human Creativity</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/human-creativity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/human-creativity/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/human-creativity.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Human Creativity" />&lt;p>With the rise of AI-generated content, will AI completely replace human creativity? Even if human-created content far outpaces what AIs can do today, how much longer will this be true? For those who scoff about how AI still makes major mistakes, remember that we&amp;rsquo;re in year 2-3 of a developmental journey that will last the rest of time. In ten or even a hundred years, do you really think that AI will still be lagging behind?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AIs can generate art faster than the fastest artists and can write stories faster than any writer. Even if lesser quality, we can only imagine what happens once AI catches up. Moreover, most people are not artists or writers. AIs now are better than the vast majority of ordinary people. Even if Midjourney generates a 6th finger sometimes, can you even draw five normal ones?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does this mean for us? If AIs can someday generate superb movies based on a script (that it could generate itself) in a fraction of the time and budget of an actual film studio, what happens then? What if AIs can generate triple-A quality games in a few days rather than the years it takes a normal game studio to create one? What if AI art becomes so good and realistic that there is no longer a differentiation between human and AI-generated art?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This thought first struck me when I was walking around in an anime marketplace in San Francisco, where I saw a sign in front of some artwork that said &amp;ldquo;NOT AI-generated.&amp;rdquo; Why would this matter? If the art was AI-generated, does that change whether you buy it? Surprisingly, the answer is probably yes. Even if we couldn&amp;rsquo;t visually tell the difference, there&amp;rsquo;s value in the fact that the degenerate anime waifu was drawn by a real person and not just an algorithm. Logically, this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. The art is still the same art, regardless of the creator. But, we like it when we know there was a real human that toiled night and day to produce something meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same principle applies to the most famous art pieces. A lot of art today is on par or superior to the paintings by Da Vinci or Picasso but are worth tens of dollars instead of millions. We assign value simply because the paintings were painted by someone famous, often combined with some sort of unique historical context behind the piece. None of this changes the final artwork, but the story behind it clearly matters to how we value it. Likewise, each art piece by a human carries a story that an AI-generated piece cannot possibly have. For this reason, I think most people would be much more comfortable and accepting of watching a movie created by humans rather than an AI-generated one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In most domains, we simply value human effort more than any other kind of effort. We typically value handcrafted artisanal pieces, hand-stitched designs, and hand-baked goods more than factory-made ones. We typically value musicians, singers, and performers more than their robotic or electronic counterparts. If a robot could play piano better than all living pianists, who would go see it? Nobody! The concertgoers appreciate the story behind the pianist&amp;ndash;their upbringing, talent, preparation, and skill&amp;ndash;things that a robot cannot have. We watch chess grandmasters play chess at a way lower level than the best engines. We spend more money on the hand-spun silk cloth rather than the factory-produced one. We do all of these things despite probably not thinking much about why. And maybe the why is illogical or even wrong, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. That&amp;rsquo;s just the way humans today are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This might not be the case forever. I really believe we are at a turning point in history because, for the first time, artificial creations are starting to be able to do the most &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo; things better than humans. In 100 years, the kids growing up will have grown up with all of this AI-generated content&amp;ndash; it won&amp;rsquo;t be a surprise to them anymore. Maybe, they won&amp;rsquo;t care at all about whether something was human- or AI-generated. Maybe watching a purely AI-generated Spiderman 1000 with crazy explosions will be all the hype. I can only imagine the consequences this might have. What happens in a world where human creativity is outpaced and outmatched by AI? What happens when the floor for creativity is so high that almost no one reaches it? Will humanity be diluted into oblivion? Would this mean the AIs practically have control over our lives, even if indirectly? Or, will our current values survive the test of time? We can only speculate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overthinking</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/overthinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/overthinking/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/overthinking.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Overthinking" />&lt;p>There are a few things in life that I am good at. Out of all of them, I’m the best at overthinking. Despite never even wanting to do it, I have become a master. With my unintentionally dutiful training, I have become the best at the thing I want to do the least.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through analyzing my personality over the years, I became more aware of how often I overthink the most mundane situations. From interactions with my friends, texting my girlfriend, or working on group projects, I’ve always had a persistent tendency to imagine that I have somehow been perceived in a bad light. It’s not that I worry that things I said were taken the wrong way, I also begin to regret saying the things I did. It’s a constant cycle of worry where I believe I’ve done something that would make people like me less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These thoughts are typically baseless, too. I’ve been told if I didn’t really do anything, I have nothing to worry about. But, staring at that unread message never fails to make me wonder what I could have possibly done wrong. It makes me find scrutiny in the simplest of actions. I won’t say it’s completely bad, either. It makes me reflect on what I’ve done and allows me to understand myself better. No doubt I can navigate more sensitive situations with more care and attention. But more often than not, it’s self-destructive. It makes me question my relationships, my self-confidence, and my capabilities. Hypothetical situations can ruin my mood and cause me to mentally spiral despite not being a reality. I will these doomsday scenarios into existence by allowing them to affect me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I become too careful at times, where I hide my thoughts and actions under a veil of uncertainty and fear of judgment. It prevents me from opening up or following my own values and principles. It makes me unable to be honest with myself in the moment. I’ve realized that it likely isn’t something I can fix or should fix. My neurotic tendencies make me the person that I am. Becoming a more stoic carefree person would really change parts of me that I don’t think should change. And even if I wanted to, I feel like there’s a ceiling to how much I can change my heart. However, there’s clearly room to grow. I should find the confidence to not be completely consumed by overthinking. Ideally, it could just be a lens to guide me through situations without melting me down. Then, I could harness just the positive aspects of something I consider negative, which could help me embrace my weaknesses. Or maybe, this is all just me overthinking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Makes a Person Bad?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bad-person/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bad-person/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/bad-person.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What Makes a Person Bad?" />&lt;p>My friend Alex and I were talking about some of the unsavory individuals in our high school after a couple of controversies popped up over the year. I specifically recall him telling me that &amp;ldquo;even bad people are good 90% of the time&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash; a statement that&amp;rsquo;s stuck with me over my college years as I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered more and more cases of unscrupulous wrongdoings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The claim is slightly overexaggerated&amp;ndash; clearly, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a small fraction people that are consistently rude and unpleasant. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that these are pretty few and far between, and I can&amp;rsquo;t really even think of someone I know who&amp;rsquo;s like this off the top of my head. Most people I meet are quite friendly and open. When talking to my friends about the people we met at some event, the typical takeaway is that &amp;ldquo;they were pretty nice.&amp;rdquo; However, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty unlikely that most of these people are actually nice people&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. It&amp;rsquo;s just that anyone can be pleasant at first; most of their personality is usually not revealed until you get to know them better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we define a good person to be a person who is &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; most of the time, I think we would be over-counting the amount of truly good people. As Alex said, even bad people are &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; a majority of the time. A better way is to observe how people behave in testy edge-case scenarios, where bad behavior is more likely to occur. Here are some examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How someone behaves while drunk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How someone behaves around members of their preferred sex&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How someone behaves in a relationship&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How someone behaves in a leadership position&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How someone behaves when they&amp;rsquo;re in the spotlight&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How someone behaves around their parents or siblings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How someone behaves in a Xbox lobby (just kidding)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not saying we should analyze people in their worst moments. We&amp;rsquo;re all guilty of doing pretty horrible things at our worst, and they&amp;rsquo;re often not indicative of who we really are. But if some behavior manifests as a pattern in the same sorts of testy situations, it&amp;rsquo;s likely an indicator of a larger personality flaw.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of more than just a few cases of people I considered &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; doing some questionable things. There have been cases of seemingly chill people cheating on their girlfriends or boyfriends, s*xually assaulting others, acting terribly in group situations, or saying nasty things behind people&amp;rsquo;s backs. I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought to myself that these flaws shouldn&amp;rsquo;t determine someone&amp;rsquo;s entire character&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. However, over time, I began to conclude that these flaws might actually determine someone&amp;rsquo;s character. Almost nobody is a &amp;ldquo;bad person&amp;rdquo; all the time (or even most of the time), so it would be unreasonable to say someone is a &amp;ldquo;bad person&amp;rdquo; only if they are bad most of the time. If someone behaves consistently badly in certain situations or across multiple situations, it should be enough to conclude they might just be a bad person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, not all flaws are created equal. We all act poorly in certain situations based on the way we grew up and our environment. But clearly, there are some clear boundaries most people can draw that isolates truly &amp;ldquo;bad behavior.&amp;rdquo; Even with our own flaws, the biggest thing that separates good people and bad people is the ability to recognize and work on them. There are loads of people who claim they will &amp;ldquo;do better&amp;rdquo; next time but end up falling back on old habits and desires. The inability to act against their flaws is a pretty telltale sign that a person isn&amp;rsquo;t truly trying to work on said flaws&amp;ndash;mostly when they are reminded time and time again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is that I should be more selective in who I should surround myself with. I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel obligated to spend time with someone because they haven&amp;rsquo;t made an arbitrarily amount of &lt;em>enough mistakes&lt;/em> for me to cut them off entirely. A few wrong steps within a cascade of right steps can still lead someone astray. Sometimes, one big step is enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Only some people are truly nice people. A lot of people aren&amp;rsquo;t and don&amp;rsquo;t have to be, either. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying nice to describe a good person. It&amp;rsquo;s just one of the ways that you can be pleasant. There are other ways to be pleasant as well. But, I do use &amp;ldquo;bad person&amp;rdquo; to refer to everyone unpleasant.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>Thoughts along the lines of &lt;em>well, he&amp;rsquo;s a good friend to me and most, but he just acts badly around girls&lt;/em>.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Celebrity Obsession</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/celebrity-obsession/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/celebrity-obsession/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/kpop.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Celebrity Obsession" />&lt;p>A trend I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed over the past decade is the increased obsession with celebrities and influencers. It&amp;rsquo;s not a surprise either. Access to the internet has increased the amount of information distribution channels. You can easily click through hundreds of daily articles about rumors and the latest gossip about your favorite or least favorite celebs. Most of them have their personal social media platforms now where you can see carefully crafted Instagram posts or shower tweets that should have just stayed shower thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the high and easy access to such information has drastically increased the ceiling for fans and haters alike, creating a new age of obsession among the general population. Celebrity worship can be easily be seen across all social platforms. It&amp;rsquo;s normal to like certain celebrities or idols, too. They often have skills, charisma, or looks that most of the population doesn&amp;rsquo;t possess. But, the level of worship has become uncanny over the past few years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest area I can point to that exhibits this problem is in the K-pop industry. Fans treat their favorite idols as their gods, going out of their way to defend them to the death as if they were a family member. The smallest criticisms will receive a lengthy response by a fan defending every single action and attacking the criticizer. Fans creating funny edits of their fancams will receive over-the-top responses like &amp;ldquo;stop joking about *insert favorite idol* and respect their privacy, how would you like it if this was you.&amp;rdquo; These responses are commonly followed by a 1000-word comment by the original poster about how the post was supposed to be light fun and just a meme, and how they care about their favorite idol as well. There&amp;rsquo;s also no doubt to me that many fans fall into both of these categories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whenever a celebrity makes a widely recognized mistake, these die-hard fans will go out of their way to reinterpret the mistake as a positive trait, often leaving long PSAs about how &amp;ldquo;people make mistakes&amp;rdquo; and how you&amp;rsquo;re probably worse in every regard. These standards probably only apply to their beloved idol and nobody else. They will worship even the most mundane things about their favorite idol, gushing on about how amazing it is that their favorite idol uses some random brand of toothpaste. At the same time, many of these fans seem to keep their idols to impossible standards, lashing out if their idol doesn&amp;rsquo;t do the things they expect them to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">Average BTS fan &lt;a href="https://t.co/AE00KcTCxO">pic.twitter.com/AE00KcTCxO&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Everything Out Of Context (@EverythingOOC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EverythingOOC/status/1688997757829386249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>I recall seeing on Instagram how fans sent a protest truck over to HYBE&amp;rsquo;s headquarters to protest how ENHYPEN&amp;rsquo;s choreography of their new song, Bite Me, featured the seven members each dancing with a female backup dancer&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>:. I can only speculate the reason for this outrage, but regardless of whether it&amp;rsquo;s because of jealousy or control, this is degenerate behavior. It&amp;rsquo;s become all too common for fans to intrude into the personal lives of their favorite celebrities, where their actions start becoming predatory and obsessive. Here are just a few examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>BTS members V and RM bowed on their live, begging their fans not to visit them at their military enlistment to respect their privacy&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People sending hate to actress Han So-hee, who featured in BTS Jungkook&amp;rsquo;s music video, &amp;ldquo;Seven&amp;rdquo; &lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oli London getting plastic surgery to look like BTS Jimin (has since realized his mistake)&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stalking idols to their personal addresses via stalker taxis (not even joking)&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This idolization culture exists in the West as well, from Kanye to Taylor Swift to the Kardashians. The crazy &amp;ldquo;fans&amp;rdquo; will do anything for their celebrity and will fight endless useless battles on the internet for the attention of absolutely nobody. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the main contributors to toxicity on the internet, where people are compelled to take sides in non-existent controversies simply because crazy fans decided to compel them into existence. However, this culture seems to be the most pervasive in Asian countries. In the K-pop industry, I&amp;rsquo;m sure the management factors these thought processes into their decisions. It&amp;rsquo;s too common to see idols apologizing for completely normal things, knowing that their reputation is at stake because of the demonic nature of some of their fans. Some examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>BTS Jungkook apologizing for hanging out with a female friend &lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Twice Tzuyu forced apology for holding a Taiwanese flag on television (she&amp;rsquo;s from Taiwan) &lt;sup id="fnref:7">&lt;a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Riize Seunghan apologizing after fans found out he had a girlfriend &lt;sup id="fnref:8">&lt;a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Backlash over Exo&amp;rsquo;s Chen for getting married and starting a family &lt;sup id="fnref:9">&lt;a href="#fn:9" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">9&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A lot of fans will defend their idol for trivial accusations. However, many of these fans are equally obsessive over the idol, writing long paragraphs about how their idol must be protected at all costs and can make their own decisions. Even if they are right, the pure investment of an overwhelming online defense and care for the celebrity is also alarming. These fans aren&amp;rsquo;t their family, girlfriend/boyfriend, or their guardian. A counter-reaction can still be harmful even in good faith. The best idea is just to move on with your life because there is no point in convincing crazy fans. Unfortunately, idolization culture is so pervasive in so many places that it has become a negative reinforcement loop&amp;ndash;where celebrities succumbing to the crazy fans causes the same fans to become emboldened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Celebrity idolization is perfectly normal. After all, we have to have some people in the public that we can all look up to. As an Asian pop fan myself, I love talking to my friends about the latest songs and idols. We love talking about new movies, new public scandals, and our favorite media stars. But at some point, there has to be a ceiling of what can be deemed &lt;em>normal&lt;/em>. We can&amp;rsquo;t enter a territory where we no longer view these celebrities as people. They may be special in some ways, but at the end of the day, they are human like the rest of us. They have quirks and flaws, and we should be mindful of them. They aren&amp;rsquo;t specimens to be unconditionally oggled at nor are they objects of constant public outrage. We need to take them for how they are, for better or for worse. Even today, the crazy stans I talk about are likely a tiny fraction of all of the fans. But, it&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much noise this small group of people can drum up, and it&amp;rsquo;s a shame that they become the public perception of what true fans actually are. The more attention they get, the more prevalent they become.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, you can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel bad for everyone. Normal fans have to deal with the antics of crazy fans. Crazy fans are in a delusional world where anything is justified so long as it is for their favorite idol. And for the idols, at the cost of fame and fortune, they are faced with a reality where they cannot really live a normal life. Their relationships and personal life become public business. They have to deal with dumb PR decisions to appease the fans, often with disregard for their morals or personal views. It&amp;rsquo;s a difficult road to navigate because their decisions are no longer personal, but where they have to consider the management and the public. Everything they do will be worshipped, scrutinized, and ripped apart. In a world full of crazies, there is nothing an idol can do to appease everyone, and often something will be sacrificed. And usually, the sacrifice is their sanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lesson to be learned: Don&amp;rsquo;t look at the comments on Kpop fan account TikToks. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether the TikTok was good, offensive, boring, bad, or hilarious. They will ruin your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222260/rabid-k-pop-fans-object-enhypens-bite-me-backup-dancers-fleet-protest-trucks">https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222260/rabid-k-pop-fans-object-enhypens-bite-me-backup-dancers-fleet-protest-trucks&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://nextshark.com/bts-beg-fans-military-enlistment-location">https://nextshark.com/bts-beg-fans-military-enlistment-location&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.asiaone.com/entertainment/jungkook-han-so-hee-receives-hate-comments-reportedly-starring-bts-seven-music-video">https://www.asiaone.com/entertainment/jungkook-han-so-hee-receives-hate-comments-reportedly-starring-bts-seven-music-video&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:4">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/oli-london-apologizes-surgeries-appear-bts-star-jimin-rcna45677">https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/oli-london-apologizes-surgeries-appear-bts-star-jimin-rcna45677&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:5">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sasaeng_fan#Tactics">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sasaeng_fan#Tactics&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:6">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.koreaboo.com/news/bts-jungkook-apology-fans-dating-scandal-bon-voyage/">https://www.koreaboo.com/news/bts-jungkook-apology-fans-dating-scandal-bon-voyage/&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:7">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/17/world/asia/taiwan-china-singer-chou-tzu-yu.html">https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/17/world/asia/taiwan-china-singer-chou-tzu-yu.html&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:8">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/k-pop/music/news/riizes-seunghan-sparks-controversy-over-instagram-live-with-alleged-girlfriend/articleshow/104332053.cms?from=mdr">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/k-pop/music/news/riizes-seunghan-sparks-controversy-over-instagram-live-with-alleged-girlfriend/articleshow/104332053.cms?from=mdr&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:8" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:9">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-are-EXO-fans-so-mad-about-Chen-starting-a-family-I-personally-think-its-great-but-I-want-to-know-the-actual-reason-in-depth-of-why-people-are-so-mad">https://www.quora.com/Why-are-EXO-fans-so-mad-about-Chen-starting-a-family-I-personally-think-its-great-but-I-want-to-know-the-actual-reason-in-depth-of-why-people-are-so-mad&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:9" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>I'm so Bored</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bored/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bored/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/bored.jpg" alt="Featured image of post I'm so Bored" />&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a month since my winter break began, and I can concretely say that I have accomplished absolutely nothing of substance. I have never been at a point in my life where I&amp;rsquo;ve had nothing solid to work toward, and I have no idea what to do. In middle school and high school, I was driven by competition and the desire to get into a good college. I wanted to win debate competitions, perform well in math competitions, and win the national Science Bowl. I wanted good grades to have a high GPA. In my free time, I could focus my time on improving in these areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that I am in college, the same no longer applies. I no longer participating in competitions, which are much sparser in the collegiate level anyway. My activities only provide short-term motivation and are relatively inconsequential in the long term. My main driver over freshman and sophomore year&amp;ndash;landing a summer internship&amp;ndash;has already been completed. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m only left with obscure goals like preparing for a career, managing my financials, or planning my future&amp;ndash;none of which provide a crystallized image of what I should be doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the first time in my life, I feel like I have nothing to do. I have a ton of options&amp;ndash;learning new career skills, playing violin, doing more art-related activities&amp;ndash;but none of them seem particularly attractive. Moreover, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider any of them to be priorities. However, I also don&amp;rsquo;t know what my priorities should be. I&amp;rsquo;ve put myself in a limbo, where I have options that are better than what I have been doing&amp;ndash;nothing&amp;ndash;but I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly want to pick any of the options I have either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This thought has also sparked more about what lies ahead. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve graduated from university, I no longer have to worry about grades. I&amp;rsquo;ll have a job which becomes more routine and longer-term than anything I have partaken in before, and I wonder my ambitions might look like then. I know my priorities will shift as I age, from school and grades to a career and family, but there will be an in-between period (including now) where I am unclear about the path forward. During school, I was anxious about school. During break where I have nothing to be anxious about, I&amp;rsquo;m anxious about nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There isn&amp;rsquo;t a takeaway here. I literally have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that once I do know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, that I&amp;rsquo;ll back on this piece and learn how I got pointed back in the right direction. In the meantime, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll just have to roam around in my thoughts and look within.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Old?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/what-does-mean-old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/what-does-mean-old/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/old.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What Does it Mean to be Old?" />&lt;p>Over the summer of 2023, I interned at an AI startup in Menlo Park, California. I purchased a gym pass to the YMCA a few miles away in Palo Alto. On my daily commute back from the gym, I biked past an old elderly couple smiling and laughing as they crossed the street together. It was a scene I saw countless times biking around the well-off suburban area full of retirees. But that day in particular, something struck a chord within me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I turned my head around to look back at the couple, I imagined what it would feel like if that was me crossing the street. A flood of questions entered my head that I had never considered before. If I was old, what would make me smile the way they did? Who would I be spending my extra time with? Do I still spend time with my high school and college friends? How sad would I feel to hear that my childhood friend had passed? Would I still have deep conversations with my friends in the middle of the night like I do now?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started to think even deeper. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a family or children, what purpose would I have to live? Even if I did, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see them all the time, so what would make me wake up in the morning? With my career long gone, what incentive do I have to drive me forward? What would I be spending my time on until the day I die? My parents have often told me to save money to retire financially free. But what would be next if I did?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have never had this conversation with anyone who&amp;rsquo;s reached this point in their life. My paternal grandparents lived in Texas by themselves in a senior home for 20 years, their main source of company being each other and their church friends. After they moved to live in Maryland with my family, they still primarily only have each other. When I spend time with them, they are always happy to feed me with their cooking. But, I always wonder what happens after I leave. What do they do all day? What purpose do they live for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often wonder what my perspective on life would be if I did, either by talking my grandparents, neighbors, or volunteering at a senior home. But alas, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the insight to answer any of these questions. It&amp;rsquo;s a scary thing to think about. What does it mean to be old? What is left after a life lived?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Deep Dive Review of Abyss</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/abyss-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/abyss-review/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/abyss.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Deep Dive Review of Abyss" />&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a movie or TV show review. However, this show deserves it, because I had some serious gripes about it while watching it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-quick-synopsis">A Quick Synopsis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Abyss centers around two friends that die tragically in separate events and are reincarnated into new bodies that they don&amp;rsquo;t recognize. Cha Min, a rather ugly but kind heir of his family&amp;rsquo;s cosmetics empire dies from an alien passing by Earth. As compensation, he is given a magical &amp;ldquo;Abyss&amp;rdquo;, an object that grants the user to revive anybody into the form of their soul. Cha Min&amp;rsquo;s pure soul results in his revival as a tall and attractive man (as Ahn Hyo-seop). In a series of unfortunate events, his prosecutor childhood friend&amp;ndash; Go Se-yeon &amp;ndash; is tragically murdered in her apartment by an unknown man. Her formerly beautiful self is reincarnated into a plain and ordinary figure (Park Bo-young). They begin working together to find out who killed Se-yeon and to vindicate Min, the primary suspect in her murder.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problems-with-the-show">Problems with the Show&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-setup">The Setup&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;m going to loosely refer to the magical entities that give Cha Min the Abyss as aliens.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing the show fails to explain is what in the world is up with the aliens that pass by the Earth. One careless alien knocks Cha Min off of a skyscraper (where he was considering committing suicide since his fianceé left him&amp;hellip;?) to his death. Min wakes up to the alien and his friend, who revived him out of pity and hands him the mystical Abyss. We have almost no idea who the aliens are, what they&amp;rsquo;re doing on Earth, why they gave Min the literal power to revive people, what the rules of the Abyss are, and what their importance is to the story. To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t think the writers knew either, since this plot point is never explained, and the characters essentially never appear on screen again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This scene is clearly just a setup that drives the story forward, but we are left wondering why any of this was necessary. It sets up anticipation for the aliens to be critical to the story, but no aliens appear on screen again until the last episode, where they have the relevance of extras eating food in the background of a scene. Despite this clear writing shortcut, I was willing to gloss over the exact details of the Abyss as long as the show delivered a compelling and tight story. Unfortunately, it did not.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-entire-premise">The Entire Premise&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This show has a relatively promising start. The idea of reincarnation allows the writers to explore how your identity is shaped by your appearance and personality. Having your reincarnated self be a physical manifestation of your soul could be a clever way for a story to allow its characters to reflect on the true nature of their being. However, it appears people&amp;rsquo;s souls are static, meaning that any character&amp;rsquo;s development over the series has zero effect on their appearance. The show does not reflect on what the soul is or what is meant to represent. We learn that Min&amp;rsquo;s attractiveness is a result of his pure soul, while Se-yeon&amp;rsquo;s plainness is a result of her generic and ruthless soul. Even as the characters grow over the series (which they don&amp;rsquo;t really do anyway), nothing about their appearances changes. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to bring the concept of soul into the mix if you&amp;rsquo;re not going to do anything interesting with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that the show plays fast and loose with the rules. Other than Min and Se-yeon, only one character&amp;rsquo;s appearance changes significantly after being reincarnated: the primary antagonist. Oh Yeong-cheol, a skilled surgeon and psychopathic serial killer turns from a middle-aged respectable-looking doctor into a grimy and old man. Jang Hee-jin, Min&amp;rsquo;s ex-going-to-be-wife, retains the exact same figure with the exception of some freckles on her face. And her step-brother/Yeong-cheol&amp;rsquo;s son, despite being a sociopath who kidnaps his step-mother, chokes Se-yeon to death and hires a hitman, is revived in the same young and handsome body. It is never explained why they retain their former appearances and clearly, one of them shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. But hey, why not just overlook this massive inconsistency? You&amp;rsquo;re over-analyzing this trivial plot point that&amp;rsquo;s literally the basis of the show!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="everythings-unrealistic">Everything&amp;rsquo;s Unrealistic&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are a few things that were just brushed over too easily. Obviously, they&amp;rsquo;re not going to cast an ugly actress to be a &amp;ldquo;plain character&amp;rdquo;, but I found it amusing how they consistently referred to Park Bo-young as ordinary-looking. However, I will not suspend my disbelief that people can just claim Min did plastic surgery and became way more handsome and grew like 15cm. It&amp;rsquo;s played off as some sort of joke, but it&amp;rsquo;s also taken seriously at the same time. His mom accepts it so easily that it&amp;rsquo;s just like&amp;hellip;c&amp;rsquo;mon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rules are also so arbitrary. Somehow all the reincarnated bodies retain the same DNA, fingerprints, teeth, yada yada. It allows the show to confirm identities in a real way, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much cheating. We&amp;rsquo;re never informed as to why this is the case. It&amp;rsquo;s just too forced.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-do-they-like-each-other">Why Do They Like Each Other?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you didn&amp;rsquo;t expect Se-yeon and Min to end up liking one another, then you haven&amp;rsquo;t watched enough K-Dramas. Spoilers, they do. But we&amp;rsquo;re never really given a reason as to why. We learn very early on that Min has had the biggest crush on Se-yeon since they were in school, which makes sense. She&amp;rsquo;s very smart, independent, and literally the most beautiful girl in the school. She is literally chased down by almost every guy in the school everywhere she goes. That&amp;rsquo;s enough of a reason for him to like her. But, why does she like him back? He&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;nice to her? Other than that, we see no explicit reason as to why she&amp;rsquo;s attracted to him. The show tells us how sweet he was to her in school which leads to her developing feelings for him, even buying chocolate for him on Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day. However, he&amp;rsquo;s dense as a brick and never understands her intentions. He asks her out multiple times over the years, and she crudely rejects him despite feeling the same way at multiple points. She wanted him to try harder&amp;hellip;which is definitely what you tell the guy you literally like back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not even trying to say that she&amp;rsquo;s out of his league or anything. It&amp;rsquo;s just that the writers don&amp;rsquo;t really establish a compelling reason for her to fall for his personality. The show barely goes out of its way to characterize his kindness or affection towards her during their youth, so we never really get a strong reason for why they would work well together. We learn that they become close friends, but we never get to witness any developments on how he won her over, even as a friend. Over the course of the show in their new bodies, she slowly grasps how competent he is, things she should already know from being friends with him for 20 years. Their sudden kiss in episode 8 feels slightly rushed and unexpected, and I feel like there was never really a build-up toward it. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it left the fans squealing regardless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also not convincing to me that she could essentially forget about him for years until she suddenly realizes that she likes him again. From how the show portrays it, it only really seems like she falls for him because of his new appearance. If there is supposed to be any commentary valuing the inside as much as the outside, it rings hollow due to how the show characterizes Se-yeon&amp;rsquo;s behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lastly, I found it extremely cringe and immature for Min to thirst over his high school crush to the woman who he asks to be his wife (Hee-jin), regardless of whether she dated him for his money or not. Things like that can only be cute in TV shows. In real life, I would file a restraining order.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mins-wife-left-him">Min&amp;rsquo;s Wife Left Him?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Oh, did I forget to mention that Min was going to marry Hee-jin, a girl that Se-yeon set him up with? Yes, this is the driving point at the very beginning of the series, where we learn that Hee-jin has suddenly called off their wedding and vanished. This depresses Min to the point where he contemplates jumping off a building, which initiates the whole plot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hee-jin is a prominent character, but it feels like the writers only throw her in for plot convenience. She has quite a dark backstory, being abused as a child by her serial killer step-father, Oh Yeong-cheol. She causes a lot of problems in the plot due to her trying to protect her mother from her stepfather, which is frankly a good dilemma to introduce to the show. However, I really didn&amp;rsquo;t get much out of her character. Other than creating some obstacles Min and Se-yeon have to overcome, the writers never really try to go any deeper with her character other than her backstory. We never really get to know the extent of her relationship with Min, how her behavior was affected later in life due to her trauma, or how she grows over the course of the series. There were likely many interesting ways where they could explore the relationship between her, Min, and Se-yeon, but it feels like the writers never got around to doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initially, we learn that she only dated Min for the money (he&amp;rsquo;s the son of his family&amp;rsquo;s cosmetic empire), which is obviously a terrible thing to do. It makes it easy for Min to transition from supposedly loving her to immediately going back to his totally normal 20-year-long high school crush. As bad as she is for dating him for the money, Min is just as reprehensible for telling her that he loved her when he really didn&amp;rsquo;t. Eventually, she confesses to Min&amp;rsquo;s mother that she began to love him for who he was after being with him for some time and only chose to cancel the wedding because she didn&amp;rsquo;t want him to get involved with her abusive father. This could have be a gateway for the plot to explore her true feelings and introduce some conflict into Min and Se-yeon&amp;rsquo;s frictionless relationship. But alas, that would be too clever. Instead, her confession was essentially ignored, and Min continues to crush on Se-yeon and Hee-jin moves on without a second thought. Great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was no need for Hee-jin to be the woman he was going to marry. Their &amp;ldquo;love&amp;rdquo; for one another never causes any conflict between Min and Se-yeon, and Min and Hee-jin never reconcile or apologize to one another. Neither of them grows from their relationship, and they move forward in their lives as if their marriage was just some small bump in the road. In a plot already focused on solving a complex murder mystery, it&amp;rsquo;s reasonable that there is no time to explore such a complex relationship. However, this plot point somehow survived and decided to drive some more dissatisfaction in the show. And that makes me sad.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="i-am-completely-unaware-of-my-ex-girlfriends-personality">I am completely unaware of my ex-girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s personality&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Another plot point that bothered me a lot revolves around police detective Park Dong-cheol and his ex-girlfriend Lee Mi-do. Oh wait, but Se-yeon&amp;rsquo;s reincarnated self looks exactly like Mi-do! And Se-yeon is looking to get critical information about the investigation into her death and Dong-cheol is a detective&amp;hellip;how about she pretends to be Mi-do?! Brilliant! Despite it obviously being ridiculous that two characters would look identical, this isn&amp;rsquo;t even the worst idea for a plot point. We could expect that Se-yeon plays with Dong-cheol&amp;rsquo;s feelings for a little bit in order to extract some information about her case until she gets caught impersonating his ex-girlfriend. Instead, he never figures out that this clone of his girlfriend has a completely different personality and knows absolutely nothing about their relationship is not his ex-girlfriend. Up until the point where Min and Se-yeon explicitly tell him that they lied to him, he brings them along on sensitive investigations and allows them to take the reigns on the case at multiple points. Not only is it definitely illegal and easy for them to get caught, they chase down suspects with no legal authority or consequences. I&amp;rsquo;m able to suspend my disbelief a little bit to go along with a story, but not this much. I get how the butterflies in your tummy can get you to do stupid things, but man, Dong-cheol is essentially begging to get his badge revoked and his ass thrown in jail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, the real Mi-do and Dong-cheol end up getting back together, which makes us question why they even broke up in the first place. But, I guess people are really weird in real life, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-the-fck-happened-to-hee-jins-mom">What the F*ck Happened to Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s Mom?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s mom surprisingly drives a lot of the plot. Due to years of abuse and torment by Yeong-cheol, her mom has essentially gone insane and needs to be taken care of at all times. Yeong-cheol threatens Hee-jin using her mother (and his wife), hiding her in remote locations in order to scare Hee-jin into submission. We learn a lot about Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s family dynamic: her abusive father, her protective mother, and her rebellious brother who got beaten and brainwashed by her father. We grow to somewhat care for Hee-jin and her mother, as their relationship drives at least 50% of the conflict in the show. After multiple episodes of chasing down Yeong-cheol and saving Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s mother, she is captured once again by Ji-wook, Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s stepbrother. In a pure fit of rage, Ji-wook kills his stepmother and disposes her body into the ocean, taunting Min that he can&amp;rsquo;t revive her with the Abyss without her body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s it. Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s mother never comes back up again. There&amp;rsquo;s no search for her body and no discussion of reviving her with the Abyss. Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s despair only lasts for a short while and we see no passion for her to retrieve her mother&amp;rsquo;s body. Her mother was her only motivation throughout the entire series. And to see such an abrupt and unexplained end to her mother was just bizarre. I really wondered if the producers just forgot that her mother existed. Poor Hee-jin, I hope they gave you some closure behind the scenes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="chekhovs-gun-the-abyss">Chekhov&amp;rsquo;s Gun: The Abyss&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As per &lt;a href="https://www.masterclass.com/articles/writing-101-what-is-chekhovs-gun-learn-how-to-use-chekhovs-gun-in-your-writing">masterclass.com&lt;/a>,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Chekhov&amp;rsquo;s Gun is a principle in storytelling that suggests that details within a story or play will contribute to the overall narrative. This encourages writers to not make false promises in their narrative by including extemporaneous details that will not ultimately pay off by the last act, chapter, or conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>How does Abyss violate this principle? It&amp;rsquo;s because of the Abyss (the magical object). It violates Chekhov&amp;rsquo;s Gun by failing to deliver the promise of Oh Yeong-cheol using the Abyss for his super mega evil plan. Kind of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When Cha Min dies for a second time, Yeong-cheol becomes the temporary owner of the Abyss because he was the first person that Min revived after becoming its owner (on accident before he knew its capabilities). Over the course of a few episodes, Yeong-cheol accidentally revives a person (who retains her appearance, because f*ck you) and learns of its power. We get to witness his evil laughs over his machinations with his newfound power. He conjures up a plan so devious it will allow him and his family to essentially rule the world. Kind of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, we learn that his master plan was to kill himself and his family so they could be reincarnated and start their lives fresh. Having had his appearance change since the first time he died, he assumed that he would gain access to a new body if he died again and revived himself. Foolish man, for he did not realize that the Abyss reincarnates you as your soul, so you retain your appearance if you die again. Of course, he should surprised. I mean, nobody told him. His assumption even makes sense, if you ignore all the rules (or lack thereof) about the Abyss reincarnating you as the appearance of your soul. However, it was a real letdown. Was this really his master plan? I expected Yeong-cheol to devise some creative method of using the Abyss to do some evil. But the whole time, he was essentially just ignorant, painting the entire storyline as a joke. It&amp;rsquo;s not even that the show violates Chekhov&amp;rsquo;s Gun. It takes out the gun and turns it into a fairy wand. The urgency of the scene fell apart almost instantly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess that&amp;rsquo;s what you get when your devious evil object is literally a magical orb that revives people. Its nature is just too friendly for even a serial killer to make it seem dangerous. It&amp;rsquo;s like having smiley faces and Kirby stickers all over the knife you plan to use to stab someone. But, even so, it could have been invigorating to see him try to revive one of his past evil accomplices or even someone very powerful or dangerous in history. Instead, his plan falls flat on the floor and so did my expectations for the rest of the show. Yeong-cheol has been shown to be a clever and manipulative killer, one I took seriously. But, after this, I kind of lost any respect for his character.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="you-could-have-been-so-much-more-ji-wook">You Could Have Been So Much More, Ji-wook&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The secondary antagonist is Seo Ji-wook, Hee-jin&amp;rsquo;s step-brother, Yeong-cheol&amp;rsquo;s son, and a prosecutor that worked with Go Se-yeon. He is disguised as chief judge Seo Cheon-shik son, under the deal with the chief who supposedly murdered his son. He was born as Oh Tae-jin, living with Yeong-cheol, Se-yeon, and his stepmother as a child. Early on, we get to see the abuse he suffered from his father. Tae-jin tried retaliating against him to no avail but was always disciplined and beaten instead. He tried protecting his sister and mother, but his incessant failures made him weak and hopeless, eventually adopting his father&amp;rsquo;s cruel behavior as a necessary measure. He is a tragically flawed character, and his trauma has embedded itself into his psyche, causing him to mirror his father in the worst of ways. But, we also see his defiance and his internal struggle to battle against the evil within him. We can clearly see that there is some good in him with his hesitance to help his father. We also realize that his helping his father out with murders is a clear case of attachment and his inability to understand any other kind of reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot to unpack in his character. He&amp;rsquo;s calm, decisive, and intimidating. He&amp;rsquo;s capable of a lot of evil and can easily be led astray. But, I expected there to be some kind of character arc. Regardless of whether he makes a noble sacrifice at the end for the greater good or remains a villain to the very end, I was hoping to get a grasp on his motives, relatability, or trauma. However, we get none of this. Tae-jin&amp;rsquo;s character is all over the place. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t always know who to help and ends up stabbing his father and sister in the back. It makes sense that he cannot determine his loyalty, but we don&amp;rsquo;t get to experience the turmoil that he is under. We never really understand why he does the things he does. He hates his father but also helps him constantly. He helps his sister out in one scene and stabs her in the back in the next scene. But, we don&amp;rsquo;t learn what he gets out of this. He obviously doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about his father&amp;rsquo;s greater goal. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t express enough motivation for me to believe that revenge is his driving factor, since nobody other than his father really did anything to him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of room to make us empathize with his character. He is haunted by his past. Other than the flashbacks, we don&amp;rsquo;t much of a grasp of how that drives him now other than his subconcious attachment to his father. He never thinks deeper about what he is even doing or what he is doing any of this for. He just becomes a muddled character who does what is necessary in the given moment, but there is no overarching string that ties his storyline together. It&amp;rsquo;s such a shame because there is so much that could be done with a flawed character like this. He could be a relatable villain with motivations that make sense but are terribly misguided, or a villain that does the right thing in the end. Instead, he ends up as the villain once he kills Yeong-cheol (which does make sense), but not a relatable one that the audience can be empathetic towrads. He just becomes a generic villain that&amp;rsquo;s a villain for the sake of being a villain, the likes that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in Thanos and Kylo Ren. All the depth in his character vanishes in the last few episodes, where he tries to kill Min and Se-yeon with no driving backbone. He gets in a fistfight after failing to shoot Min and gets taken down by the police in a comical fashion. He didn&amp;rsquo;t even end up doing anything super evil other than buying a gun illegally, and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even do anything with it but accidentally shoot Se-yeon. Tae-jin could have been so much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="plot-armor-to-the-max">Plot Armor to the Max&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There has to be some catch to using the Abyss, right? Good, there is. It&amp;rsquo;s not much, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s there. Min finds out that once he has used the Abyss for the final revival, he will vanish along with the Abyss. When Ji-wook/Tae-jin accidentally shoots Se-yeon in the penultimate episode (which was very dumb, by the way), he is faced with the dilemma of using it on her with the price of vanishing for eternity. And he does, as he should. She sheds tears after the death of her friend as we see him appearing in the middle of a forest, behind a veil where he cannot interact with reality. Supposedly, he can move on to the afterlife, but he chooses to try to get back to Se-yeon, undergoing a lot of &amp;ldquo;pain&amp;rdquo;. We have no idea what the &amp;ldquo;pain&amp;rdquo; is, but he supposedly suffers from it. After an arbitrary amount of time, he runs into a very unimportant background character that appeared in one episode, who gives him another Abyss that allows him to return to the real world. For what sacrifice? Seemingly none. He just gets to return. No questions asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like, what? There was literally no urgency or impact of his death if he could just return to Earth because of the background character Joe McSchmo who gave him another Abyss. What stakes were there in the final moments if you&amp;rsquo;re just going to retcon the show so McMin can spend the rest of his life with Park Bo-young? It&amp;rsquo;s goofy, tacky, and rushed. He undergoes no trial or adversity. He just gets to return back to life without any problems. That&amp;rsquo;s lazy writing. Even if he were to return this way, I feel like there should have been some explanation as to why he was given the Abyss in the first place or why he deserves to live again. But, we&amp;rsquo;re just left in the dark with some contrived heart-warming cozy flowery explanation by some pseudo-background character who has supposedly been observing Min this whole time. We don&amp;rsquo;t know what he is. We still don&amp;rsquo;t know who the aliens are. If you&amp;rsquo;re still wondering what&amp;rsquo;s going on, screw you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="back-to-the-premise-a-discussion-of-beauty-and-soul">Back to the Premise: A Discussion of Beauty and Soul&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the concept of reincarnation wasn&amp;rsquo;t meant for the writers to explore identity, it could have at least been an exploration of how attractiveness affects how people are treated in life. With the attractiveness of the two characters reversing completely at the very start, I was hoping that the writers could provide some clever commentary on how beauty affects the individual, as well as how to look past the outside and explore what is on the inside. However, the show doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything meaningful to say about it. The new identities only serve to drive the plot in weak and contrived ways, where the reversal in attractiveness is barely necessary to the story at all. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need to be plot-critical as long as there is a message within the story somewhere, but the show fails to deliver on that front as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It would have been somewhat meaningful if Se-yeon was able to return to her old beautiful self once she had grown as a character, whose soul is now worthy of being beautiful. This might be a bit tacky, but at least it would deliver on the idea that your body is a reflection of your soul. It can show the audience that even if you cannot fix your outside to look like Jungkook, you can at least work on your inside. Alternatively, Min and Se-yeon could have somehow returned to their old bodies, which would demonstrate that their love for each other transcends their physical characteristics. But, they just remain their reincarnated selves and live the rest of their lives happily. Pish posh.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="is-there-nothing-good">Is There Nothing Good?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Obviously, this is not the case. The fact that I even finished the show means I was at least invested to see it through to the end. The disappointment in each episode was small, but large enough that it could accumulate over the course of the series to end up overwhelming the good things about the show. But, I still think the premise is very interesting and very fun to think about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a short list of things I did enjoy:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ahn Hyo-seop: he&amp;rsquo;s very handsome.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dong-cheol, the police detective. He was a lot of fun and everything he did made a lot of sense (other than not recognizing someone posing as his ex). He was a very pure character and entertaining to watch. Lee Si-eon gives a very convincing portrayal of the character.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lee Sung-jae as Oh Yeong-cheol and Kwon Soo-hyun as Oh Tae-jin. Both characters were kind of terrifying in their own right. Yeong-cheol was convincingly creepy and talked in a very calm and psychopathic way. Soo-hyun commanded every scene, where his dark facial expressions really conveyed his ominous intentions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Couply moments. Park Bo-young and Ahn Hyo-seop were very cute in this show. I enjoyed it. However, I feel like none of their cute scenes didn&amp;rsquo;t really belong in this drama. Having the mood flip-flop so fast just made it seem like I was watching two different shows at the same time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fallin&amp;rsquo; by Kim Feel. One of the soundtracks throughout the show. I like this song a lot.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="do-i-watch-it">Do I watch it?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, you really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t if you read this entire piece because I literally spoiled the whole show for you. But, to be perfectly honest, I feel like there are a lot of better shows to watch. But, if you are looking to have an easy watch and you like the main cast, feel free to give it a chance. Watching a bad show is sometimes better than watching a mediocre one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unreliability of AI</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/unreliability-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/unreliability-of-ai/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/hallucination.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Unreliability of AI" />&lt;p>Since the revolutionary public release of generative AI models, there has been an incredible wave of interest, hype, and expectations around their capabilities. Millions of people around the world are harnessing the powers of text-to-image and language models to explore new ideas and accomplish tasks that would have been even impossible in the past. These technologies sprung up so fast that we have yet to internalize the full extent of their possibilities, limitations, and dangers. And this is only the beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have all likely tried asking ChatGPT a myriad of questions, from simple queries to relatively complex ones. They are able to answer questions about history, summarize difficult concepts, solve basic cognitive problems, write comprehensive essays faster than humans, and even generate coding solutions. With such powerful and flexible use cases, people have started to dream up incredibly powerful applications, such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Q&amp;amp;A chatbots that can answer questions about PDFs and websites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Code generation platforms, legal document generators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Information serializers and summarizers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copyrighting Tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>agents that can accomplish difficult tasks like booking flight tickets, conducting research, and planning your calendar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>UI/UX design drafting&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The commercial space has blown up with a massive tsunami of new startups looking to build applications using generative AI, and established companies are scrambling to integrate AI-based features into their existing products and platforms. There has been an incredible surge in excitement and anticipation within investors, with over 40 billion dollars&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> invested into AI in only the past 6 months. The new AI revolution easily surpasses the crypto hype and is becoming the greatest boom since the dot-com bubble. On your Twitter or LinkedIn feed, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen hundreds or even thousands of accounts posting about AI and its capabilities. Every day, there are dozens of new accounts posting their new demos on the website touting their new products. Despite the massive wave of new companies, very few have created a comprehensive product that is available to be consumed by the masses. Why is this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The simple answer is that AI is unreliable. By only analyzing the best scenarios, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to think that AI can do anything. That&amp;rsquo;s why so many startups cherry-pick the examples that they show on Twitter and in their promotion videos&amp;ndash; they are meant to show the best that AI has to offer. But, when you decide to sign up for their beta product, it either doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, barely works, or you don&amp;rsquo;t even hear back from them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to traditional products such as social media platforms, API back-ends, or video streaming services, you expect the product to essentially be reliable 99.9% of the time. Failures come and go, but they are typically minuscule or solvable within a reasonable timeframe. But, you never expect them to fail consistently&amp;ndash; and big concerns and problems emerge when they do. The technology driving most products are predictable, well-tested, and reliable to a (mostly) known extent. On the other hand, generative AI is not an exact science. For example, language models can fail very consistently in predictable or even unpredictable ways. When they fail, it can be hard to know why they failed. And even if you can isolate the reason, it&amp;rsquo;s often difficult to find a fix. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely seen ChatGPT fabricate statistics or data, say something blatantly false, or just fail to give an answer. For example, here are some things language models cannot do well:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Solve complex problems with multiple layers and variables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Perform simple arithmetic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reverse a word (try it)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Answer questions with information that is new or that it is unaware of&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There is a layer of uncertainty and unpredictableness in AI that simply isn&amp;rsquo;t present elsewhere. When you go book an airplane ticket, it almost HAS to be 100% reliable. You click the airline you want, the flight you want, and the type of ticket you want. You make a reservation and you pay. However, if you ask an AI agent to perform the task, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance it might not find the right airplane, accidentally books first class, or just fails outright. When drafting a legal document using some LawyerAI software (because lawyers are expensive), it might output some legal jargon or federal violation that isn&amp;rsquo;t even real. When it comes to these edge-case (and a lot of times, normal) situations, people cannot tolerate this level of inconsistency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This barrier is likely what most AI companies (including the startup I am working at) face when creating a new product. This is by no means an impossible obstacle. AI engineers are working every day in order to minimize errors, hallucinations, and variability in AI generations. There are strategies like &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.11903">chain of thought&lt;/a> to increase language model reliability. Researchers are building new and more powerful and ethical models with safeguards to decrease bias and improve accuracy. However, it is a very difficult task to get a product to a level that is suitable for production. Anyone can have an idea, but it takes a lot of effort to make that idea a reality. But, we&amp;rsquo;re very early in the new AI revolution. The hope is that as the technology advances, we can get to a point where AI can be seen as reliable as traditional mechanisms that governed the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Krytal Hu, from Reuters: &amp;ldquo;Venture capital funding plunges globally in first half despite AI frenzy&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/venture-capital-funding-plunges-globally-first-half-despite-ai-frenzy-2023-07-06/">https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/venture-capital-funding-plunges-globally-first-half-despite-ai-frenzy-2023-07-06/&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Why Bits and Bytes?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bits-and-bytes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bits-and-bytes/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/computer.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why Bits and Bytes?" />&lt;p>Why do computers use binary? The human world is practically defined by the number 10. Ever since we evolved to be competent enough to manipulate numbers, we have almost exclusively used a number system in base 10, &lt;em>cross-culturally&lt;/em>. But computers use base 2. Why base 2 specifically? There are an infinite number of bases to use&amp;ndash; some that make more sense to us than others&amp;ndash; but we decided to go with base 2. In any computing class, the teacher likely launches into discussions of binary addition and subtraction and Boolean algebra without a second thought. It&amp;rsquo;s assumed that computers use binary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m near the end of my second year of college as a &lt;em>computer&lt;/em> engineering student, and not one professor I have had has explicitly told us the reason why computers are in base 2. Maybe, it&amp;rsquo;s because the reason is so simple that it is implied. But, an explicit discussion would have been nice. The reason that almost all computers today use binary is due to &lt;em>simplicity&lt;/em> on a design front. In binary, you only have to deal with two digits, or &lt;em>two states&lt;/em>: 1 or 0, on or off. With any base of more than 2, you have to start manipulating numbers with many more states, which increases complexity. Boolean algebra lets us manipulate these two states easily. Operators have defined input and output mappings. With even a ternary (base 3) system, you would have to design a new series of much more complicated operators to perform simple computations like NOT, AND, or OR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how do computers store these 1s and 0s? Through electrical signals, or &lt;strong>voltages&lt;/strong>. Circuits are designed with cutoffs for HIGH and LOW voltages, representing a 1 or a 0. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple binary switch using electricity. If you had a decimal system, you would have to define voltage cutoffs from 0 all the way to 9. Ten levels of voltages. It would be much harder to define cutoffs when the voltages are not exact. A 5 could easily be interpreted as a 6 and vice-versa. It would be an electrical engineer&amp;rsquo;s nightmare. Imagine having a light switch with 10 different positions. It would be pretty hard to get exactly the brightness you want. So we&amp;rsquo;ve streamlined it into a switch. On or off. Yes or No. Simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Computers are designed using a binary system for their simplicity, designability, and manufacturability. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to encode &amp;ldquo;ons&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;offs&amp;rdquo; into electrical systems. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to manipulate two states with Boolean algebra. Could we theoretically build a ternary or decimal computer? Probably. It would be really hard and not worth the effort. Computers don&amp;rsquo;t have feelings. They are not humans. They don&amp;rsquo;t like decimals better than binary. To the computer, everything is a yes or a no. It will continue to do what it was programmed to do. And without any clear benefits of larger-base computing systems, there&amp;rsquo;s no reason to change anything.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One-Month Reflection</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/one-month-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/one-month-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/conquer.jpg" alt="Featured image of post One-Month Reflection" />&lt;p>February 4th marked the one-month anniversary of the creation of my shorts page, a collection of my short-form writing. Seeing my friend &lt;a href="https://eliqian.xyz">Eli&lt;/a> embark on his one-month writing journey inspired me to try it for myself. I was at a point where I was desperate to share my ideas, but I could not find the right medium to do so. Over the course of 2022, I wrote one single ten-thousand-word monstrosity detailing my self-reflection over the second semester of my freshman year. This put me in the mindset that all my writing needed to be long and arduous, hindering my motivation to crank out more. I made numerous amount of attempts over the following months to write new blog posts, but I failed in every regard. I forced myself to write things I wasn&amp;rsquo;t completely interested in. I started many pieces, only to give up on them halfway through. I experimented with book reviews and personal stories, but none of my ideas felt right. I never published any of these posts. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t meet the expectations that I demanded from myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I contemplated whether I actually liked writing or not. I knew I wanted to write, but I just could not come up with any ideas I deemed interesting enough to follow through on. Certainly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to generate the long-form writing that I felt was necessary to be worthy to post on my blog. I learned to understand that the medium was my limiting variable. All of the problems stemmed from my inability to write long pieces on a whim. I needed to reorient my approach. After seeing Eli&amp;rsquo;s daily short-form writing, I was inspired to do the same. I wanted to write in a way that didn&amp;rsquo;t stress me out and made me &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to finish whatever I started. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the burden of tireless editing and endless reorganization of my work. I was going to start writing shorter pieces of things I wanted to explore. Having often tweeted about shower thoughts and interesting tidbits, I already had a large repository of ideas. I realized that Twitter was already a different medium for expressing my ideas. I didn&amp;rsquo;t panic about sharing my thoughts; the platform made it natural for me to do so. Now, all I needed to do was to channel those ideas into a slightly more fleshed-out form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought of just publishing new shorter articles onto my blog, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel right. My longer-form writing felt like my statement pieces. If I published many shorter pieces on top of them, then fewer people would have the chance of discovering them. I decided to create a separate page to host my short-form writing or my shorts. I spent a day or two designing the layout and ultimately chose to publish my first short on my personal website rather than my blog. I used Substack-like cards with a thumbnail, title, and date, with the hope that the friendly presentation would be inviting to read. I made a commitment on Twitter and my first short that I would write every day of the month. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this now, then you know I wasn&amp;rsquo;t successful with that benchmark. However, I did achieve everything I had hoped to when I decided to create this shorts page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="revelations">Revelations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Lowering the burden to write&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I began seeing writing in a new light. I would go into writing with a different mindset. Each piece was a unique exploration of ideas I had at the moment. I was not afraid of the time commitment I would have to put in each short, as I expected to finish on the spot, whether it took 15 minutes or an hour. The first short I wrote on &lt;a href="https://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps">&amp;ldquo;Dating Apps&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> became so long that I decided to publish it as a stand-alone blog. I didn&amp;rsquo;t plan on making it so long, but the words just kept on coming. It was also the first research-based piece that I published. Over the next week, I would just take notes on my phone during the day on the ideas that came to my head and pick the most interesting ones to write about at night. Sometimes, I would revive an idea I tweeted weeks or even months ago. While I was on vacation in Florida, I found inspiration in the new things that I saw and experienced. Although I did not have a great idea every day, I still felt motivated to write each short. It was exactly what I had hoped for.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Inviting Design&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The Substack-like card design really motivated me to publish. This seems like a really strange reason to want to write, but I realized this when I found myself wanting to come up with clever titles and find unique thumbnails for each short. Some shorts would start out as a title before developing into ideas. I would spend long sessions hunting for the perfect image or trying to generate my own with &lt;a href="https://midjourney.com/">Midjourney&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://openai.com/dall-e-2/">DALLE2&lt;/a>.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> This process had the same feeling as customizing your lock screen, decorating your room, or putting Christmas lights up around your home. An interesting discovery indeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://eliqian.substack.com/i/95549966/it-feels-good-to-publish">Publishing is fun&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Publishing is fun. Working on something and having something to show for it was incredibly gratifying. I found myself wanting to share the things I wrote on Twitter. I liked seeing the thumbnail and titles popping up on my feed. I enjoyed finally substantiating the ideas that had been floating in my head for a long time. I also had this interesting feeling:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sometimes when I publish an article I just stare at it (not even reading it) for the rest of the day. I have no idea why. Maybe because I’m proud? I waste so much time doing this&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Eric Chen (@below_ocean) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/below_ocean/status/1621389869304913920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 3, 2023&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Essentially, I would spend time just looking at my newly published article without even reading it. Maybe it was a sense of pride or maybe it was just a distraction. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure I know, either. Nevertheless, each published article was a little win for the day. It kept me in good spirits and gave me an excuse to take an unnecessarily long break after. After finishing writing, I would fix grammar mistakes and read it over once or twice, no more. If I found any mistakes afterward, I would just quickly fix them and re-publish. This ensured that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get too bogged down by imperfect writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>More topics to discuss&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Writing about more topics gave me more conversation fodder. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some in-depth discussions with my friends about some of the things I wrote about, which generally led to more interesting conversations about other topics. I have referenced my own ideas when discussing the meaning of education and movies in one of my classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>Writing in an IDE is easy?!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If you didn&amp;rsquo;t already know, this website was made with Hugo, a static site generator that compiles markdown files into HTML. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a coding project that has a lot of the work done behind the scenes, but you still need a code editor to work on it. I did most of my writing within VSCode (a popular code editing interface). I realized that writing in such a weird environment removed all the distractions in a typical word editor. I would find spelling and grammar mistakes well after completing my first draft. The weird font and inverted colors eased the writing process. Even though I had great text editors like Obsidian, Notion, and Google Docs, I found myself preferring to write in VSCode. I know, what a nerd.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="6">
&lt;li>My shorts were not even that short&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I assumed that I would just write short blips of what happened each day, but I ended up writing medium-length philosophical discussions of different topics. I developed an expectation that each short should be somewhat enlightening and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;em>too&lt;/em> short. This thought may end up becoming the same pitfall I fell into when writing blogs, so I am making a commitment to write about all sorts of things. Essentially, I need to temper and modify my expectations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was no exact pattern in length. Pieces range from 200-1,000 words. Whenever I published, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even sure of how long each short was. A few days ago, I added a word count indicator at the bottom of each short. It was a good thing for me to not be sure of how long each piece was exactly, as it might have affected when I felt &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; exploring a particular topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-you-should-do">What You Should Do&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do I recommend doing this? Hell yes, I do. It&amp;rsquo;s been an incredibly gratifying and interesting journey for me, and it&amp;rsquo;s only been a month. There is a lot of value in writing. It allows you to explore yourself, your ideas, and your environment. It&amp;rsquo;s an immortal snapshot of your identity at a given point in time. It allows you to be creative with your imagination. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be short-form writing. It can be as long as you want. These shorts were just a strategy that worked for me. You can write stories, chapter books, recipes, or fanfictions. Whatever floats your boat. Just make sure to orient your writing in a way that maximizes your effort and interest. If you end up embarking on this new journey, please reach out. I would love to read any of your future (or current!) creations.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>All the thumbnails without attribution were generated with Midjourney. The short &lt;a href="https://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/">&amp;ldquo;In Defense of Difficult Exams&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> was the only thumbnail generated with DALLE2.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Stepping Stones</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/stepping-stones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/stepping-stones/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/stones.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Stepping Stones" />&lt;p>In many of my science classes over the years, I found myself extremely confused about the intuition behind theorems and proofs. I would ponder, &lt;em>how could you possibly figure that out?&lt;/em> This pervasive thought did not only apply to complex topics. There are so many simple things that this could refer to. How about long division? We all employ that technique all the time, an elementary and systematic approach to dividing any two real numbers that seems trivial. But, would I have come up with such an elegant way of doing it? Maybe, but I cannot know for sure, for it is something I have already learned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my algorithms class the last semester, I thought the same things when learning Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algorithm, Kadane&amp;rsquo;s algorithm, and binary search. These are relatively simplistic algorithms, but I was always thinking whether I would have ever figured them out on my own. Looking back, I would say that this is a relatively naive way of looking at things. The reason these algorithms and ideas have names is because we see them as great discoveries. They&amp;rsquo;re named after the phenomenal scientists that discovered them. They needed an immense understanding of the topics before they even knew where to begin. These ideas were not discovered over night. They may have taken years. They were not proved in the span of a 45 minute lecture in a college class.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason we have education is to quickly teach us the principles that took thousands of years to discover. If we were meant to re-discover everything that&amp;rsquo;s already known, we would never have made it past the stone age. We build on the foundation our predecessors left behind. It allows us to focus on the now instead of the past. It allows us to continuously innovate on the knowledge we have been given. It&amp;rsquo;s okay for you and I not to immediately understand Stokes&amp;rsquo; Theorem. He walked so we could run. He laid down the path for us to forge on ahead. It&amp;rsquo;s our responsibility to embrace and iterate on the ideas that have been passed down to us. We need not spend an eternity on the past. It is our duty to build on it and leave a greater foundation for the future to inherit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Will</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/free-will/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/free-will/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/crossroads.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Free Will" />&lt;p>Do we have control over our lives? Are we truly the one who makes decisions for ourselves, or is our future determined by a predetermined and inescapable fate? Philosophers have pondered this concept of free will for a long time, and the answer is not so clear. The colloquial notion of free will is a concept at a very high level of analysis, one where we evaluate the tenants of existence, consciousness, and autonomy. But if we change perspectives, we can analyze free will on the microscopic scale. Every thought you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had is a collection of particles interacting at the atomic level, governed by the laws of physics. In fact, everything that&amp;rsquo;s ever happened is a collection of particles interacting with one another. But at the human level, these interactions manifest in unbelievably complex structures that we perceive as reality. But if your thoughts and actions are literally just particle interactions, then is everything you ever do already written into nature? You don&amp;rsquo;t get to control the laws of physics, yet you still believe that you do things because you &lt;em>willed&lt;/em> them into existence. But, that really isn&amp;rsquo;t the case. It&amp;rsquo;s the atoms in your body that created this illusion of freedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This concept is extremely hard to digest. Your choice to read this article today was governed by the atoms in your body moving and colliding in predetermined ways. You beginning to understand that free will isn&amp;rsquo;t so simple is also due to atoms in your body moving and colliding in predetermined ways. That&amp;rsquo;s amazing, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? The universe conjured us, beings so complex and organized that somehow we can even contemplate this concept of free will. Every particle interaction that has ever occurred led to a chain of events where we could exist. We&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by millions of species that do not have the capacity for such complex thought. Their particles do not interact in a way that allows them to facilitate it. Your dog cannot. The rocks in your backyard and the river nearby cannot. But, we can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an interview between podcaster Lex Fridman and physicist Brian Greene on free will, Greene said something I found particularly interesting: &amp;ldquo;we are liberated from the limited behavioral repertoire of these rocks and water bottles to have this broad spectrum of responses.&amp;rdquo; He claims that we should be grateful that we have the complex systems necessary to respond to stimuli in a way that most other objects and beings cannot. The fact that we are capable of these responses &lt;em>is&lt;/em> our freedom. I particularly like this notion because it shows that even though we might not have choice, we still &lt;em>can&lt;/em>. And that makes all the difference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a humorous YouTube video titled &amp;ldquo;Why is the Milk Gone?&amp;rdquo; by exurb1a, he contemplates the idea of free will by analyzing the chain of events that led to you running out of milk at lower and lower resolutions. Let me give you an example. After a long day of work, you come home and trip on a broomstick that had fallen to the ground. Why did you trip? It&amp;rsquo;s because the broomstick is on the ground. So the broomstick made you fall. But why is the broomstick on the ground? It&amp;rsquo;s because your damn cat knocked it over. So your cat is the reason you fell. But what made your cat knock it over? It&amp;rsquo;s because you adopted your cat from that shelter. So&amp;hellip;you adopting a cat is the reason you fell. You can slowly lower the resolution until you blame the universe for existing as the reason that you fell. Everything since the inception of the universe 14 billion years ago has followed a trajectory determined by the laws the universe created. Exurb1a ponders that if we created a new universe with the exact same blueprint, would everything turn out the same? Would the universe&amp;rsquo;s creation lead to the creation of the solar system, you being born, you adopting your cat, your cat knocking over a broomstick, and you tripping over the fallen broomstick?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The laws of the universe are not completely black and white. Quantum Mechanics tells us that many particles exist in non determinant states. Electrons exist in a probability distribution. Quantum tunneling isn&amp;rsquo;t an exact process. Maybe, restarting the universe would not lead to you tripping over a broom. Only one difference is needed to cause a butterfly-effect cascade of events, leading to a world where were never even born. But, would you really be comfortable with this explanation, that your free will is simply the result of the probablistic nature of your particles? The answer isn&amp;rsquo;t obvious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whether free will exists or not, I do not see what is wrong with &lt;em>believing&lt;/em> that it exists. If we behave as if it does exist, then what ultimate difference will it make? Believing everything that happens is up to fate allows people to justify a lack of responsibility. &lt;em>I failed my test because I was always going to. I am unsuccessful because of fate. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to try because there is no point.&lt;/em> Believing in free will makes you accountable for your actions. You cannot blame the universe for your failings. You can chalk up your successes to your own decisions. It allows you to seek out your desires and craft your own path without thinking the universe is trying to stop you. We&amp;rsquo;ve created philosophical guidelines to help us navigate and interpret the world and they do not necessarily have to be &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo;. And maybe, instead of seeing free will as a concept of fact or fiction, you can use it as your doctrine to guide your own journey in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lex Fridman Interview:
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B6HryoK4_4g" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Why is the Milk Gone&amp;rdquo;, recommended to me by &lt;a href="https://eliqian.xyz">Eli&lt;/a>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KjeKiIa7XEk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Interesting Crash Course Video:
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vCGtkDzELAI" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Routine and Adventure</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/routine-and-adventure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/routine-and-adventure/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/journey.png" alt="Featured image of post Routine and Adventure" />&lt;p>Life is a balance bewteen routine and adventure. Routine gives us the stability we need. It tells us what to expect and what to do. It&amp;rsquo;s your own crystal ball. If you lose routine, you lose predictability, which would quickly turn your life into chaos. Imagine trying to balance a day full of surprises every day. It would drive you mad. On the other hand, routine brings boredom. It&amp;rsquo;s a cycle of expectation and action. Without things to spice up your life, you would drown in endless predictability. It&amp;rsquo;s the feeling you get when you&amp;rsquo;re on break for too long, waking up every day past noon and playing video games until the sun rises the next day. Adventure offers some variation. It messes with your crystal ball&amp;rsquo;s predictions. It adds the excitement you need to push forward. It&amp;rsquo;s the trip to France after months of hard work. It&amp;rsquo;s the surprise birthday party after a dreadful day. It offers you a chance to go on an expedition&amp;ndash; to explore the unknown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often don&amp;rsquo;t have a healthy balance of routine and adventure. Many of us are bogged down by the doldrums of daily life, each day as monotonous as the last. Many others are overwhelmed by endless unexpected ventures, grasping for some solid ground to stand on. When overly exposed to one, it&amp;rsquo;s common for us to want to seek the other. But we can forget that a healthy life is a balance of both. The doldrums may bog you down, but they are the foundation you build on. The ventures may overwhelm you, but they provide the raw materials for shaping who you become.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shaped by Upbringing</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/shaped-by-upbringing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/shaped-by-upbringing/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/growup.png" alt="Featured image of post Shaped by Upbringing" />&lt;p>We are shaped by our upbringing. Everything that we experience is through the lens through which we view the world, influenced by the major and minute variables of our environment. I have come to a point in my life where I can notice how my past affects the way I behave. I see the ways my upbringing shaped my personality and my desires, in both relationships and company. We make these sorts of observations about others very often. We&amp;rsquo;re not surprised when a problematic child is the son of a crack-addicted couple. We can understand why child celebrities don&amp;rsquo;t assimilate properly when they become adults. However, these are relatively trivial observations. When looking at your own life, there are likely a lot of subtle things about you that were heavily guided by childhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, my argumentative side emerges like a shadow during heated debates, echoing the memories of my parents&amp;rsquo; arguments from my childhood. My timid self emerges when asking for favors, fearing the possible rejection and rebuke I received as a child. It was during my freshman year of college that I came to grasp the extent of my low self-esteem, likely stemming from a lifetime of hearing comparisons to others. I notice that I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to take or internalize compliments, which I did not hear very much of during my youth. It&amp;rsquo;s not all negative. Most of my academic ambition has been driven by my parents encouraging me to pursue invigorating competition and my friends&amp;rsquo; competitive mindsets. I highly value conscientiousness from seeing the number of hours my parents poured into their work. However, I think the negative aspects stand out more (for better or for worse), as they can clearly point out how you deviate from the norm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking at your own experiences, you can likely draw your own conclusions. Maybe a lifetime of abuse and neglect leads you to seek validation and support. If you found purpose in taking care of your younger siblings when you were in school, maybe you tend to do favors for your friends. You absorb your environment from the day you are born, and behaviors that might seem unusual to others might be your entire world. Many children go through rebellious phases as they develop. We can all imagine a kid yelling: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to treat my kids better than you treat me!&amp;rdquo; at her parents. But we can also imagine that same kid in the future thinking to herself that &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve become my mother.&amp;rdquo; In your worst moments, you tend to embody what you&amp;rsquo;ve known for your entire life. You might lash out at your friends or your child as your father did to you. You might do the things that you wish your parents never did to you. It&amp;rsquo;s because that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;ve internalized: that in these situations, it is okay to do what your parents did. For generations, I can assume my ancestors beat their children when they behaved poorly, which is precisely what my parents did to me. And I can only pray I won&amp;rsquo;t continue that behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="who-takes-responsibility">Who Takes Responsibility?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One interesting thought I had the other day is: to what extent are your actions your own? An easy answer is: 100% of your actions are your own, but it&amp;rsquo;s not so simple, is it? We have established that you are shaped by your upbringing. So to what extent are you responsible for your upbringing? It&amp;rsquo;s been shown that children with a family history of criminal behavior are more likely to get involved with criminal behavior themselves. We are not surprised when a mass-sh**ter had an abusive childhood and got bullied in school. We can extrapolate to more concrete factors, like mental illness or personality type. For most criminals, we claim that they are responsible for what they did. We don&amp;rsquo;t send criminals&amp;rsquo; parents to jail for their son&amp;rsquo;s actions. But, to some extent, their parents may be responsible for the way that they turned out, right? For people born with a disposition towards psychopathy, we still blame them for their actions. But, what&amp;rsquo;s the alternative? In most cases, you cannot attribute responsibility to anyone else. Outside of personal responsibility, there is no one else we can legally blame. To some extent, your fate will be controlled by the roll of a die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This piece wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me to levy criticisms at my parents or childhood. No one is perfect. At the end of the day, your parents are just as human as you. And they will make mistakes as well. But, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand yourself to see how you may be influenced by your past. The first step is self-awareness. From then, you can slowly free yourself from your past a forge a future that you choose to define.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A great video about why we love people who hurt us:
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5pqLtNEiNI4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Help or Harm?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/help-or-harm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/help-or-harm/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/aiart.png" alt="Featured image of post Help or Harm?" />&lt;p>With the rise of automation and artificial intelligence, people have begun to discuss whether they are more beneficial or detrimental to society. On the one hand, they are redefining what is possible. On the other, they are replacing tasks that humans would traditionally do. But, why is that a bad thing, if even a bad thing at all? Automating human activities can have the consequence of replacing humans completely. The invention of the telephone switchboard in the early 1900s ended up replacing hundreds of thousands of telephone operators. With the advent of robots that can flip burgers and AI that can generate speech better than most humans, there&amp;rsquo;s a good reason why people are beginning to fear this technological takeover. Nobody wants to lose their job&amp;ndash;their livelihood&amp;ndash; to a machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, some people may argue that advanced technology enhances human capacity. Calculators allowed us to focus on problem-solving rather than computation. Our phones give us access to all the information in the world. Robots can allow humans to do more meaningful work. We can hire the displaced to maintain the robots and work in new industries. AI tools like ChatGPT can help us write better essays and code more efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think both sides of the argument are true, to some extent. There will no doubt be jobs that are completely eradicated by automation in the next couple of decades. I can imagine that technologies similar to that of ChatGPT will generate objective news articles sometime soon. I can imagine that DALLE-like technologies will replace a lot of freelance artists. However, there&amp;rsquo;s also no doubt that these technologies will help people achieve more. People will have robots do menial tasks for them, like mowing the lawn. Coders will use large language models to help them write tedious code, and game developers can use AI-generated music instead of paying hefty fees to music producers. However, there are ramifications of automation that we should consider. There are points where it can go too far. We don&amp;rsquo;t want AI making ethical and moral decisions. We should be wary of the jobs that robots replace. With the rapid pace of technological development, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible for the legal side of the equation to catch up. We need to tread as carefully as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s one last consideration of automation that I don&amp;rsquo;t see a lot of people talking about: the increased need for intelligence. As technological advancements displace routine tasks previously performed by humans, it creates a landscape where individuals are compelled to undertake tasks of greater complexity. This is a problem. I don&amp;rsquo;t think human intelligence is advancing in a way fast enough to match society&amp;rsquo;s demands. Most jobs today already require people to work with computers in some way. Computers are incredibly complex, and it&amp;rsquo;s just the first step. At some point, couldn&amp;rsquo;t we expect that most jobs require people to work with even more advanced technologies? Whether you want to believe it or not, people will be left behind. Not everyone can be a genius. Intelligence isn&amp;rsquo;t a factor you can change easily, if even at all. If we get to a point where technology can do almost everything that humans can do, what is going to be our purpose then? Only the geniuses will continue to thrive, while the rest of us watch in despair. Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll invent ways to enhance human intelligence. Maybe, technology will never get to that point. The future is uncertain, but these are questions that we should contemplate as we continue to navigate through uncharted territory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Might've Been a Nazi</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/you-mightve-been-a-nazi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/you-mightve-been-a-nazi/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/nazi.jpg" alt="Featured image of post You Might've Been a Nazi" />&lt;p>We live in the fairest time in human history. The people today are the most wealthy and free compared to almost everyone even a few hundred years ago. I didn&amp;rsquo;t say that we live in a perfect society. Poverty, racism, and inequality still plague our planet today. But, we can be thankful for all of the incredible developments we have made in recent history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s travel back in time for a second. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt the Nazi party was extremely effective, in the worst way imaginable (not pulling a Kanye here). They had a mission, a strategy, and aggressive rhetoric that convinced a huge plurality of the country to support a party of genocide. It would be very naive to assume that those millions of people in support of Nazism were purely evil. It would also be very naive for you to assume that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done what they did if you were in the same position.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an era of tolerance and freedom, it&amp;rsquo;s easy for us to think we have strong moral virtue. We can&amp;rsquo;t possibly imagine that we could be evil. If we were in Germany in the 1930s, we would&amp;rsquo;ve fought back against Hitler. We would&amp;rsquo;ve stood against tyranny in Maoist China. We would&amp;rsquo;ve risked jail to protest against Jim Crow. However, courage is very difficult. It takes very special people to defy expectations&amp;ndash; there will always be people who suffer for it. During the Civil Rights Movement, it took the suffering of those at the start to set the groundwork for mass protests to occur. It takes time for people to manifest the courage to fight back. It&amp;rsquo;s the reason we have heroes like Corrie Ten Boom and Rosa Parks. If we could all be heroes, then the term &amp;ldquo;hero&amp;rdquo; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that &lt;em>you&lt;/em> wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been a hero. But most of us wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the courage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Nazi Party had the majority vote in 1933 by 26 points (10 million people)&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. They appealed to the middle class. They promised the people they would restore Germany to its former glory during a time of economic stagnation and turmoil. They said they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t leave people behind as the Communists and Capitalists did. And lastly, they convinced the people that the Jews (and gypsies, etc.) were responsible for the economic problems and the loss of the World War&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. People bought that idea. They were inspired by Hitler&amp;rsquo;s words. They found an easy scapegoat for all of their problems: the Jews. And as the party became more popular, more and more people bought in. It was an easy decision. Get rid of the Jews, and all the problems would cease to exist. Civilians turned against their neighbors as the Nazi Party took over. Ordinary people committed the most heinous acts you could imagine. Would you be willing to risk execution to speak out against the party in power? If you were a member of the &amp;ldquo;supreme race&amp;rdquo;, would you risk your privilege to fight against your family and friends? The answer today is easily a strong &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;. But if you were there in the moment, would you have the resolve to do the same?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very difficult problem to think about. If you are born in a country where women are oppressed and you learn to oppress women, who is at fault? You can say with pretty high certainty that most people would abide by the rules of the country. The same goes for slavery. Were most people in the South evil? Did humans become less evil over time? Probably not. We&amp;rsquo;re all born of circumstance, and we choose to follow the crowd. It&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to fathom a reality that we do not know. And it takes courageous people to fight for that reality. Most of us will end up following the crowd. Most of us would probably have been a Nazi. But, some people choose to fight for the ideal. And we should thank them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This begs the question: how many steps are we from being evil? We don&amp;rsquo;t control our heritage, our environment, or our upbringing. Which small things could we have tweaked in our own timeline that would&amp;rsquo;ve sent us off the deep end? How many mistakes away were we from making the worst mistake of our life? Everyone has the capacity for evil. We all have fleeting thoughts that we don&amp;rsquo;t act on because we&amp;rsquo;ve been taught better. But, it takes one small slip up, one moment of misjudgment to become what others would consider &amp;ldquo;evil&amp;rdquo;. So, what&amp;rsquo;s the takeaway? To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure. The easy bit of advice would be to stand for your principles. But when you&amp;rsquo;re told the opposite by millions of people, your resolve will crumble. It&amp;rsquo;s not a reasonable expectation, but it&amp;rsquo;s an ideal for you to strive for. Maybe the takeaway is to appreciate what you have. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you should be thankful for all those who had to suffer to give you the life that you have today, where you can focus on your personal life instead of avoiding the genocidal tendencies of your government. How about a piece of advice instead: speak the truth. The truth is an absolute defense. You might suffer for it. But, it&amp;rsquo;s all you really have in the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This post was inspired by this talk
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XY7a1RXMbHI" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Election Results in Germany&amp;rdquo;, marxists.org, &lt;a href="https://www.marxists.org/archive/trotsky/germany/elect.htm">https://www.marxists.org/archive/trotsky/germany/elect.htm&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;How did the Nazis become So popular?&amp;rdquo;, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, &lt;a href="https://las.illinois.edu/news/2014-10-01/how-did-nazis-become-so-popular">https://las.illinois.edu/news/2014-10-01/how-did-nazis-become-so-popular&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Time is Relative</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/time-is-relative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/time-is-relative/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/time.webp" alt="Featured image of post Time is Relative" />&lt;p>Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor tells us that the simplest idea is always the best. In many situations, this is true. There is no need to needlessly complicate. The more complications you create, the more explanations you need to find.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This rule does not apply in the realm of time. We perceive time to move in a linear fashion, but this is not the case at all. Einstein discovered almost 100 years ago that in every situation, time is relative. Via special and general relativity, he showed the world that the simplest explanation was not the correct one. Time isn&amp;rsquo;t linear at all. Time is relative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does that even mean? It means that time isn&amp;rsquo;t uniform for all objects in the universe. In fact, the way time progresses depends on the relation (hence, relativity) between two entities. The ideas behind special and general relativity are incredibly complex, but there are really fascinating implications that we can all understand. Special relativity tells us that light travels at the same speed in all reference frames. In simple terms, no matter how fast you are moving, the light around you is moving at the constant speed of 300,000 km/s. Why is this weird? Imagine running next to a train moving at 60mph. The faster you go, the slower the train seems to go. Once you&amp;rsquo;re running at 60mph, it is as if the train is not moving at all. However, light is like a train that keeps moving at the same speed as you no matter how fast you run. If you&amp;rsquo;re running at 100 mph, the train will still seem to be moving at 60mph. Trippy, I know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few consequences of this observation. In special relativity, there exists the idea of time dilation, where time will pass differently based on a velocity difference between two objects. Imagine you are on a spaceship traveling at a high speed, and you have a clock on board. From your perspective, time is passing normally on your clock. However, if you were to look out the window at the Earth, you would see that time is zipping by quicker. For example, if you were traveling at 90% of the speed of light, and you stayed on the spaceship for one year, when you returned to Earth, you would find that 100 years have passed. Another phenomenon, called length contraction, occurs when an object is traveling toward you. If a meter stick is traveling towards you at 90% of the speed of light, it will appear to be less than half of a meter. As it approaches the speed of light, it will continue to shrink towards zero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note how I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention a minimum velocity it takes for these phenomena to occur. That means they occur in everyday life, you just don&amp;rsquo;t notice it. At human speeds, they are practically nonexistent. At 60mph, the time dilation factor for an entire year is on the scale of 10 trillionths of a second. And that&amp;rsquo;s for a year. For a second, it&amp;rsquo;s on the scale of femtoseconds. That&amp;rsquo;s 1 / 10^15 of a second! So realistically speaking, you could live your life as if special relativity didn&amp;rsquo;t exist. But, we&amp;rsquo;ll see later that it actually does affect your everyday life, just in ways that you don&amp;rsquo;t think about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is general relativity? Einstein theorized that gravity is a result of the curvature of spacetime, where larger objects would distort the &amp;ldquo;fabric of spacetime&amp;rdquo; even more, resulting in larger gravitational effects (Einstein must have been insane). What the hell does that even mean? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, but I can do my best to describe it. Essentially, spacetime is a 4D way of describing physical space&amp;ndash; the fourth dimension being time. Heavy objects will warp this spacetime in the fourth dimension, similar to the way a large bowling ball will bend a stretched-out bedsheet. And &lt;em>somehow&lt;/em>, objects will follow the curvature, bending in the direction of the object that created it. With this theory, even massless &amp;ldquo;objects&amp;rdquo; like light (photons) will be influenced by gravity, which Newtonian gravity does not explain. The details don&amp;rsquo;t matter too much, but there are some bizarre consequences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time dilation also exists in general relativity, but in a different form, aptly termed &lt;strong>gravitational time dilation&lt;/strong>. It predicts that the passage of time can be affected by the strength of a gravitational field. In a strong gravitational field, time will appear to pass more slowly, as compared to a weaker gravitational field or the absence of a gravitational field. This effect occurs because the fabric of spacetime is curved by the presence of a massive body, and the closer an object is to the massive body, the more pronounced the curvature of spacetime will be. As a result, a clock that is located closer to a massive body will be measured to tick slower than a clock that is farther away. So, the more massive planet or the closer you are to it, the slower time will tick. Near the singularity of a black hole, time will essentially cease to exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This probably just sounds like a bunch of gibberish at this point. Can we even measure these effects? The problematic answer is yes. Humans are so brilliant that we can even measure these effects on our home planet. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen the bending of light near the Sun (called &lt;strong>gravitational lensing&lt;/strong>), measured time dilation using atomic clocks that we flew on planes, and corrected time delays on spacecraft. For example, it is critical for GPS to have accurate timing in order to synchronize with devices on our planet. GPS satellites are affected by both general and special relativity. Since they are moving fast relative to the surface, special relativity predicts a time delay of 7 microseconds per day. Since they are also further from Earth&amp;rsquo;s gravitational center (higher potential energy), general relativity predicts that their time gets ahead by 45 microseconds a day. Overall, GPS clocks tick about 38 microseconds faster every single day&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. This can add up over time and cause problems, so the engineers make sure that the GPS ticks a bit slower to match clocks on Earth. Brilliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, special and general relativity are just theories. What are theories? Theories are not facts. They are systems of thoughts that are constructed to explain reality. There is a very good chance that these theories are not 100% accurate or even true at all. Newton&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity is incomplete, yet physicists and engineers use his equations every single day because they explain reality very accurately &lt;em>most of the time&lt;/em>. Even if general relativity and special relativity are &amp;ldquo;false&amp;rdquo;, they have accurately predicted many real-life situations, just as how Newtonian gravity predicts most real-life situations. We even know general relativity doesn&amp;rsquo;t mesh well with quantum effects. But, not all theories have to be true in every situation. They just have to be useful in the situations where they apply. And unless we can find something better, they are the best we can do today. And if you think you can do better, then maybe you are the next Einstein.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Real-World Relativity: The GPS Navigation System&amp;rdquo;, Ohio State University, &lt;a href="https://www.astronomy.ohio-state.edu/pogge.1/Ast162/Unit5/gps.html">https://www.astronomy.ohio-state.edu/pogge.1/Ast162/Unit5/gps.html&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Bicker Bicker</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/bicker-bicker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/bicker-bicker/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/truth.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Bicker Bicker" />&lt;p>The truth is the light in the darkness. When you are uncertain, the truth is the absolute defense. It gives us solid ground to stand on. We all strive for truth. It allows us to understand the reality we live in. We learn to find the truth. We think, we observe, and we grow&amp;ndash; all with the purpose of getting closer to the absolute truth. And lastly, we argue for it. In a sea of billions, there are endless disagreements to be settled. And without arguing, there is no way to determine what is real and what is not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arguing must be a good thing, right? It helps us clear the fog. But, the word &amp;ldquo;argument&amp;rdquo; generally has a negative connotation. They are often disrespectful, frowned upon, and childish. But why is it so? It&amp;rsquo;s because humans have emotions. Our judgment is clouded by our feelings, ego, and mindset. We are fragile. We dislike being wrong, and we dislike being told we&amp;rsquo;re wrong even more. That is why many arguments often lead to an explosion in both parties, neither side leaving the debate with their minds changed. Arguments become a clash of emotions rather than facts. Sometimes, we argue even &lt;em>knowing&lt;/em> that we are wrong. But we bicker nonetheless. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the human condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is nothing to be gained in being right when you cannot convince others. Winning an argument via the destruction of the opposition fosters hatred rather than understanding. If the goal was to convert him into your way of thinking, you have failed. Arguments must consider the emotion of the opposition. Winning them over emotionally is just as critical as &amp;ldquo;winning&amp;rdquo; the argument. If you defeated them emotionally, they will not be convinced of your validity&amp;ndash; they will just search for more reasons that they are correct. Debating is a skill. Sometimes, it is worth &amp;ldquo;arguing&amp;rdquo;. Maybe, you aren&amp;rsquo;t looking to convert others to your way of thinking. But, the strategy you choose must suit your purpose. Converting others to your way of thinking is a different skill set.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, the search for the truth involves the conversion to your way of thinking. Your goal is to win over the masses in order to update reality. The next time you find yourself getting into a heated argument, make sure you act in accordance with your goals. If you desire to establish the truth, then make sure your words align with your intent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who are You?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/who-are-you/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/who-are-you/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/self.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Who are You?" />&lt;p>Who are you? A collection of cells that form a mass of muscle, tissue, and bones around 5-7 feet high. A vessel of consciousness existing within the framework of time and space. An amalgamation of memories, character traits, and emotion. You probably have a strong sense of who you are. You are the primary witness of your body, your memories, your thought processes, and your consciousness. Everyone else is just a mere observer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somehow, a collection of cells formed you, a sentient being so complex that no one but God himself truly understands. How is it that such simple building blocks can form something so incredibly complex? How is it that we are able to tell that we are alive, that we are who we think we are? Only you can really tell. Everyone else just sees the façade of your internal self. If you disappeared and were replaced with a clone that has your memories, your personality, and your emotions, no one else would be able to know. Only you would know. To your friends and family, the clone is no different than you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we were able to make clones of ourselves in the future, what would that entail? Sure, some meat copies of you can carry on your legacy as if you were immortal. But, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be there to witness it once you&amp;rsquo;re gone. While your clones continue to live your life for eternity, they will not carry &lt;em>you&lt;/em>. But, what does it even mean to be you? If someone else can look like you and behave like you, then are they really any different?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hero or Villain?</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/mlk.webp" alt="Featured image of post Hero or Villain?" />&lt;p>Today is Martin Luther King Jr. Day. It&amp;rsquo;s a day to celebrate one of the most important leaders of the Civil Rights movement. A day to honor the man who delivered one of the most memorable and impactful speeches in American history. A day to honor the man who dreamt of a world where people would be evaluated by the content of their character rather than the color of their skin. There is no doubt that MLK was one of the most important figures in American history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, MLK was not a flawless human being. Some reports claimed that MLK was a serial adulterer: he likely had extramarital affairs with multiple women&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. There was an FBI report that claimed that MLK may have been an accomplice in sexual assault, laughing while one of his friends assaulted another woman&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Even if these particular claims are not 100% true, it is widely held that MLK had serious problems in his personal life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is this enough of a reason to cast away his message? Should we disregard his impact on the world because of his own character? This is a larger question that applies to every hero in history. How should we perceive those who did great things when there are clear deficiencies in their character? This is something I have struggled with for a long time. I had to question whether I should be looking up to my heroes. George Washington owned slaves. Heisenberg was a Nazi. Michael Phelps drove under the influence while on probation for the very same offense. What do we make of these people?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back. There are heroes of the public: people who changed the world. People who saved lives. People who influenced entire generations. But, there are also heroes at the individual level. Even though you are likely not a celebrity, you make a difference in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. There is probably someone that looks up to you. You are evaluated to the same degree, just on a smaller scale. If we look at everyone in history, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that no one is perfect. If you dig deep enough you&amp;rsquo;ll find problems with everyone. We all make mistakes. We have all made terrible mistakes. After all, it&amp;rsquo;s part of the human condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our heroes are the same. They are still people. It would be wonderful if every aspect of our heroes were ideal. But, that is never the case. Our heroes have just as many flaws. They just have some special traits that often outshine their flaws. But, the flaws are still there if you dig deep enough. In modern culture, all you have to do is scroll far enough back in a celebrity&amp;rsquo;s Twitter history. For you, one of your friends can simply pull up a message you sent 10 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not that difficult to find something you said that will bring the torch-carrying mob to your front porch. Evaluating people on solely on purity isn&amp;rsquo;t a feasible strategy. If you look hard enough, nobody should be admired. There would be no more heroes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I offer you to view your heroes under the mantra: &amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t look up to people for what made them the same. We look up to people for what made them different.&amp;rdquo; Let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the heroes again through this lens. George Washington was the first President of the United States and played a key role in leading the Continental Army to victory in the American Revolutionary War, helping establish the United States as an independent nation. Werner Heisenberg&amp;rsquo;s uncertainty principle fundamentally changed the way we viewed the subatomic world. Michael Phelps is the greatest Olympic champion to have ever lived, winning more than double the number of gold medals than any other Olympian in history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, our heroes have flaws. But, that is not why they are important. We should look at what made them unique during their time. Of course, some will have had serious relationship problems. Of course, some were irresponsible. Of course, some went down the wrong path. But, to think that you or anyone else is absent of flaws is naive. We all have our issues. But, this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that there is no balance. There are ways that made people uniquely evil. So evil that their deficiencies darken any good they may have introduced to the world. There are people who should be shamed. However, this balance is purely subjective, so there is obviously never going to be a consensus among all. But, when you see that someone is widely respected, you should take a moment to evaluate why people respect them despite their flaws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One more strategy to evaluate our heroes is to detach the ideas from the person. Our heroes can have great ideas and terrible ideas. Their good ideas are still good, and their bad ideas are still bad. So when you inevitably disagree with a part of someone, you can still look at their great ideas. This applies to your heroes and your friends. After all, when is anyone right about everything? Even Einstein was wrong about quantum mechanics. MLK had socialistic tendencies that went against the message of his &amp;ldquo;I have a Dream&amp;rdquo; speech. To have a hero is to support their great ideas. But, only their great ideas. This strategy makes it so that you do not have to support &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of someone. You do this all the time. You are still friends with your friends despite their problems. You take the good with the bad. When your friends say something you disagree with, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to support it. When Einstein tells you quantum mechanics is wrong, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to agree. When someone uses your hero&amp;rsquo;s statements against you, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to defend yourself for things you don&amp;rsquo;t believe in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MLK day will not go away. People will levy complaints against his character, just as MLK wanted. But, at the end of the day, it seems that most respect his message more than they dislike his deficiencies. And maybe, that&amp;rsquo;s not such a bad thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I’m an MLK scholar – and I’ll never be able to view King in the same light&amp;rdquo;, The Conversation, &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/im-an-mlk-scholar-and-ill-never-be-able-to-view-king-in-the-same-light-118015">https://theconversation.com/im-an-mlk-scholar-and-ill-never-be-able-to-view-king-in-the-same-light-118015&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We need to face the whole truth about Martin Luther King, Jr.&amp;rdquo;, Daily News, &lt;a href="https://www.nydailynews.com/opinion/ny-oped-face-the-whole-truth-about-martin-luther-king-jr-20190612-u6hdhuga7zfefky3ll4twcdrty-story.html">https://www.nydailynews.com/opinion/ny-oped-face-the-whole-truth-about-martin-luther-king-jr-20190612-u6hdhuga7zfefky3ll4twcdrty-story.html&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Death</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/death/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/death/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/death.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Death" />&lt;p>Death awaits all of us. He is calm and patient. Some will arrive at his doorstep early. Some will take many years. But, at time&amp;rsquo;s end, he will greet all of us at his door. There is no escape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Death is such a grave concept (pun intended). It marks the point where something ceases to live. Everyone lives to avoid death. We eat to not starve. We exercise to stay healthy. We avoid dangerous situations to preserve ourselves. We (and every other creature) have a biological impulse to live. It&amp;rsquo;s what has allowed us to survive to this point in time. We want to live, but we&amp;rsquo;re also afraid of death. But, why? What is it that makes us fear it so? Is the pain in our final moments? Are we afraid that our loved ones will grieve? These are factors in the equation, but the concept is much more terrifying and much more daunting than any of these reasons alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it boils down to humans being afraid of the unknown. We don&amp;rsquo;t know what happens in death. Maybe our souls are reincarnated into another body, another universe, or another lifeform. Maybe there is eternal nothingness that ensues. Maybe we will rise to heaven or be dragged into the pits of hell. Maybe we will cease to exist, our final breath being the final moment of &lt;em>us&lt;/em>. Not knowing what will happen to us at death is terrifying. There&amp;rsquo;s no predictable next step. You can&amp;rsquo;t make plans for the unknown. It&amp;rsquo;s the same existential dread that we feel when we&amp;rsquo;re alone, lost in the dark. You don&amp;rsquo;t know if you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by threats. You cannot predict anything, and you have no control over your surroundings. The same goes for death. It is something that you cannot control; it&amp;rsquo;s only something you can delay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We cannot fathom what it means to not be alive. Our consciousness arose when we were born into this world. We cannot know what happened before our birth. There are no memories, no feelings, no well&amp;hellip;anything. We didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, and we cannot understand what it meant to not exist. Just grappling with that concept is quite terrifying. People have tried to define death. In other words, people have created ways of thought to define the unknown. Different religions have been very useful in defining life and death. They define what happens to the soul or happens to the body. They establish definite systems of thought that make death less daunting. It&amp;rsquo;s like having the answer to a practice problem. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to guess whether you are right. It works, too. I heard of many religious Christians who were not afraid of death in their final moments. They believe they will be united with Christ and sent to Heaven. These belief systems are a really powerful tool that humans created that can combat the unknown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a little more to death. It marks the end of our lives. It marks the end of our &lt;em>identity&lt;/em>. I watched an &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gr4hSWmTbNI">interesting video&lt;/a> that dives into a bit about why we fear death. The author of the video claims that we spend our lives cultivating our identity: a father, a son, a dentist, an athlete, etc. We craft our individuality, define our goals, and form countless relationships. In life, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to lose a part of your identity. The author uses an example of a dedicated rising basketball player failing to make his high school team, which tears that part of his identity away. It&amp;rsquo;s a painful process to lose pieces of yourself, and it takes time to repair the damage. But, what does it mean to lose &lt;em>everything&lt;/em>? Every piece of you will be gone, the pieces that you spent your life working on. Gone. And you don&amp;rsquo;t know when or how that will happen. Now, does it get more terrifying than that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that in the third paragraph, I mention that &lt;strong>humans&lt;/strong> are afraid of the unknown. I say humans because we are likely the only species on Earth that wrestles with the deeper and philosophical concept of death. We have minds that developed in a way that allows us to grapple with why it. In other animals, fearing death might just be an impulse, nothing more than a mechanism to keep the host alive. In a way, fearing death is a privilege to humans. And honestly, that is a good thing. It&amp;rsquo;s better to understand something than it is to be ignorant of it. It allows us to explore what it means to live and what we should do with our lives. Even though death awaits, we can still find ways to find meaning in life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In Defense of Difficult Exams</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/exams.png" alt="Featured image of post In Defense of Difficult Exams" />&lt;p>Nobody likes difficult exams. After all, the professor might ask us questions we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before. He might ask about ideas we haven&amp;rsquo;t considered before. Difficult exams can tank my grade. That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair, right? Unfortunately, I would argue that those are actually &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is the purpose of an exam? Exams are meant to test your understanding of the material. I&amp;rsquo;ve had many exams in college that are just refreshed versions of previous semesters&amp;rsquo; exams. Change a number here and there, change some units, and voila! New exam question. I&amp;rsquo;ve also had exams where the professor goes out of their way to tell the students what will be on the exam. Why are these things &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo;? Well, they go against the purpose of exams, which is to &amp;ldquo;test your understanding of the material.&amp;rdquo; Using similar questions incentivizes students to memorize a particular method of solving questions. It promotes a surface-level understanding of the material, since getting full points is usually the only goal when taking an exam. Giving out the test format allows students to narrow down what they have to study. In other words, you&amp;rsquo;re incentivizing students to only understand specific portions of the curriculum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s define what a difficult exam is. A difficult exam is an exam that challenges your understanding of the material. It forces you to apply your tools in ways you might not be familiar with. It makes you think about how to tackle a problem and introduces potential pitfalls that demonstrate an incomplete understanding. I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating for 250-IQ problems, riddles, or trick questions. There are obviously exams that are too difficult. But, with my experience in college, an alarming amount of exams can be considered overly-simplistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, why are difficult exams good? Well, forcing you to apply your tools in new ways shows that you actually understand what you&amp;rsquo;re working with. You&amp;rsquo;re not applying formulas to known situations, you&amp;rsquo;re analyzing a problem to see &lt;em>how&lt;/em> a formula can be used. This mimics real life. You&amp;rsquo;re never going to get a problem at your job that clearly defines a physics problem with initial conditions. It won&amp;rsquo;t be labeled with &amp;ldquo;kinematics question #1&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;solve using the quadratic formula.&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;ll be forced to understand the problem at heart and learn how to apply your knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is all in principle. I like easy exams as much as the next guy. I like having high grades and formulaically studying for an exam I already know the format of. It&amp;rsquo;s simply way less stressful. But in principle, easy exams don&amp;rsquo;t really challenge students&amp;rsquo; thinking. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t force them to use their critical thinking and problem-solving skills. In high school, I had a math teacher (Mr. Schwartz) that gave us exams with problems unlike those on our homeworks. He would write the questions in a way where we had to think about how to apply the tools we learned over the semester. It was tough. But, I think his strategy incentivized deeper studying and understanding of the material. Doing well on an exam was gratifying because you felt as though you earned your grade. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t just handed to you on a platter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Problem writing is a skill. It forces experts to come up with new ways of asking essentially the same question. It forces humanity to approach complex and novel problems. It&amp;rsquo;s way harder to do than simply refresh old questions. In the math olympiad every year, the world&amp;rsquo;s top geniuses come up with ways to ask new questions. The strategies remain the same, but the solution is never trivial. Imagine if they just copied last year&amp;rsquo;s questions with different numbers. What a joke that would be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, this is the professor&amp;rsquo;s prerogative. Students shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be at fault for figuring out the best ways to play the game. But, if that game has an easy strategy, it&amp;rsquo;s not a challenge for the students. Professors who challenge their students will end up providing a lot more value in the long run. Once they&amp;rsquo;re out of school at a job or doing research, they will be prepared to take on the problems that come their way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shared Identity</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/life.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Shared Identity" />&lt;p>I went on a boat tour in Everglades National Park this afternoon. Our tour guide, Mitchell, took guided us through the 3-mile-long Buttonwood Canal, where we arrived at the mouth of Florida Bay. He was very knowledgeable of the different plants, birds, and animal life in the area– after all, it’s his job. Along the water, we passed by a few speedboats driven by middle-aged men with short hair, sun hats, sunglasses, fishing rods, and tanned skin. These boatmen and Mitchell have lived here for all of their lives. They are masters of their domain, and I am just a tourist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was suddenly filled with a sense of smallness. All of us live in a bubble that we think is the world. But, there are so many people out there who live lives we couldn’t even imagine. I live in a world where people are meant to study hard in school, attend a prestigious university, and pursue a decent and sustainable career. I wake up thinking about internships and engineering projects. This bubble is all I’ve really known. The closest people around me probably have similar expectations, reinforcing my worldview. But to Mitchell, my worldview is probably laughable. He lives in a world where people are meant to follow in their parents&amp;rsquo; footsteps, learning the ways of the water, and continuing a family legacy of fishermen. He probably thinks of how the weather is going to be for the day, when he should go out onto the water, and what supplies he should buy in the evening. What is the worldview of a daughter of a billionaire? She might think the goal in life is to create a world-shattering invention, run a successful business, and dedicate oneself to philanthropy. What about the worldview of a gang member? A city boy? A kid from the hood? I barely know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are dozens of assumptions we make in every moment– assumptions that might be completely different than someone with a completely different background. It really takes effort to learn about the types of people that make up this world. One of the main reasons for pursuing strong relationships with others is to expand your worldview, to gain perspective. But, we like to be comfortable. We usually end up living our lives with those that are similar to us. People who have similar expectations, values, and situations. And there’s nothing wrong with that. After all, how could you maintain a stable relationship with someone that you barely share anything with? However, I think it’s worth something to try to live your life outside your comfort zone. Perhaps, to pursue friendships that maybe don’t seem like they would work from a glance. Given all of our differences, there are always subtle threads that unite everyone. And your goal should be to tug on those threads, a bit more than those around you. You can talk to people outside your profession, volunteer for random charities, read memoirs and biographies, travel across the world, or live in hostels to try to meet strangers. The list goes on and on. All of us have some shared identity. And those who expand themselves to have the most encompassing identity have the capacity to do the most good. There are so many walks of life that are so different from mine that I couldn’t possibly begin to understand them. But throughout my life, I hope to begin to understand them, even if just a little bit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunrise</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/sunrise.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Sunrise" />&lt;p>I watched the sun rise at Dania Beach, Florida this morning. I watched as the rays of our red-orange Sun peeked over the dark blue horizon. As it rose across the waters, the light reflected off of the ocean, forming a gold carpet towards the shore. The sky was smeared salmon and pink, gradually melting into blue. It was awe-inspiringly beautiful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first sunrise. As a matter of fact, the Sun has rose every single day that I have been alive. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it with my own eyes a dozen times, and each time has been more beautiful than the last. How can we find such joy in something so trivial? A simple answer is that the sky turns pretty colors. That is also a good answer. Watching a sunrise is usually a special event because we don&amp;rsquo;t witness it every day, and the fact that it is beautiful is a good enough reason to enjoy it. But, I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s more than that. There&amp;rsquo;s emotion, too. The lingering feeling of awe, humility, appreciation, and calm. For the rest of our lives, the Sun will rise happily every day. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about the state of politics or the recent wildfire. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t care that you got a promotion or that your loved one just passed. Nature will run its course. Even when you&amp;rsquo;re gone, it will continue to do its job for an eternity. It makes us see how trivial we are on our tiny rock in space. No matter your problems, no matter your strife, the Sun will start a new day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dealt an Unfortunate Hand</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/poker.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dealt an Unfortunate Hand" />&lt;p>Life is unfair. Some people start with everything and some people start with nothing. We&amp;rsquo;re born of circumstances that we cannot control. We do not decide our parents, our birthplace, our birthday, or our name. We&amp;rsquo;re given a hand, and we&amp;rsquo;re forced to play it. It&amp;rsquo;s an undeniable fact that people have different privileges. Some people are beautiful, some people are geniuses, some people are tall, and some people have it all. It&amp;rsquo;s like they were given pocket aces while you were given a two and a three. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to look at them with disdain and envy. After all, much of their life is due to luck and not hard work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, society still smiles upon those with privilege. We put beautiful people in magazines, we give awards to geniuses, and we admire those of high social status. This widens the divide between the fortunate and the dispossessed. It would be so easy to retaliate against those with lady luck on their side. After all, they didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything to earn what they have. Let&amp;rsquo;s start a people&amp;rsquo;s revolution!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, wait. It&amp;rsquo;s not so simple. As lucky as some people are, they didn&amp;rsquo;t choose to be lucky. If we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be criticized for factors out of our control, that same principle applies to the fortunate. Equality is good, right? We don&amp;rsquo;t even have to look at it from the equality perspective. What would hating on the fortunate do for &lt;em>you&lt;/em>? Wiping out the fortunate is not going to improve your situation. We&amp;rsquo;ll have fewer talented people, no savants, no inventors, no models, no tall people, and no wealthy people. Hating those with more privileges than you won&amp;rsquo;t improve your situation. It will make you bitter, resentful, and ungrateful. You&amp;rsquo;re not going to get your dream job by hating the math whiz next door. You&amp;rsquo;re not going to get into Harvard by complaining about how much better everyone else has it. You&amp;rsquo;re responsible for your life&amp;rsquo;s trajectory. Even if you were dealt a bad hand, you have to play it. You have to push for something. That&amp;rsquo;s the only way your situation will improve, and that&amp;rsquo;s the only way you can make something of yourself. Forget about others because only you can control your own outcome. And you should act immediately. There&amp;rsquo;s no folding. You only have one round.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Playing your pocket twos like they&amp;rsquo;re pocket aces can even win you the round. The billionaires like Warren Buffett and Bill Gates aren&amp;rsquo;t the smartest people in the world. They took risks and played the game. They knew their strengths and they had a strategy. Look where they are now. There are people who live on minimum wage that will live happier lives than some millionaire. They understand their cards and can find more happiness and virtue in their lives than the millionaire can, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t have five Bentleys or a dozen Louis Vuitton handbags. Your fate is in your own hands. I know you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering: some people&amp;rsquo;s hands are so bad that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly be happy. First of all, that&amp;rsquo;s probably not you. But, even if it is, let me tell you a story. There was this woman who had almost nothing going for her. She was extremely unattractive, unintelligent, and dirt poor. Her parents were gone, she had no friends, and she lived alone. But, she told her therapist that she enjoyed volunteering at the psych ward because she was able to help those with situations she deemed even worse than hers. Try to imagine a worse situation than hers. But somehow, she can see that there are people even worse off that she can help. What&amp;rsquo;s your excuse?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve thrown around the terms &amp;ldquo;privileged&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;fortunate&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;lucky&amp;rdquo; many times throughout this piece. But, what do they even mean? How can you even know how most people compare to you? Everyone deals with different burdens. At a surface glance, you think you&amp;rsquo;ve figured out those around you. Jim has rich parents, so he has everything. Ashley is super hot and probably gets a free ride through life. The surface manifestations of privilege can be a façade. You never know what internal struggles they have. Maybe Jim&amp;rsquo;s parents neglect him. Maybe Ashley is failing all of her classes. You will never be sure. So what&amp;rsquo;s the point of labeling them more fortunate than you are? You probably have things they don&amp;rsquo;t. You should learn to appreciate what you have and what you&amp;rsquo;ve been given. But again, even if they are more fortunate than you in every way, hating them won&amp;rsquo;t make your life any less miserable. Play your hand. You won&amp;rsquo;t win anything if you don&amp;rsquo;t try.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chess Addiction</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/chess.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chess Addiction" />&lt;p>Over the last two years, I have become addicted to chess. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent hours upon hours watching analyses of famous games between the strongest grandmasters that have ever lived. Each game is a story. Some are long, others are short. Some are super complicated, others are relatively simple. Some are wild, others are calm. The variety keeps the game interesting, just as different books and genres keep reading interesting. The style of a game depends on the player, the time format, the mood, the environment, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chess is a game of strategy, understanding, tactics, and emotion. Players at the highest level have to out-calculate or out-wit their opponents over the course of hours, minutes, or seconds. There are three formats; classical, the longest format where players are given hours of time. Rapid, the medium format where players are given time in the range of 10-20 minutes. And blitz, the shortest format where players are given anywhere between 3-5 minutes. Each time format has a completely different strategy. Less time means less time to think. Players avoid complications because they do not have time to calculate enough variations. More time means more time to think. Instead of playing instant moves, the top players may spend tens of minutes in a classical game versus a few seconds. There&amp;rsquo;s actually a last set of formats since the dawn of the internet. Bullet. Players are given a minute or less, where insane positions arise on the board given the limited amount of time. Players try to destroy their opponents as soon as possible by attacking their opponent ferociously or entering highly tactical positions. If one finds themselves losing, they may enter a time scramble where they try to make their opponent lose on time. This is called flagging your opponent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Strategy, understanding, and tactics seem reasonable. After all, it seems like the player with the better chess fundamentals and skills should win the game. Although this is probably true for the most part, it is easy to forget that chess players are human. Humans have emotions. They are influenced by their opponent, the environment, and their own minds. Playing a tough opponent can cause players to panic and doubt their abilities. High stake games can cause players to lose composure. Losing many games in a row can cause underconfidence and anger. Winning many games in a row can cause overconfidence or self-assurance. You can play mind games in chess. Depending on your opponent, it can give you a massive edge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how a simple board game invented over a thousand years ago has stood the test of time. There are more people today than ever invested in the game. Chess is now popularized on media, YouTube, Twitch, and more. Chess is an incredibly balanced game, where the player with the white pieces only has an ever-so-slight advantage. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible how humans invented such a game back then. After all, how do we know an 8x8 board is ideal, with 16 pieces on each side and a unique distribution of pieces with different abilities? It&amp;rsquo;s quite marvelous, in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every day, more beautiful games are played by players of all levels. Whether it be online or in a real tournament, anyone can play. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it fascinating how we can look at an arrangement of pieces on a wooden board and call it beautiful? Instead of drawings or paint with meanings, it&amp;rsquo;s the complexity of the position. In an arrangement with thousands, millions, or more possible continuations, there are a select few or one unique continuations that leads to the termination of the game. Usually, that continuation is not obvious at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another unique introduction to chess is the chess engine. Computers with powerful processing capabilities can find the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; move in any position. What took the top grandmasters hours if not weeks to agree on (if even at all), we can today find the top moves in an instant. It&amp;rsquo;s like having an answer key to every test. It seems like engines take all the fun out of chess, but it is mostly the contrary. While players have begun to memorize engine lines (it&amp;rsquo;s still very difficult to understand why the best moves are the best), most top players can use engines to improve their play, find new strategies, and understand the intricacies of complicated positions like they never could before. It&amp;rsquo;s really interesting how the human mind was able to create an engine that can play better than all the humans in the world combined.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What makes chess so fun to play? It&amp;rsquo;s like any puzzle. You have to think over an endless sea of options and figure out which one is best. You have to be able to convince yourself of your choice. You can focus on the opening, middlegame, and endgame, each part having its own intricacies and complications, bringing variety to the game. Lastly, chess is a game of dominance. You defeating a player are you displaying your superior (most of the time) chess capabilities? It&amp;rsquo;s truly a battle of intellect, and a win is very rewarding, mostly when you feel that you played many good moves to defeat your opponent. On the other hand, it can truly be frustrating when you lose complicated games or get obliterated by your opponent. I have never been as angry in any other game as I have been in chess. It&amp;rsquo;s a double-edged sword.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I am still quite a novice, I want to continue to explore chess. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really put the most effort into chess fundamentals. I&amp;rsquo;ve only played games. But, when I find the time, I will focus on actually learning the positional skills that are required to be considered a well-rounded player. And the best thing is, there is no end. There&amp;rsquo;s no way that I will &amp;ldquo;conquer&amp;rdquo; the game. No matter how long I focus and study chess, there is always room to improve. If Magnus Carlsen is still improving every day, then how could I ever get bored of it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Humans are Silly</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/thinking-man.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Humans are Silly" />&lt;p>Humans are silly. We do a lot of really silly things. We look at squiggles on a piece of paper to learn. We bop our heads to random assembleges of acoustic waves. We go to office buildings and trade our time for pieces of paper with fancy images on them. The list goes on and on. We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard that nagging voice from a parent or friend: &amp;ldquo;why are you wasting your time?&amp;rdquo; Maybe we were playing video games, chatting with our friends, or doodling on a piece of paper. After all, they&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;useless activities.&amp;rdquo; But, if we extrapolate out any human activity, we can make it sound ridiculous, even though we do them on a daily basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re a investor. You buy pieces of a company at some random evaluation based on public perception. Those pieces may suddenly become much more valubale, whether it be from an Elon Musk tweet or actual progress. You don&amp;rsquo;t care. You buy low, sell high, and call it a day. You consider yourself a risk taker, when all you&amp;rsquo;re doing is playing around with invisible IOU cards with variable worth. And somehow, what you&amp;rsquo;re doing is highly respected. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re a fiction author. You&amp;rsquo;re just a grown-up child that writes down your ridiculous fantasies on paper. You make children &amp;ldquo;waste&amp;rdquo; time daydreaming about unrealistic figures of your imagination. But somehow, you might be one of the most famous people alive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are biologically driven to survive and reproduce. In a purely biological sense, anything we do that doesn&amp;rsquo;t contribute to those purposes is silly. But, we do it anyway. We seek companionship, wealth, fun, happiness, and adventure. We choose to do more than just survive. It drives us. It makes us happy. We have created systems of thought to understand why we do these things. And, we accept it. It makes sense. We do things all the time without knowing why we want to, and we&amp;rsquo;re also tasked with understanding why we do those things. It&amp;rsquo;s an infinite cycle of action and comprehension. We can ask why until infinity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why are you a lawyer? I want to make money. Why do you want to make money? I want to buy things. Why do you want to buy things? The things make me happy. Why do the things make you happy? They bring me joy. Why do they bring you joy? They make me think deeply. Why does thinking deeply bring you joy? At some point, you won&amp;rsquo;t have a good answer anymore. We are highly complex creatures. But, why is this the reality? God only knows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dating Apps</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/dating-app.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dating Apps" />&lt;p>I was going to write about dating apps here, but it ended up being so long that I put it on my blog. You can read it here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.echen.io/p/dating-apps/">https://blog.echen.io/p/dating-apps/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Carefree Writing</title><link>https://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://echen.io/images/calligraphy.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Carefree Writing" />&lt;p>I have not published a blog post in half a year. Emphasis on &lt;em>published&lt;/em>. I have many backlogged drafts that I never completed, from book reviews to self reflections. Writing has become a chore for me. I spend too much time on the details, losing focus on the greater meaning behind the piece itself. If writing is thinking, then I have not thought. If writing is self expression, then I have not expressed myself. As I have been told, don&amp;rsquo;t let the perfect be the enemy of the good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The medium really matters. I expect my blogs to be long and drawn out, even though they do not need to be. People write very short and simple blogs all of the time. When I tweet some shower thought on Twitter, I am never bogged down by expectation. I wish to carry that mindset over to my normal writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inspired by my friend, &lt;a href="https://eliqian.xyz/publish">Eli Qian&lt;/a>, I am making a commitment to writing more often. I will try to publish more short-form writing to make it easier to get back into writing. For the next month, I will post an excerpt here daily. I will not worry about word counts or public judgement. I am letting my spirit roam free.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>