<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Short-form Writings on echen.io</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/</link><description>Recent content in Short-form Writings on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://echen.io/shorts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chess Addiction</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</guid><description>Over the last two years, I have become addicted to chess. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent hours upon hours watching analyses of famous games between the strongest grandmasters that have ever lived. Each game is a story. Some are long, others are short. Some are super complicated, others are relatively simple. Some are wild, others are calm. The variety keeps the game interesting, just as different books and genres keep reading interesting. The style of a game depends on the player, the time format, the mood, the environment, and more.</description></item><item><title>Humans are Silly</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</guid><description>Humans are silly. We do a lot of really silly things. We look at squiggles on a piece of paper to learn. We bop our heads to random assembleges of acoustic waves. We go to office buildings and trade our time for pieces of paper with fancy images on them. The list goes on and on. We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard that nagging voice from a parent or friend: &amp;ldquo;why are you wasting your time?</description></item><item><title>Dating Apps</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</guid><description>I was going to write about dating apps here, but it ended up being so long that I put it on my blog. You can read it here:
https://blog.echen.io/p/dating-apps/</description></item><item><title>Carefree Writing</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</guid><description>I have not published a blog post in half a year. Emphasis on published. I have many backlogged drafts that I never completed, from book reviews to self reflections. Writing has become a chore for me. I spend too much time on the details, losing focus on the greater meaning behind the piece itself. If writing is thinking, then I have not thought. If writing is self expression, then I have not expressed myself.</description></item></channel></rss>