<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Short-form Writings on echen.io</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/</link><description>Recent content in Short-form Writings on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://echen.io/shorts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Does it Mean to be Old?</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/what-does-mean-old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/what-does-mean-old/</guid><description>Over the summer of 2023, I interned at an AI startup in Menlo Park, California. I purchased a gym pass to the YMCA a few miles away in Palo Alto. On my daily commute back from the gym, I biked past an old elderly couple smiling and laughing as they crossed the street together. It was a scene I saw countless times biking around the well-off suburban area full of retirees.</description></item><item><title>A Deep Dive Review of Abyss</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/abyss-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/abyss-review/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a movie or TV show review. However, this show deserves it, because I had some serious gripes about it while watching it.
A Quick Synopsis Abyss centers around two friends that die tragically in separate events and are reincarnated into new bodies that they don&amp;rsquo;t recognize. Cha Min, a rather ugly but kind heir of his family&amp;rsquo;s cosmetics empire dies from an alien passing by Earth. As compensation, he is given a magical &amp;ldquo;Abyss&amp;rdquo;, an object that grants the user to revive anybody into the form of their soul.</description></item><item><title>The Unreliability of AI</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/unreliability-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/unreliability-of-ai/</guid><description>Since the revolutionary public release of generative AI models, there has been an incredible wave of interest, hype, and expectations around their capabilities. Millions of people around the world are harnessing the powers of text-to-image and language models to explore new ideas and accomplish tasks that would have been even impossible in the past. These technologies sprung up so fast that we have yet to internalize the full extent of their possibilities, limitations, and dangers.</description></item><item><title>Why Bits and Bytes?</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/bits-and-bytes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/bits-and-bytes/</guid><description>Why do computers use binary? The human world is practically defined by the number 10. Ever since we evolved to be competent enough to manipulate numbers, we have almost exclusively used a number system in base 10, cross-culturally. But computers use base 2. Why base 2 specifically? There are an infinite number of bases to use&amp;ndash; some that make more sense to us than others&amp;ndash; but we decided to go with base 2.</description></item><item><title>One-Month Reflection</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/one-month-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/one-month-reflection/</guid><description>February 4th marked the one-month anniversary of the creation of my shorts page, a collection of my short-form writing. Seeing my friend Eli embark on his one-month writing journey inspired me to try it for myself. I was at a point where I was desperate to share my ideas, but I could not find the right medium to do so. Over the course of 2022, I wrote one single ten-thousand-word monstrosity detailing my self-reflection over the second semester of my freshman year.</description></item><item><title>Stepping Stones</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/stepping-stones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/stepping-stones/</guid><description>In many of my science classes over the years, I found myself extremely confused about the intuition behind theorems and proofs. I would ponder, how could you possibly figure that out? This pervasive thought did not only apply to complex topics. There are so many simple things that this could refer to. How about long division? We all employ that technique all the time, an elementary and systematic approach to dividing any two real numbers that seems trivial.</description></item><item><title>Free Will</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/free-will/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/free-will/</guid><description>Do we have control over our lives? Are we truly the one who makes decisions for ourselves, or is our future determined by a predetermined and inescapable fate? Philosophers have pondered this concept of free will for a long time, and the answer is not so clear. The colloquial notion of free will is a concept at a very high level of analysis, one where we evaluate the tenants of existence, consciousness, and autonomy.</description></item><item><title>Routine and Adventure</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/routine-and-adventure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/routine-and-adventure/</guid><description>Life is a balance bewteen routine and adventure. Routine gives us the stability we need. It tells us what to expect and what to do. It&amp;rsquo;s your own crystal ball. If you lose routine, you lose predictability, which would quickly turn your life into chaos. Imagine trying to balance a day full of surprises every day. It would drive you mad. On the other hand, routine brings boredom. It&amp;rsquo;s a cycle of expectation and action.</description></item><item><title>Shaped by Upbringing</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/shaped-by-upbringing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/shaped-by-upbringing/</guid><description>We are shaped by our upbringing. Everything that we experience is through the lens through which we view the world, influenced by the major and minute variables of our environment. I have come to a point in my life where I can notice how my past affects the way I behave. I see the ways my upbringing shaped my personality and my desires, in both relationships and company. We make these sorts of observations about others very often.</description></item><item><title>Help or Harm?</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/help-or-harm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/help-or-harm/</guid><description>With the rise of automation and artificial intelligence, people have begun to discuss whether they are more beneficial or detrimental to society. On the one hand, they are accentuating what is possible. On the other, they are replacing tasks that humans would traditionally do. But, why is that a bad thing, if even a bad thing at all? Automating human activities can have the consequence of replacing humans completely. The invention of the telephone switchboard in the early 1900s ended up replacing hundreds of thousands of telephone operators.</description></item><item><title>You Might've Been a Nazi</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/you-mightve-been-a-nazi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/you-mightve-been-a-nazi/</guid><description>We live in the fairest time in human history. The people today are the most wealthy and free compared to almost everyone even a few hundred years ago. I didn&amp;rsquo;t say that we live in a perfect society. Poverty, racism, and inequality still plague our planet today. But, we can be thankful for all of the incredible developments we have made in recent history.
Let&amp;rsquo;s travel back in time for a second.</description></item><item><title>Time is Relative</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/time-is-relative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/time-is-relative/</guid><description>Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor tells us that the simplest idea is always the best. In many situations, this is true. There is no need to needlessly complicate. The more complications you create, the more explanations you need to find.
This rule does not apply in the realm of time. We perceive time to move in a linear fashion, but this is not the case at all. Einstein discovered almost 100 years ago that in every situation, time is relative.</description></item><item><title>Bicker Bicker</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/bicker-bicker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/bicker-bicker/</guid><description>The truth is the light in the darkness. When you are uncertain, the truth is the absolute defense. It gives us solid ground to stand on. We all strive for truth. It allows us to understand the reality we live in. We learn to find the truth. We think, we observe, and we grow&amp;ndash; all with the purpose of getting closer to the absolute truth. And lastly, we argue for it.</description></item><item><title>Who are You?</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/who-are-you/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/who-are-you/</guid><description>Who are you? A collection of cells that form a mass of muscle, tissue, and bones around 5-7 feet high. A vessel of consciousness existing within the framework of time and space. An amalgamation of memories, character traits, and emotion. You probably have a strong sense of who you are. You are the primary witness of your body, your memories, your thought processes, and your consciousness. Everyone else is just a mere observer.</description></item><item><title>Hero or Villain?</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</guid><description>Today is Martin Luther King Jr. Day. It&amp;rsquo;s a day to celebrate one of the most important leaders of the Civil Rights movement. A day to honor the man who delivered one of the most memorable and impactful speeches in American history. A day to honor the man who dreamt of a world where people would be evaluated by the content of their character rather than the color of their skin.</description></item><item><title>Death</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/death/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/death/</guid><description>Death awaits all of us. He is calm and patient. Some will arrive at his doorstep early. Some will take many years. But, at time&amp;rsquo;s end, he will greet all of us at his door. There is no escape.
Death is such a grave concept (pun intended). It marks the point where something ceases to live. Everyone lives to avoid death. We eat to not starve. We exercise to stay healthy.</description></item><item><title>In Defense of Difficult Exams</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</guid><description>Nobody likes difficult exams. After all, the professor might ask us questions we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before. He might ask about ideas we haven&amp;rsquo;t considered before. Difficult exams can tank my grade. That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair, right? Unfortunately, I would argue that those are actually &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; things.
What is the purpose of an exam? Exams are meant to test your understanding of the material. I&amp;rsquo;ve had many exams in college that are just refreshed versions of previous semesters&amp;rsquo; exams.</description></item><item><title>Shared Identity</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</guid><description>I went on a boat tour in Everglades National Park this afternoon. Our tour guide, Mitchell, took guided us through the 3-mile-long Buttonwood Canal, where we arrived at the mouth of Florida Bay. He was very knowledgeable of the different plants, birds, and animal life in the area– after all, it’s his job. Along the water, we passed by a few speedboats driven by middle-aged men with short hair, sun hats, sunglasses, fishing rods, and tanned skin.</description></item><item><title>Sunrise</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</guid><description>I watched the sun rise at Dania Beach, Florida this morning. I watched as the rays of our red-orange Sun peeked over the dark blue horizon. As it rose across the waters, the light reflected off of the ocean, forming a gold carpet towards the shore. The sky was smeared salmon and pink, gradually melting into blue. It was awe-inspiringly beautiful.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first sunrise. As a matter of fact, the Sun has rose every single day that I have been alive.</description></item><item><title>Dealt an Unfortunate Hand</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</guid><description>Life is unfair. Some people start with everything and some people start with nothing. We&amp;rsquo;re born of circumstances that we cannot control. We do not decide our parents, our birthplace, our birthday, or our name. We&amp;rsquo;re given a hand, and we&amp;rsquo;re forced to play it. It&amp;rsquo;s an undeniable fact that people have different privileges. Some people are beautiful, some people are geniuses, some people are tall, and some people have it all.</description></item><item><title>Chess Addiction</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</guid><description>Over the last two years, I have become addicted to chess. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent hours upon hours watching analyses of famous games between the strongest grandmasters that have ever lived. Each game is a story. Some are long, others are short. Some are super complicated, others are relatively simple. Some are wild, others are calm. The variety keeps the game interesting, just as different books and genres keep reading interesting. The style of a game depends on the player, the time format, the mood, the environment, and more.</description></item><item><title>Humans are Silly</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</guid><description>Humans are silly. We do a lot of really silly things. We look at squiggles on a piece of paper to learn. We bop our heads to random assembleges of acoustic waves. We go to office buildings and trade our time for pieces of paper with fancy images on them. The list goes on and on. We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard that nagging voice from a parent or friend: &amp;ldquo;why are you wasting your time?</description></item><item><title>Dating Apps</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</guid><description>I was going to write about dating apps here, but it ended up being so long that I put it on my blog. You can read it here:
https://blog.echen.io/p/dating-apps/</description></item><item><title>Carefree Writing</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</guid><description>I have not published a blog post in half a year. Emphasis on published. I have many backlogged drafts that I never completed, from book reviews to self reflections. Writing has become a chore for me. I spend too much time on the details, losing focus on the greater meaning behind the piece itself. If writing is thinking, then I have not thought. If writing is self expression, then I have not expressed myself.</description></item></channel></rss>