<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Short-form Writings on echen.io</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/</link><description>Recent content in Short-form Writings on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://echen.io/shorts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hero or Villain?</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/hero-or-villain/</guid><description>Today is Martin Luther King Jr. Day. It&amp;rsquo;s a day to celebrate one of the most important leaders of the Civil Rights movement. A day to honor the man who delivered one of the most memorable and impactful speeches in American history. A day to honor the man who dreamt of a world where people would be evaluated by the content of their character rather than the color of their skin.</description></item><item><title>Death</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/death/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/death/</guid><description>Death awaits all of us. He is calm and patient. Some will arrive at his doorstep early. Some will take many years. But, at time&amp;rsquo;s end, he will greet all of us at his door. There is no escape.
Death is such a grave concept (pun intended). It marks the point where something ceases to live. Everyone lives to avoid death. We eat to not starve. We exercise to stay healthy.</description></item><item><title>In Defense of Difficult Exams</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/difficult-exams/</guid><description>Nobody likes difficult exams. After all, the professor might ask us questions we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before. He might ask about ideas we haven&amp;rsquo;t considered before. Difficult exams can tank my grade. That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair, right? Unfortunately, I would argue that those are actually &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; things.
What is the purpose of an exam? Exams are meant to test your understanding of the material. I&amp;rsquo;ve had many exams in college that are just refreshed versions of previous semesters&amp;rsquo; exams.</description></item><item><title>Shared Identity</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/shared-identity/</guid><description>I went on a boat tour in Everglades National Park this afternoon. Our tour guide, Mitchell, took guided us through the 3-mile-long Buttonwood Canal, where we arrived at the mouth of Florida Bay. He was very knowledgeable of the different plants, birds, and animal life in the area– after all, it’s his job. Along the water, we passed by a few speedboats driven by middle-aged men with short hair, sun hats, sunglasses, fishing rods, and tanned skin.</description></item><item><title>Sunrise</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/sunrise/</guid><description>I watched the sun rise at Dania Beach, Florida this morning. I watched as the rays of our red-orange Sun peeked over the dark blue horizon. As it rose across the waters, the light reflected off of the ocean, forming a gold carpet towards the shore. The sky was smeared salmon and pink, gradually melting into blue. It was awe-inspiringly beautiful.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t my first sunrise. As a matter of fact, the Sun has rose every single day that I have been alive.</description></item><item><title>Dealt an Unfortunate Hand</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/unfortunate-hand/</guid><description>Life is unfair. Some people start with everything and some people start with nothing. We&amp;rsquo;re born of circumstances that we cannot control. We do not decide our parents, our birthplace, our birthday, or our name. We&amp;rsquo;re given a hand, and we&amp;rsquo;re forced to play it. It&amp;rsquo;s an undeniable fact that people have different privileges. Some people are beautiful, some people are geniuses, some people are tall, and some people have it all.</description></item><item><title>Chess Addiction</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/chess-addiction/</guid><description>Over the last two years, I have become addicted to chess. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent hours upon hours watching analyses of famous games between the strongest grandmasters that have ever lived. Each game is a story. Some are long, others are short. Some are super complicated, others are relatively simple. Some are wild, others are calm. The variety keeps the game interesting, just as different books and genres keep reading interesting. The style of a game depends on the player, the time format, the mood, the environment, and more.</description></item><item><title>Humans are Silly</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/humans-are-silly/</guid><description>Humans are silly. We do a lot of really silly things. We look at squiggles on a piece of paper to learn. We bop our heads to random assembleges of acoustic waves. We go to office buildings and trade our time for pieces of paper with fancy images on them. The list goes on and on. We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard that nagging voice from a parent or friend: &amp;ldquo;why are you wasting your time?</description></item><item><title>Dating Apps</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/dating-apps/</guid><description>I was going to write about dating apps here, but it ended up being so long that I put it on my blog. You can read it here:
https://blog.echen.io/p/dating-apps/</description></item><item><title>Carefree Writing</title><link>http://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://echen.io/shorts/carefree-writing/</guid><description>I have not published a blog post in half a year. Emphasis on published. I have many backlogged drafts that I never completed, from book reviews to self reflections. Writing has become a chore for me. I spend too much time on the details, losing focus on the greater meaning behind the piece itself. If writing is thinking, then I have not thought. If writing is self expression, then I have not expressed myself.</description></item></channel></rss>