<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>engineering on echen.io</title><link>http://dev.echen.io/tags/engineering/</link><description>Recent content in engineering on echen.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 16:40:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dev.echen.io/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Northrop Grumman Environmental Sustainability</title><link>http://dev.echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://dev.echen.io/extracurriculars/ng-challenge/</guid><description>Northrop Grumman and UMD host a collaborative annual competition in areas of high importance, ranging anywhere from Machine Learning to Cybersecurity. In 2022, the topic of interest was environmental sustainability. Per Northrop Grumman&amp;rsquo;s own description, the point of the game was to &amp;ldquo;develop an original concept for a product, service, software, or a combination of the three, in areas such as clean energy, water scarcity, food security&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
A joint team of three others and I designed an IoT stormwater management system to prevent runoff and flooding on residential properties.</description></item><item><title>ENES100: An Engineering Interlude</title><link>http://dev.echen.io/projects/enes100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:41:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://dev.echen.io/projects/enes100/</guid><description>Being thrust into the world of engineering was a thrilling experience. When you&amp;rsquo;re tasked with building an autonomous data-collecting vehicle that traverses a makeshift terrestrial arena, how could it not be?
Thank you to my team: Ruth, Alex, Emmanuel, Michael, Curtis, Ajeet, Yaqi. I had a blast.
The LinkedIn Version Designed and implemented an autonomous over-terrain vehicle with the objective of collecting data and traversing an arena with obstacles Engineered the power system and circuitry of the Arduino, sensors, and motors Incorporated the Arduino C sensing code for WiFi communication and object detection Monitored communication avenues between structural and navigation subteams Presented vehicle performance and engineering design process at final conference</description></item><item><title>SEDS - Liquid Rocket Team</title><link>http://dev.echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://dev.echen.io/extracurriculars/seds/</guid><description>I lead the Data Acquisition Team subteam in UMD SEDS&amp;rsquo;s Liquid Rocket Team. Our responsibility is to manage the testing instrumentation, data collection, and safety protocols of the team. The liquid rocket team is the newest addition to SEDS@UMD, launched in 2021. Liquid rocket engines are notoriously difficult to manufacture, as liquid fuel propulsion requires a considerable more amount of calculation and engineering decisions than your traditional solid-fuel rocket engines. Despite the hardships, we aim to hot-fire test our first 350lbf rocket engine during the 2022-2023 year and launch an actual rocket sometime within the next 5 years.</description></item></channel></rss>